Let's see how we can use
reinforcement
learning to control
the Lunar Lander or
for other reinforcement
learning problems.
The key idea is that we're going
to train a neural network to
compute or to approximate
the state action value
function Q of s,
a and that in turn will
let us pick good actions.
Let's see how it works.
The heart of the learning
algorithm is we're going to
train a neural
network that inputs
the current state and
the current action and
computes or
approximates Q of s, a.
In particular, for
the Lunar Lander,
we're going to take
the state s and
any action a and
put them together.
Concretely, the state was
that list of eight numbers
that we saw previously,
so you have xy, x dot,
y dot, Theta, Theta dot,
and then LR for where
the legs are grounded,
so that's a list
of eight numbers
that describe the state.
Then finally, we have four
possible actions: nothing,
left, main, a main
engine, and right.
We can encode any of
those four actions
using a one-hot feature vector.
If action were the first action,
we may encode it using 1, 0, 0,
0 or if it was
the second action to
find the left cluster,
we may encode it as 0, 1, 0, 0.
This list of 12 numbers,
eight numbers for the state
and then four numbers,
a one-hot encoding of the action
is the inputs we'll have
to the neural network,
and I'm going to call this X.
We'll then take these
12 numbers and feed
them to a neural
network with say,
64 units in the
first hidden layer,
second hidden layer,
and then a single output
in the output layer.
The job of the neural network
is the output Q of s, a.
The state action-value
function for
the Lunar Lander given
the input s and a.
Because we'll be using
neural network training
algorithms in a little bit,
I'm also going to refer
to this value Q of s,
a as the target value Y
that were training the neural
network to approximate.
Notice that I did say
reinforcement
learning is different
from supervised learning,
but what we're
going to do is not
input a state and have
it output an action.
What we're going to do is input
a state action pair and have
it try to output Q of s,
a, and using a neural
network inside
the reinforcement
learning algorithm this
way will turn out to
work pretty well.
We'll see the details in
a little bit so don't
worry about it if it
doesn't make sense yet.
But if you can train
a neural network
with appropriate choices
of parameters in
the hidden layers and
in the upper layer
to give you a good
estimates of Q of s,
a, then whenever you're
Lunar Lander is in some state s,
you can then use the
neural network to
compute Q of s, a.
For all four actions,
you can compute Q of s, nothing,
Q of s, left, Q of s,
main, Q of s, right,
and then finally,
whichever of these has
the highest value,
you pick the
corresponding action a.
For example, if out of
these four values, Q of s,
main is largest, then you would
decide to go and fire
the main engine of
the Lunar Lander.
The question becomes,
how do you train
a neural network to
output Q of s, a?
It turns out the
approach will be to use
Bellman's equations to create
a training set with
lots of examples,
x and y,
and then we'll use
supervised learning
exactly as you learned
in the second course
when we talked about
neural networks.
To learn using
supervised learning,
a mapping from x to y,
that is a mapping from
the state action pair to
this target value Q of s, a.
But how do you get the
training set with values for
x and y that you can then
train a neural network
on? Let's take a look.
Here's the Bellman
equation, Q of s,
a equals R of s plus Gamma,
max of a prime, Q of
s prime, a prime.
The right-hand side is
what you want Q of s,
a to be equal to,
so I'm going to
call this value on
the right-hand side
y and the input
to the neural network
is a state and
an action so I'm
going to call that x.
The job of the neural
network is to input x,
that is input the
state action pair,
and try to accurately
predict what will be
the value on the right.
In supervised learning,
we were training
a neural network to
learn a function f,
which depends on a
bunch of parameters,
W and B, the parameters
of the various layers
of the neural network
and it was the job of the
neural network to input x.
Hopefully I'll put something
close to the target value y.
The question is, how can we come
up with a training set with
values x and y for a new
network to learn from.
Here's what we're going
to do. We're going to use
the lunar lander and
just try taking
different actions in it.
If we don't have a
good policy yet,
we'll take actions randomly,
further, left fasser, further,
right fasser further,
main engine, do nothing.
By just trying out
different things in the
lunar lander simulator
we'll observe a lot
of examples of when
we're in some state and
we took some action,
may be a good action, maybe a
terrible action either way.
Then we got some reward R of
s for being in that state,
and as a result of our action,
we got to some new state, S'.
As you take different
actions in the lunar lander,
you see this S,
a, R of s, S',
and we call them tuples in
Python code many times.
For example, maybe one time
you're in some state S
and just to give this an
index and we call this S^1,
and you happen to
take some action a^1,
this could be nothing left,
main thrusts there or right.
As a result of which
you've got some reward,
and you want up at
some state S^'1.
Maybe at different times
you're in some other state S2,
you took some other action,
could be good action,
could be bad action,
could be any of
the four actions,
and you got the reward,
and then you want up with S
'2 and so on multiple times.
Maybe you've done this 10,000
times or even more
than 10,000 times,
so you would have to save
the way with not just S^1,
a^1 and so on, but up
to S^10,000, a^10,000.
It turns out that each
of these tuples will
be enough to create a single
training example, x^1, y^1.
In particular, here's
how you do it.
There are four elements
in this first tuple.
The first two will be
used to compute x^1,
and the second two would
be used to compute y^1.
In particular, x^1
is just going to be
S^1, a^1 put together.
S^1 would be eight numbers,
the state of the lunar lander,
a^1 would be four numbers,
the one-hot encoding of whatever
action this was and y^1
would be computed using
the right-hand side of
the Bellman equation.
In particular, the
Bellman equation says,
when you input S^1,
a^1, you want Q of S^1,
a^1 to be this right hand side,
to be equal to R
of S^1 plus Gamma
max over a' of Q
of S^1'a' prime.
Notice that these two
elements of the tuple
on the right give you enough
information to compute this.
You know what is R of S^1?
That's the reward you've
saved the way here.
Plus the discount factor gamma
times max over all actions,
a' of Q of S'^1,
that's a state you got
to in this example,
and then take the maximum over
all possible actions, a'.
I'm going to call this y^1.
When you compute this,
this will be some
number like 12.5 or 17,
or 0.5 or some other number.
We'll save that
number here as y^1,
so that this pair x^1,
y^1 becomes the first
training example
in this low dataset
we're computing.
Now, you may be wondering,
where does Q of S',
a' or Q of S'^1, a' come from.
Well, initially we don't
know what is the Q function.
But it turns out that when you
don't know what is
the Q function,
you can start off with taking
a totally random guess.
What is the Q function?
We'll see on the
next slide that the
[inaudible] will
work nonetheless.
But in every step Q here is
just going to be some guess.
They'll get better
over time it turns
out of what is the
actual Q function.
Let's look at the
second example.
If you had a second experience
where you are in state
S^2 to got to a^2,
got that reward and
then got to that state.
Then we would create
a second training
example in this dataset,
x^2, where the input
is now S^2, a^2,
so the first two elements go
to computing the input x,
and then y^2 will be
equal to R of s^2 plus
gamma max of a' Q of S' to a',
and whatever this
number is, y^2.
We put this over here
in our small but
growing training set,
and so on and so forth,
until maybe you end up with
10,000 training examples
with these x, y pairs.
What we'll see
later is that we'll
actually take this
training set where the
x's are inputs with
12 features and the
y's are just numbers.
We'll train a new
network with, say,
the mean squared
error loss to try to
predict y as a function
of the input x.
What I describe here is
just one piece of the
learning algorithm we'll use.
Let's put it all together
on the next slide and see
how it all comes together
into a single algorithm.
Let's take a look at what
a full algorithm for learning
the Q-function is like.
First, we're going to take
our neural network and
initialize all the parameters
of the neural network randomly.
Initially we have no idea,
whether it's a Q function,
let's just pick totally
random values of the widths.
We'll pretend that
this neural network is
our initial random guess
for the Q-function.
This is a little bit
like when you are
training linear
regression and you
initialize all the
parameters randomly
and then use gradient descent
to improve the parameters.
Initializing it randomly
for now is fine.
What's important is
whether the algorithm can
slowly improve the parameters
to get a better estimate.
Next, we will repeatedly
do the following;
We will take actions
in the lunar lander,
so float around randomly,
take some good actions,
take some bad actions.
It's okay either way.
But you get lots of
these tuples of when
it was in some state,
you took some actually
gathering what R
of S and you got to
some state s prime.
What we will do is store to
10,000 most recent
examples of these tuples.
As you run this algorithm,
you will see many steps
in the lunar lander,
maybe hundreds of
thousands of steps.
But to make sure we don't end up
using excessive computer memory,
common practice is to just
remember the 10,000 most
recent such tuples that we saw
taking actions in the MTP.
This technique of storing
the most recent examples only is
sometimes called the replay
buffer in reinforcement
learning algorithm.
For now, we're just flying
the lunar lander randomly,
sometimes crashing,
sometimes not and getting
these tuples as experienced
for our learning algorithm.
Occasionally then we will
train the neural network.
In order to train
the neural network,
here's what we'll do.
We'll look at these 10,000 most
recent tuples we had saved and
create a training set
of 10,000 examples.
Training set needs lots
of pairs of x and y.
For our training examples,
x will be the s,
a from this part of the tuple.
There'll be a list
of 12 numbers,
the 8 numbers for the state and
the 4 numbers for the one-hot
encoding of the action.
The target value that we want
a neural network
to try to predict
would be y equals R of S
plus Gamma max of a prime,
Q of s prime a prime.
How do we get this value of Q?
Well, initially is
this neural network that we
had randomly initialized.
It may not be a very good guess,
but it's a guess.
After creating these 10,000
training examples we'll
have training examples x1,
y1 through x10,000, y10,000.
We'll train a neural network
and I'm going to call the
new neural network Q new,
such that Q new of s,
a learns to approximate y.
This is exactly training that
neural network to output f
with parameters w and b,
to input x to try to
approximate the target value y.
Now, this neural
network should be
a slightly better
estimates of what
the Q function or
the state action value
function should be.
What we'll do is we're going
to take Q and set it to
this new neural network
that we had just learned.
Many of the ideas in this
algorithm are due to Mnih et al.
It turns out that if
you run this algorithm
where you start with
a really random guess
of the Q function,
then use Bellman's equations to
repeatedly try to improve
the estimates of the Q function.
Then by doing this
over and over,
taking lots of actions,
training a model, that will
improve your guess
for the Q-function.
For the next model you train,
you now have a slightly
better estimate
of what is the Q function.
Then the next model you
train will be even better.
When you update Q equals Q new.
Then for the next time you train
a model Q of s prime
a prime will be an
even better estimate.
As you run this algorithm on
every iteration, Q of s prime,
a prime hopefully becomes
an even better estimate
of the Q function
so that when you run the
algorithm long enough,
this will actually become
a pretty good estimate
of the true value of Q of s,
a, so that you can
then use this to pick,
hopefully good
actions or the MTP.
The algorithm you just saw
is sometimes called the
DQN algorithm which stands
for Deep Q-Network because
you're using deep learning and
neural network to train a model
to learn the Q functions.
Hence DQN or DQ using
a neural network.
If you use the algorithm
as I described it,
it will work,
okay, on the lunar lander.
Maybe it'll take a
long time to converge,
maybe it won't land
perfectly, but it'll work.
But it turns out that with
a couple of refinements
to the algorithm,
it can work much better.
In the next few videos,
let's take a look
at some refinements
to the algorithm