Welcome to the final video of
this machine learning
specialization.
We've been through
a lot of videos
together and this
is the last one.
Let's summarize the main
topics we've gone over,
and then I like to say
a few words and then
we'll wrap up the class.
Looking back, I think we've
been through a lot together.
The first course we went through
was on supervised
machine learning,
including regression
and classification.
Where you learned about
linear regression,
logistic regression,
cost functions,
and the gradient
descent algorithm.
In the second course,
we then looked at more
advanced learning algorithms,
including neural networks,
decision tree ensembles,
and also went through advice for
machine learning such
as bias and variance
and how to use a train hold-out
cross validation and test
sets and how to improve
your learning
algorithm efficiently.
Then the third course was on
unsupervised learning
recommenders
and reinforcement learning,
where we talked about clustering
algorithms, anomaly
detection algorithms,
collaborative filtering and
content-based filtering,
and then in this past week,
reinforcement learning.
With this broad set of tools,
you are now well
qualified to build
a huge range possible machine
learning applications.
Congratulations on making it
all the way to this last video.
If you've worked all the way
through this specialization,
you now have a very solid
foundation in machine learning.
I think you've made
a great start to
become an expert in
machine learning.
As you know, machine learning
is having a huge impact on
society as a powerful tool
used by billions of people
every day through web search,
product recommendations,
speech recognition,
and many other applications.
There's even improving human
knowledge through hoping
with scientific
discovery is driving
billions of dollars of
value and is enabling
new applications that were
unimaginable just
a few years ago.
But I think the
best application of
machine learning are
still yet to be invented,
and that brings us to you.
You are now well-qualified to
wield the tools of
machine learning,
to build applications yourself,
and to create things.
I hope that you will use
these skills to make other
people's lives better.
Before wrap up this class,
I want to say just one
last thing to you.
This class has been
fun for me to teach,
but not long ago,
I was a student myself,
and so I know how
time-consuming it is
to learn this stuff.
I know you're a busy person with
many other things
going on in your life,
so that you took the time
to watch the videos,
go through the quizzes and labs.
I know you've put a lot of time
and put a lot of yourself
into this class.
I just want to say,
thank you very
much for having been a
student in this class.
I'm very grateful to you
and appreciate all the
time you spent with
me and with the