In this video, we'll look at
two further refinements to
the reinforcement learning
algorithm you've seen.
The first idea is called
using mini-batches,
and this turns out to be an
idea they can both speedup
your reinforcement learning
algorithm and it's
also applicable to
supervised learning.
They can help you speed up
your supervised learning
algorithm as well,
like training a neural network,
or training a linear regression,
or logistic regression model.
The second idea we'll
look at is soft updates,
which it turns out will help
your reinforcement
learning algorithm
do a better job to converge
to a good solution.
Let's take a look at
mini-batches and soft updates.
To understand
mini-batches, let's
just look at supervised
learning to start.
Here's the dataset of
housing sizes and prices
that you had seen
way back in the first course
of this specialization
on using linear regression
to predict housing prices.
There we had come up with
this cost function for
the parameters w and b,
it was 1 over 2m,
sum of the prediction minus
the actual value y^​2.
The gradient in
this algorithm was
to repeatedly
update w as w minus
[inaudible] alpha times the
partial derivative respect
to w of the cost J of wb,
and similarly to
update b as follows.
Let me just take this
definition of J of
wb and substitute it in here.
Now, when we looked
at this example,
way back when were
starting to talk
about linear regression
and supervised learning,
the training set size
m was pretty small.
I think we had 47
training examples.
But what if you have a
very large training set?
Say m equals 100 million.
There are many
countries including
the United States with over
a 100 million housing units,
and so a national
census will give you
a dataset that is this
order of magnitude or size.
The problem with this algorithm
when your dataset is this big,
is that every single step of
gradient descent requires
computing this average
over 100 million examples,
and this turns out
to be very slow.
Every step of gradient descent
means you would compute
this sum or this average
over 100 million examples.
Then you take one tiny
gradient descent step
and you go back and
have to scan over
your entire 100 million example
dataset again to compute the
derivative on the next step,
they take another tiny
gradient descent step
and so on and so on.
When the training set
size is very large,
this gradient descent algorithm
turns out to be quite slow.
The idea of mini-batch
gradient descent is to not
use all 100 million
training examples
on every single iteration
through this loop.
Instead, we may pick
a smaller number,
let me call it m prime
equals say, 1,000.
On every step, instead of using
all 100 million examples,
we would pick some subset of
1,000 or m prime examples.
This inner term becomes
1 over 2m prime is
sum over sum m prime examples.
Now each iteration
through gradient descent
requires looking only at the
1,000 rather than 100
million examples,
and every step takes
much less time and just
leads to a more
efficient algorithm.
What mini-batch
gradient descent does
is on the first iteration
through the algorithm,
may be it looks at that
subset of the data.
On the next iteration,
maybe it looks at that subset
of the data, and so on.
For the third
iteration and so on,
so that every iteration
is looking at
just a subset of
the data so each iteration
runs much more quickly.
To see why this might be
a reasonable algorithm,
here's the housing dataset.
If on the first
iteration we were
to look at just
say five examples,
this is not the whole
dataset but it's slightly
representative of
the string line
you might want to
fit in the end,
and so taking one
gradient descent step to
make the algorithm better fit
these five examples is okay.
But then on the next iteration,
you take a different five
examples like that shown here.
You take one gradient
descent step
using these five examples,
and on the next
iteration you use
a different five examples
and so on and so forth.
You can scan through
this list of
examples from top to bottom.
That would be one way.
Another way would be if
on every single
iteration you just
pick a totally different
five examples to use.
You might remember with
batch gradient descent,
if these are the contours
of the cost function J.
Then batch gradient
descent would say,
start here and take a step,
take a step, take a step,
take a step, take a step.
Every step of gradient descent
causes the parameters
to reliably
get closer to the global minimum
of the cost function
here in the middle.
In contrast, mini-batch
gradient descent or
a mini-batch learning algorithm
will do something like this.
If you start here,
then the first iteration
uses just five examples.
It'll hit in the
right direction but
maybe not the best gradient
descent direction.
Then the next iteration
they may do that,
the next iteration that,
and that and sometimes
just by chance,
the five examples you chose
may be an unlucky choice and
even head in the wrong direction
away from the global minimum,
and so on and so forth.
But on average,
mini-batch gradient descent will
tend toward the global minimum,
not reliably and
somewhat noisily,
but every iteration is
much more computationally
inexpensive and
so mini-batch learning or
mini-batch gradient descent
turns out to be a
much faster algorithm
when you have a very
large training set.
In fact, for
supervised learning,
where you have a very
large training set,
mini-batch learning or
mini-batch gradient descent,
or a mini-batch version
with other optimization
algorithms like Atom,
is used more common than
batch gradient descent.
Going back to our reinforcement
learning algorithm,
this is the algorithm that
we had seen previously.
The mini-batch version
of this would be,
even if you have
stored the 10,000 most
recent tuples in
the replay buffer,
what you might choose
to do is not use all
10,000 every time
you train a model.
Instead, what you might do
is just take the subset.
You might choose just
1,000 examples of these s,
a, R of s,
s prime tuples and
use it to create
just 1,000 training examples
to train the neural network.
It turns out that this will make
each iteration of training
a model a little bit more
noisy but much
faster and this will
overall tend to speed
up this reinforcement
learning algorithm.
That's how mini-batching
can speed up
both a supervised
learning algorithm
like linear regression
as well as this reinforcement
learning algorithm
where you may use a
mini-batch size of say,
1,000 examples, even
if you store it away,
10,000 of these tuples
in your replay buffer.
Finally, there's one
other refinement to
the algorithm that can make
it converge more reliably,
which is, I've
written out this step
here of Set Q equals Q_new.
But it turns out that this can
make a very abrupt change to Q.
If you train a new
neural network to new,
maybe just by chance is not
a very good neural network.
Maybe is even a little bit
worse than the old one,
then you just overwrote
your Q function
with a potentially worse
noisy neural network.
The soft update method
helps to prevent
Q_new through just one
unlucky step getting worse.
In particular, the
neural network
Q will have some parameters,
W and B,
all the parameters for all
the layers in the
neural network.
When you train the
new neural network,
you get some parameters
W_new and B_new.
In the original algorithm S
[inaudible] on that slide,
you would set W to be equal
to W_new and B equals B_new.
That's what set Q
equals Q_new means.
With the soft update,
what we do is instead
Set W equals 0.01
times W_new plus 0.99
times W. In other words,
we're going to make W to be
99 percent the old version of
W plus one percent of
the new version W_new.
This is called a
soft update because
whenever we train a new
neural network W_new,
we're only going to accept a
little bit of the new value.
As similarly, B
equals 0.01 times
B_new plus 0.99 times B.
These numbers, 0.01 and 0.99,
these are hyperparameters
that you could set,
but it controls how
aggressively you move W
to W_new and these two numbers
are expected to add up to one.
One extreme would be if
you were to set W equals
one times W_new plus 0
times W, in which case,
you're back to the
original algorithm
up here where you're
just copying W_new onto
W. But a soft update
allows you to make
a more gradual change to Q or to
the neural network parameters
W and B that affect
your current guess for
the Q function Q of s, a.
It turns out that using
the soft update method
causes the reinforcement
learning algorithm
to converge more reliably.
It makes it less likely
that the reinforcement
learning algorithm will
oscillate or divert or have
other undesirable properties.
With these two final
refinements to the algorithm,
mini-batching, which actually
applies very well to
supervise learning as well,
not just reinforcement learning,
as well as the idea
of soft updates,
you should be able to get
your lunar algorithm to
work really well on
the Lunar Lander.
The Lunar Lander is actually
a decently complex,
decently challenging
application and so that
you can get it to work and
land safely on the moon.
I think that's actually
really cool and I hope you
enjoy playing with
the practice lab.
Now, we've talked a lot about
reinforcement learning.
Before we wrap up, I'd
like to share with you
my thoughts on the state
of reinforcement learning
so that as you go out
and build applications
using different machine learning
techniques via supervised,
unsupervised,
reinforcement learning
techniques that you
have a framework for
understanding where
reinforcement learning
fits in to the world of
machine learning today.
Let's go take a look at