when we start to develop reinforcement
learning hours later this week,
you see that there's a key quantity that
reinforcement learning arrows will try to
compute and that's called
the state action value function.
Let's take a look at
what this function is.
The state action value function
is a function typically
denoted by the letter uppercase Q.
And it's a function of a state
you might be in as well as
the action you might choose to
take in that state and QFSA.
Will give a number that equals the return.
If you start in that state.
S and take the action A just once and
after taking
action A once you then
behave optimally after that.
So after that you take whatever actions
will result in the highest possible
return.
Now you might be thinking there's
something a little bit strange about this
definition because how do we know
what is the optimal behavior?
And if we knew what the auto behavior, if
we already knew what's the best action to
take in every state,
why do we still need to compute Q of SA.
Because we already have the auto policy.
So I do want to acknowledge that there's
something a little bit strange about this
definition.
There's almost something a little bit
circular about this definition, but
rest assured When we look at specific
reinforcement learning outcomes later will
resolve this slightly circular definition
and will come up with a way to compute
the Q function even before we've
come up with the optimal policy.
But you see that in a later video.
So don't worry about this for now.
Let's look at an example we saw
previously that this is a pretty
good policy Go left from stage 2, 3 and
four and go right from State five.
It turns out that this is
actually the optimal policy for
the mars rover application When the
discount factor gamma is 0.5, so Q of S.
A will be equal to the total
return If you start from say that
take the action A and
then behave optimally after that.
Meaning take actions
according to this policy.
Shown over here,
let's figure out what Q of s,a.
Is for a few different states.
Let's look at say Q of state too.
And what if we take the action to go
right well if you're in state two and
you go right then you end
up at state three And
then after that you behave optimally
you're going to go left from ST three and
then go left from state to and
then eventually you get the reward of 100.
In this case, the rewards you get
would be zero from state to zero
when you get to stay three zero
when you get back to state two and
then 100 when you finally get
to the terminal state one and
so the return will be zero
plus 0.5 times that plus 0.5
squared times ac plus 0.5 cubed times 100.
And this turns out to be 12.5 And so
Q of ST two of going
right as equal to 12.5.
Note that this passes, no judgment on
whether going right is a good idea or not.
It's actually not that good an idea
from state to to go right, but
it just faithfully reports out
the return if you take action A and
then behave optimally afterwards.
Here's another example.
If you're in state to and
you were to go left, then the sequence
of rewards you get will be zero when
you're in state two followed by 100.
And so
the return is zero plus 0.5 times 100
that's equal to 50 in order to
write down The values of QSA.
In this diagram,
I'm going to write 12.5 here on the right
to denote that this is Q of
state to going to the right.
And then when I write a little
50 here on the left to denote
that this is Q of ST two and
going to the left just to take one more
example What if we're in ST four and
we decide to go left.
Well if you're in stage four you go left,
you get rewards zero and
then you take action left here.
So zero gain, take action left here,
zero and then 100.
So Q of four Left results in rewards zero
because the first action is left and
then because we followed the optimal
policy afterwards You can reward 00 100.
And so
the return is zero plus 00.5 times that.
Plus 4.5 squared times that
plus 0.5 Q times that.
Which is therefore equal to 12.5.
So Q4 left is 12.5.
I'm going to write this year as 12.5.
And it turns out if you were to carry
out this exercise for all of the other
states and all of the other actions,
you end up with this being the Q of s,a.
For different states and different actions
And then finally at the Terminal State.
Well it doesn't matter what you do, you
just get that terminal reward 100 or 40.
So just write down those
terminal awards over here.
So this is Q of s,a.
For every state state one through six and
for the two actions,
action left and action right.
Because the state action value function
is almost always noted by the letter Q.
This is also often called the Q function.
So the terms Q.
Function and state action value
function are used interchangeably and
it tells you what are your returns or
really what is the value?
How good is it?
Just take action A and ST S and
then behave optimally after that.
Now it turns out that once you can
compute the Q function this will
give you a way to pick actions as well.
Here's the policy and return.
And here are the values two of s,a.
From the previous slide.
You notice one interesting thing when
you look at the different states which
is that if you take state to taking
the action left results in a,q.
Value or state action value of 50 which is
actually the best possible return you can
get from that state.
In state three two of s,a.
for the action left also
gives you that higher return
is therefore the action left
gives you the return you want.
And in state five is actually
the action going to the right that
gives you that higher return of 20.
So it turns out that the best
possible return from any state S.
Is the largest value of Q,F, S.
A maximizing over A.
Just to make sure this is clear what
I'm saying is that in say stay for
There is two of state four
left which is 12.5 And q.
of state four right,
Which turns out to be 10.
And the larger of these two
values which is 12.5 Is
the best possible return
from that state four.
In other words the highest return you
can hope to get from State four is 12.5.
And it's actually the larger of
these two numbers 12.5 and 10.
And moreover, if you want your
Mars Rover to enjoy a return of 12.5
rather than say 10 then the action
you should take is the action A.
That gives you the larger
value of Q of s,a.
So the best possible action
status is the action A.
That actually maximizes Q, of s,a.
So this might give you a hint for
why computing Q, of s,a.
Is an important part of the reinforcement
learning algorithm that will build later.
Namely if you have a way
of computing Q of s,a.
For every state and for
every action then when you're in
some state s all you have to do is
look at the different actions A.
And pick the action A.
That maximizes Q of s,a.
And so pi F.
S can just pick the action A.
That gives the largest value of Q of s,a.
And that will turn out
to be a good action.
In fact it turned out to
be the optimal action.
Another intuition about why
this makes sense is Qof s,a.
Is returned if you sudden status and
take the action A.
And then behave optimally after that.
So in order to earn
the biggest possible return,
what you really want is
to take the action A.
That results in the biggest total return.
That's why if only we have
a way of computing Q f s,a.
For every state taking the action
aid that maximizes return under
these circumstances seems like it's
the best action to take in that state.
Although this isn't something
you need to know for this.
Cause I want to mention also that if you
look online or look at the reinforcement
learning literature, sometimes you
also see this Q function written as Q.
Star instead of Q.
And this Q function is sometimes
also called the optimal Q function.
These terms just refer to the Q
function exactly as we've defined it.
So if you look at the reinforcement
learning literature and read about Q.
Star or the Q function,
that just means the state action value
function that we've been talking about.
But for the purposes of this course
you don't need to worry about this.
So to summarize if you
can compute Q of s,a.
For every state and every action,
then that gives us a good way to
compute the auto policy pi of S.
So that's the state action value
function or the Q function.
We'll talk later about how to come up
with an algorithm to compute them despite
the slightly circular aspect of
the definition of the Q function.
But first let's take a look at the next
video at some specific examples of what
these values Q of s,a.