Using the state-action
value function example.
You're seeing what
the values of QSA are like.
In order to keep holding our intuition
about reinforcement learning problems and
how the values of QSA change depending on
the problem will provided an optional lab.
That lets you play around modify
the [INAUDIBLE] example and see for
yourself how QSA will change.
Let's take a look.
Here's a Jupyter Notebook that I hope
you play with after watching this video.
I'm going to run these helper functions,
now notice here that this
specifies the number six that the two
actions so I wouldn't change these.
And this specifies the terminal left
in the terminal right rewards which
has been 140 and then zero was
the rewards of the intermediate states.
The discount factor gamble 0.5.
And let's ignore
the misstep probability for
now we'll talk about
that in a later video.
And with these values if you run
this code this will compute and
visualize the optimal policy as
well as the Q function Q of SA.
You learn later about how to develop
a learning algorithm to estimate or
compute Q of SA yourself.
So for now don't worry about what code
we have written to compute Q of SA.
But you see that the values here Q of SA
are the values we saw in the lecture.
Now here's where the fun starts.
Let's change around some of the values and
see how these things change.
I'm going to update the terminal
right reward to a much
smaller value says only 10.
If I now rerun the code,
look at how Q of SA changes and
now thinks that if you're in state 5.
Then if you go left and
behave optimally you get 6.25.
Whereas if you go right and
behave also the after that you
get a return of only five.
So now when the reward at the right is so
small it's only 10.
Even when you're so
close to you rather go left all the way.
And in fact the auto policy is now
to go left from every single state.
Let's make some other changes.
I'm going to change the terminal
right reward back to 40.
But let me change
the discount factor to 0.9,
with a discount factor
that's closer to one.
This makes the Mars Rover less impatient
is willing to take longer to hold out for
a higher reward because rewards in
the future are not multiplied by
0.5 to some high power is multiplied
by 0.9 to some high power.
And so is willing to be more patients,
because rewards in the future are not
discounted or multiplied by as small
a number as when the discount was 0.5.
So let's rerun the code.
And now you see this is Q of SA for
the different states and
now for
state 5 going left actually gives you
a higher reward of 65.61 compared to 36.
Notice by the way that 36 is 0.9
times this terminal reward of 40.
So these numbers make sense.
But when a small patient is willing to go
to the left, even when you're in state 5.
Now let's change gamma to a much
smaller number like 0 .3.
So this very heavily discounts
rewards in the future.
This makes it incredibly impatient.
So let me rerun this code and
now the behavior has changed.
Noticed that now in
state 4 is not going to
have the patience to go for
the larger 100 reward,
because the discount factor
gamma is now so small is 0.3.
It would rather go for the reward of 40
even though it's a much smaller reward is
closer and that's whether we choose to do.
So I hope that you can get a sense by
playing around with these numbers yourself
and running this code.
How the values of Q of SA change
as was how the optimal return
which you notice is the larger
of these two numbers QSA.
How that changes as well as how
the optimal policy also changes.
So I hope you go and play with
the optional lab and change the reward
function and change the discount factor
gamma and try a different values.
And see for
yourself how the values of Q of SA change,
how the optimal return from
different states change and
how the auto policy changes
depending on these different values.
And by doing so, I hope that will
sharpen your intuition about how
these different quantities are affected
depending on the rewards and
so on in reinforcement
learning application.
After you play to the lab,
we then be ready to come back and
talk about what's probably the single
most important equation in reinforcement
learning, which is something
called the bellman equation.
So I hope you have fun playing
with the optional lab and
after that let's come back to