In the last video, we saw
a neural network
architecture that will input
the state and action and attempt
to output the Q
function, Q of s, a.
It turns out that
there's a change to
neural network architecture that
make this algorithm
much more efficient.
Most implementations
of DQN actually use
this more efficient architecture
that we'll see in this
video. Let's take a look.
This was the neural
network architecture
we saw previously,
where it would input 12
numbers and output Q of s, a.
Whenever we are in some state s,
we would have to carry
out inference in
the neural network
separately four times to
compute these four
values so as to pick
the action a that gives
us the largest Q value.
This is inefficient
because we have to carry
our inference four times
from every single state.
Instead, it turns out
to be more efficient
to train a single
neural network to
output all four of these
values simultaneously.
This is what it looks like.
Here's a modified neural network
architecture where the input
is eight numbers corresponding
to the state of
the lunar lander.
It then goes through
the neural network
with 64 units in the
first hidden layer,
64 units in the
second hidden layer.
Now the output unit
has four output units,
and the job of the neural
network is to have
the four output
units output Q of s,
nothing, Q of s, left,
Q of s, main,
and q of s, right.
The job of the neural
network is to compute
simultaneously the Q value
for all four possible actions
for when we are in the state
s. This turns out to
be more efficient
because given the state
s we can run inference
just once and get all
four of these values,
and then very quickly
pick the action
a that maximizes Q of s, a.
You notice also in
Bellman's equations,
there's a step in which we
have to compute max over
a prime Q of s prime a prime,
this maximizes a gamma
and then there was
plus R of s up here.
This dual network also makes it
much more efficient
to compute this
because we're getting
Q of s prime a
prime for all actions a
prime at the same time.
You can then just pick
the max to compute
this value for
the right-hand side of
Bellman's equations.
This change to the neural
network architecture
makes the RN much
more efficient,
and so we will be using
this architecture in
the practice lab.
Next, there's one other
idea that'll help
the algorithm a
lot which is something called
an Epsilon-greedy policy,
which affects how you choose
actions even while
you're still learning.
Let's take a look
at the next video