In some applications,
when you take an action,
the outcome is not always
completely reliable.
For example, if you
command your Mars rover to
go left maybe there's a
little bit of a rock slide,
or maybe the floor is
really slippery and so
it slips and goes in
the wrong direction.
In practice, many robots don't
always manage to do
exactly what you
tell them because
of wind blowing
and off course and the wheel
slipping or something else.
There's a generalization of
the reinforcement
learning framework
we've talked about so far,
which models random or
stochastic environments.
In this optional video,
we'll talk about how
these reinforcement
learning problems work,
continuing with our simplifying
Mars Rover example,
let's say you take the action
and command it to go left.
Most of the time you'll
succeed but what if
10 percent of the time
or 0.1 of the time,
it actually ends up accidentally
slipping and going in
the opposite direction?
If you command it to go left,
it has a 90 percent
chance or 0.9
chance of correctly going
in the left direction.
But the 0.1 chance of actually
heading to the right
so that it has
a 9 percent chance of
ending up in say three in
this example and a
10 percent chance
of ending up in state five.
Conversely, if you
were to command it to
go right and take
the action, right,
it has a 0.9 chance
of ending up in state
five and 0.1 chance of
ending up in state three.
This would be an example of
a stochastic environment.
Let's see what happens in
this reinforcement
learning problem.
Let's say you use this
policy shown here,
where you go left in stages
2 3 4 and go rights or try
to go right in state five.
If you were to
start in state four
and you were to
follow this policy,
then the actual sequence of
states you visit may be random.
For example, in state four,
you will go left,
and maybe your loop and lucky,
and it actually gets
the state three,
and then you try
to go left again,
and maybe it
actually gets there.
You tell it to go left again,
and it gets to that state.
If this is what happens,
you end up with the
sequence of rewards 000100.
But if you were to try
this exact same policy
a second time,
maybe you're a
little less lucky,
the second time you start here.
Try to go left and
see it succeeds
so a zero from state four
zero from state three,
hear you tell it to go left,
but you've got unlucky
this time and the robot
slips and ends up heading
back to state four instead.
Then you're taught to
call left, and left,
and left, and eventually
get to that reward of 100.
In that case, this will
be the sequence of
rewards you observe.
This one from four to three
to four three two then one,
or is even possible,
if you tell from
state four to go
left following the
policy you may get
unlucky even on the
first step and you end
up going to state five
because it slipped.
Then state five, you
command it to go right,
and it succeeds as
you end up here.
In this case, the sequence of
rewards you see will be 0040,
because it went
from four to five,
and then states six,
we had previously
written out the return
as this sum of
discounted rewards.
But when
the reinforcement learning
problem is stochastic,
there isn't one sequence of
rewards that you see for
sure instead you see this
sequence of different rewards.
In a stochastic reinforcement
learning problem,
what we're interested in is not
maximizing the return because
that's a random number.
What we're interested
in is maximizing
the average value of the
sum of discounted rewards.
By average value, I mean if
you were to take your policy
and try it out a thousand
times or a 100,000 times
or a million times,
you get lots of different
reward sequences like
that and if you were
to take the average
over all of these
different sequences
of the sum of
discounted rewards,
then that's what we call
the expected return.
In statistics, the term expected
is just another way
of saying average.
But what this means is we want
to maximize what we expect
to get on average in
terms of the sum of
discounted rewards.
The mathematical
notation for this is to
write this as E. E stands
for expected value of R1 plus
Gamma R2 plus, and so on.
The job of reinforcement
learning algorithm is to choose
a policy Pi to maximize
the average or the expected
sum of discounted rewards.
To summarize, when you have
a stochastic reinforcement
learning problem or
a stochastic Markov
decision process
the goal is to choose a policy
to tell us what
action to take in
state S so as to maximize
the expected return.
The last way that this changes,
what we've talked about is it
modifies Bellman
equation a little bit.
Here's the Bellman equation
exactly as we've written down.
But the difference now is that
when you take the
action a in state s,
the next state s prime
you get to is random.
When you're in state 3
and you tell it to go
left the next state s prime
it could be the state 2,
or it could be the state 4.
S prime is now random,
which is why we also put
an average operator or
unexpected operator here.
We say that the total
return from state s,
taking action a, once in
a behaving optimally,
is equal to the reward
you get right away,
also called the immediate reward
plus the discount factor,
Gamma plus what you
expect to get on
average of the future returns.
If you want to sharpen
your intuition about what
happens with these
stochastic reinforcement
learning problems.
You'd go back to
the optional lab
that I had shown you just now,
where this parameter
misstep problem is
the probability of
your Mars Rover
going in the opposite direction,
than you had commanded it to.
If we said misstep
prop two is 0.1 and
re-execute the Notebook
and so these numbers
up here are the optimal return
if you were to take the
best possible actions,
take this optimal policy but
the robot were to step in
the wrong direction 10
percent of the time
and these are the q values
for this stochastic NTP.
Notice that these values
are now a little bit
lower because you can't
control the robot
as well as before.
The q values, as well
as the optimal returns,
have gone down a bit.
In fact, if you were to increase
the misstep probability,
say 40 percent of
the time the robot doesn't
even go into directions.
You're commanding it to only
60 percent of the time.
It goes where you told it to,
then these values end
up even lower because
your degree of control over
the robot has decreased.
I encourage you to play with
the optional lab and
change the value of
the misstep probability
and see how that
affects the for return or
the auto expected return,
as well as the Q
values, q of s a.
Now, in everything
we've done so far,
we've been using this
Markov decision process,
this Mars rover with
just six states.
For many practical applications,
the number of states
will be much larger.
In the next video,
we'll take the
reinforcement learning or
Markov decision
process framework
we've talked about so far and
generalize it to this much
richer and maybe even
more interesting set of
problems with much larger and in
particular with
continuous state spaces,
let's take a look at