We've developed a reinforcement
learning formalism
using the six state
Mars rover example.
Let's do a quick review of
the key concepts and also see
how this set of concepts can be
used for other
applications as well.
Some of the concepts
we've discussed
are states of a reinforcement
learning problem,
the set of actions, the rewards,
a discount factor,
then how rewards and
the discount factor altogether
use to compute the return,
and then finally, a
policy whose job it
is to help you pick actions
so as to maximize the return.
For the Mars rover example,
we had six states
that we numbered
1-6 and the actions were
to go left or to go right.
The rewards were 100
for the leftmost state,
40 for the rightmost state,
and zero in between
and I was using a
discount factor of 0.5.
The return was given by this
formula and we could have
different policies Pi depict
actions depending on
what state you're in.
This same formalism
or states, actions,
rewards, and so on can be used
for many other
applications as well.
Take the problem or find
an autonomous helicopter.
To set a state
would be the set of
possible positions
and orientations and
speeds and so on
of the helicopter.
The possible actions
would be the set of
possible ways to move
the controls stick
of a helicopter,
and the rewards may be a plus
one if it's flying well,
and a negative 1,000
if it doesn't fall
really bad or crashes.
Reward function that tells you
how well the
helicopter is flying.
The discount factor, a number
slightly less than
one maybe say,
0.99 and then based
on the rewards and
the discount factor,
you compute the return
using the same formula.
The job of a
reinforcement learning
algorithm would be to find
some policy Pi of s so
that given as input,
the position of
the helicopter s,
it tells you what
action to take.
That is, tells you how to
move the control sticks.
Here's one more example.
Here's a game-playing one.
Say you want to use
reinforcement learning
to learn to play chess.
The state of this problem would
be the position of all
the pieces on the board.
By the way, if you play chess
and know the rules well,
I know that's little
bit more information
than just the position of
the pieces is
important for chess,
but I'll simplify it a
little bit for this video.
The actions are the possible
legal moves in the game,
and then a common choice
of reward would be if you
give your system a reward of
plus one if it wins a game,
minus one if it loses the game,
and a reward of zero
if it ties a game.
For chess, usually
a discount factor
very close to one will be used,
so maybe 0.99 or even 0.995 or
0.999 and the return
uses the same formula as
the other applications.
Once again, the goal is given
a board position to pick a
good action using a policy Pi.
This formalism of a reinforcement
learning application
actually has a name.
It's called a Markov
decision process,
and I know that sounds like
a big technical
complicated term.
But if you ever hear this
term Markov decision process
or MDP for short,
that's just the formalism
that we've been
talking about in the
last few videos.
The term Markov in the MDP or
Markov decision process
refers to that the future
only depends on the current
state and not on anything
that might have occurred prior
to getting to the current state.
In other words, in a
Markov decision process,
the future depends only
on where you are now,
not on how you got here.
One other way to think of
the Markov decision
process formalism is
that we have a robot or
some other agent that
we wish to control
and what we get to do
is choose actions a and
based on those actions,
something will happen in the
world or in the environment,
such as our position in
the world changes or we
get to sample a piece of
rock and execute the
science mission.
The way we choose
the action a is with
a policy Pi and based on
what happens in the world,
we then get to see or we
observe back what
state we're in,
as well as what rewards
are that we get.
You sometimes see different
authors use a diagram like
this to represent the
Markov decision process or
the MDP formalism but this
is just another way of
illustrating the set of concepts
that you learn about in
the last few videos.
You now know how a reinforcement
learning problem works.
In the next video
we'll start to develop
an algorithm for
picking good actions.
The first step toward that
will be to define and then
eventually learn to compute
the state action value function.
This turns out to be one
of the key quantities
for when we want to develop
a learning algorithm.
Let's go onto the next
video to see what is this,