The lunar lander lets you land
a simulated vehicle on the moon.
It's like a fun little video game that's
been used by a lot of reinforcement
learning researchers.
Let's take a look at what it is.
In this application you're in command
of a lunar lander that is rapidly
approaching the surface of the moon.
And your job is the fire thrusters
at the appropriate times to land it
safely on the landing pad.
To give you a sense of what it looks like.
This is the lunar lander
landing successfully and
it's firing thrusters downward and
to the left and
right to position itself to land
between these two yellow flags.
Or if the reinforcement landing algorithm
policy does not do well then this is what
it might look like where the lander
unfortunately has trashed
on the surface of the moon.
In this application you have four
possible actions on every time step.
You could either do nothing,
in which case the forces of inertia and
gravity pull you towards
the surface of the moon.
Or you can fire a left thruster when you
see a little red dot come out on the left,
that's firing the left.
They'll tend to push the lunar
lander to the right or
you can fire the main engine that's
thrusting down the bottom here.
Or you can fire the right thruster and
that's firing the right thruster
which will push you to the left and
your job is to keep on
picking actions over time.
So it's the lunar lander safely between
these two flags here on the landing pad.
In order to give the actions a shorter
name I'm sometimes going to call
the actions nothing meaning do nothing or
left meaning farther left thruster or
main meaning fire the main
engine downward or right.
So I'm going to call
the actions nothing left.
Maine and write for
short later in this video.
How about the states face of this?
Mtp the states are its position X and Y.
So how far to the left or right and
how high up is it as well as
velocity x.y how fast is it
moving in the horizontal and
vertical directions and
then also is angle.
So how far is the lunar lander tilted
to the left or tilted to the right?
Is angular velocity fated not.
And then finally, because a small
difference in positioning makes a big
difference in whether or not it's landed.
We're going to have two other variables in
the state vector which we call l and r.
Which corresponds to whether the left
leg is grounded, meaning whether or not
the left leg is sitting on the ground as
well as r which corresponds to whether or
not the right leg is
sitting on the ground.
So whereas xy x.theta
theta.our numbers l and
r will be binary valued and
can take on only values zero or
one depending on whether the left and
right legs are touching the ground.
Finally his reward function for
the lunar lander.
If it manages to get to the landing pad,
didn't receive the reward between 100 and
140 depending on how well it's flown when
gotten to the center of the landing pad.
We also give it an additional reward for
moving toward or away from the pad so
it moves closer to the pad it receives
a positive reward and it moves away and
drifts away.
It receives a negative reward.
If it crashes it gets a large -100 reward,
it achieves a soft landing,
that is a landing.
There's another crash,
it gets a +100 reward for each leg,
the left leg or
the right link that it gets grounded.
It receives a +10 reward and
finally to encourage it not to waste too
much fuel and
fire thrusters aren't necessarily.
Every time it fires the main engine
we give it a -0.3 rewards and
every time it fires the left or the right
side thrusters we give it a -0.03 reward.
Notice that this is a moderately
complex reward function.
The designers of the lunar lander
application actually put some thought into
exactly what behavior you want and
codified it in the reward function.
To incentivize more of
the behaviors you want and
fear of the behaviors like
crashing that you don't want.
You find when you're building your own
reinforcement learning application
usually takes some thought to specify
exactly what you want or don't want and
to codify that in the reward function.
But specify the reward function should
still turn out to be much easier to
specify the exact right action
to take from every single state.
Which is much harder for this and many
other reinforcement learning applications.
So the lunar lander problem is as follows.
Our goal is to learn a policy pi.
That when given a state S as written
here picks an action a equals pi of S.
So as to maximize the return
the sum of discounted rewards.
And usually for the lunar lander would
use a fairly large value for gamma ra.
In fact for the would use the value
of camera that's equal to 0.985 so
pretty close to one.
And if you can learn a policy pi that
does this then you successfully land
this lunar lander exciting application and
we're now finally ready to
develop a learning algorithm which
will turn out to use deep learning or
neural networks to come up with
a policy to land the lunar lander.
Let's go into the next video where we