The learning algorithm
that we developed,
even while you're
still learning how
to approximate Q(s,a),
you need to take some
actions in the lunar lander.
How do you pick those actions
while you're still learning?
The most common way
to do so is to use
something called an
Epsilon-greedy policy.
Let's take a look
at how that works.
Here's the algorithm
that you saw earlier.
One of the steps in
the algorithm is
to take actions in
the lunar lander.
When the learning algorithm
is still running,
we don't really know what's
the best action to
take in every state.
If we did, we'd already
be done learning.
But even while we're still
learning and don't have
a very good estimate
of Q(s,a) yet,
how do we take actions
in this step of the
learning algorithm?
Let's look at some options.
When you're in some state s,
we might not want to take
actions totally at random
because that will
often be a bad action.
One natural option would be
to pick whenever in state s,
pick an action a that
maximizes Q(s,a).
We may say, even
if Q(s,a) is not
a great estimate
of the Q function,
let's just do our best
and use our current guess
of Q(s,a) and pick the
action a that maximizes it.
It turns out this may work okay,
but isn't the best option.
Instead, here's what
is commonly done.
Here's option 2,
which is most of the time,
let's say with
probability of 0.95,
pick the action that
maximizes Q(s,a).
Most of the time we try to pick
a good action using our
current guess of Q(s,a).
But the small fraction
of the time, let's say,
five percent of the time,
we'll pick an action a randomly.
Why do we want to occasionally
pick an action randomly?
Well, here's why.
Suppose there's
some strange reason that
Q(s,a) was initialized
randomly so that the
learning algorithm thinks
that firing the main thruster
is never a good idea.
Maybe the neural
network parameters
were initialized so that Q(s,
main) is always very low.
If that's the case,
then the neural network,
because it's trying
to pick the action
a that maximizes Q(s,a),
it will never ever try
firing the main thruster.
Because it never ever tries
firing the main thruster,
it will never learn that firing
the main thruster is actually
sometimes a good idea.
Because of the random
initialization,
if the neural network somehow
initially gets stuck in
this mind that some things are
bad idea, just by chance,
then option 1,
it means that it will never
try out those actions and
discover that maybe is
actually a good idea
to take that action,
like fire the main
thrusters sometimes.
Under option 2 on every step,
we have some small
probability of trying out
different actions so that
the neural network can
learn to overcome its own
possible preconceptions
about what might be
a bad idea that turns
out not to be the case.
This idea of picking
actions randomly is
sometimes called an
exploration step.
Because we're going to try
out something that may
not be the best idea,
but we're going to just try out
some action in some
circumstances,
explore and learn more
about an action in
the circumstance
where we may not have
had as much experience before.
Taking an action that
maximizes Q(s,a),
sometimes this is called a
greedy action because we're
trying to actually maximize
our return by picking this.
Or in the reinforcement
learning literature,
sometimes you'll also hear
this as an exploitation step.
I know that exploitation
is not a good thing,
nobody should ever
explore anyone else.
But historically, this
was the term used
in reinforcement
learning to say,
let's exploit everything we've
learned to do the best we can.
In the reinforcement
learning literature,
sometimes you hear
people talk about
the exploration versus
exploitation trade-off,
which refers to how often do
you take actions
randomly or take
actions that may not be the
best in order to learn more,
versus trying to maximize
your return by say,
taking the action that
maximizes Q (s,a).
This approach, that is
option 2, has a name,
is called an
Epsilon-greedy policy,
where here Epsilon is
0.05 is the probability of
picking an action randomly.
This is the most
common way to make
your reinforcement
learning algorithm
explore a little bit,
even whilst
occasionally or maybe
most of the time
taking greedy actions.
By the way, lot of people
have commented that
the name Epsilon-greedy
policy is confusing because
you're actually being greedy
95 percent of the time,
not five percent of the time.
So maybe 1 minus
Epsilon-greedy policy,
because it's 95 percent greedy,
five percent exploring, that's
actually a more accurate
description of the algorithm.
But for historical reasons,
the name Epsilon-greedy
policy is what has stuck.
This is the name that
people use to refer to
the policy that explores
actually Epsilon fraction
of the time rather
than this greedy Epsilon
fraction of the time.
Lastly, one of the trick
that's sometimes used in
reinforcement learning is
to start off Epsilon high.
Initially, you are taking
random actions a lot at
a time and then
gradually decrease it,
so that over time you are
less likely to take
actions randomly and
more likely to use
your improving estimates of
the Q-function to
pick good actions.
For example, in the
lunar lander exercise,
you might start off with
Epsilon very, very high,
maybe even Epsilon equals 1.0.
You're just picking
actions completely at
random initially and then
gradually decrease it all
the way down to say 0.01,
so that eventually you're
taking greedy actions
99 percent of
the time and acting
randomly only a very small
one percent of the time.
If this seems complicated,
don't worry about it.
We'll provide the code
in the Jupiter lab that
shows you how to do this.
If you were to implement
the algorithm as we've
described it with
the more efficient neural
network architecture and with
an Epsilon-greedy
exploration policy,
you find that they work pretty
well on the lunar lander.
One of the things
that I've noticed for
reinforcement
learning algorithm is
that compared to
supervised learning,
they're more finicky in terms
of the choice of
hyper parameters.
For example, in
supervised learning,
if you set the learning rate
a little bit too small,
then maybe the algorithm
will take longer to learn.
Maybe it takes three
times as long to train,
which is annoying, but
maybe not that bad.
Whereas in
reinforcement learning,
find that if you set
the value of Epsilon
not quite as well,
or set other parameters
it doesn't take three
times as long to learn.
It may take 10 times or a
100 times as long to learn.
Reinforcement
learning algorithms,
I think because they're are
less mature than supervised
learning algorithms,
are much more finicky to
little choices of
parameters like that,
and it actually sometimes is
frankly more frustrating to
tune these parameters with
reinforcement learning
algorithm compared
to a supervised
learning algorithm.
But again, if you're
worried about
the practice lab, the
program exercise,
we'll give you a sense of
good parameters to use
in the program exercise
so that you should
be able to do that
and successfully learn
the lunar lander,
hopefully without
too many problems.
In the next optional video,
I want us to drive a couple
more algorithm refinements,
mini batching, and also
using soft updates.
Even without these
additional refinements,
the algorithm will work okay,
but these are additional
refinements that make
the algorithm run much faster.
It's okay if you
skip this video,
we've provided
everything you need in
the practice lab to hopefully
successfully complete it.
But if you're interested
in learning about more of
these details of two
named reinforcement
learning algorithms,
then come with me and let's
see in the next video,