To finish out the reinforcement
learning formalism,
instead of looking
at something as
complicated as a
helicopter or a robot dog,
we can use a simplified example
that's loosely inspired
by the Mars rover.
This is adapted from
the example due to
Stanford professor
Emma Branskill and one of
my collaborators,
Jagriti Agrawal,
who had actually
written code that
is actually controlling
the Mars rover
right now that also helped me
talk through and helped
develop this example.
Let's take a look. We'll
develop reinforcement learning
using a simplified example
inspired by the Mars rover.
In this application,
the rover can
be in any of six positions,
as shown by the six boxes here.
The rover, it might
start off, say,
in disposition into
fourth box shown here.
The position of
the Mars rover is
called the state in
reinforcement learning,
and I'm going to call
these six states,
state 1, state 2,
state 3, state 4,
state 5, and state 6,
and so the rover is
starting off in state 4.
Now the rover was
sent to Mars to
try to carry out different
science missions.
It can go to different places to
use its sensors such as
a drill, or a radar,
or a spectrometer to
analyze the rock at different
places on the planet,
or go to different
places to take
interesting pictures for
scientists on earth to look at.
In this example, state
1 here on the left has
a very interesting surface that
scientists would love
for the rover to sample.
State 6 also has
a pretty interesting
surface that
scientists would quite
like the rover to sample,
but not as interesting
as state 1.
We would more
likely to carry out
the science mission ant
state 1 than at state 6,
but state 1 is further away.
The way we will
reflect state 1 being
potentially more valuable is
through the reward function.
The reward at state 1 is a 100,
and the reward at stage 6 is 40,
and the rewards at all of
the other states in-between,
I'm going to write as a reward
of zero because there's
not as much
interesting science to
be done at these states 2,
3, 4, and 5.
On each step, the rover gets
to choose one of two actions.
It can either go to the left
or it can go to the right.
The question is, what
should the rover do?
In reinforcement
learning, we pay
a lot of attention
to the rewards
because that's how we know if
the robot is doing
well or poorly.
Let's look at some
examples of what might
happen if the robot
was to go left,
starting from state 4.
Then initially
starting from state 4,
it will receive a
reward of zero,
and after going left,
it gets to state 3,
where it receives again
a reward of zero.
Then it gets to state 2,
receives the reward is 0,
and finally just to state 1,
where it receives
a reward of 100.
For this application,
I'm going to assume that
when it gets either
state 1 or state 6,
that the day ends.
In reinforcement learning,
we sometimes call this
a terminal state,
and what that means is that,
after it gets to one of
these terminals states,
gets a reward at that state,
but then nothing
happens after that.
Maybe the robots run out of
fuel or ran out of
time for the day,
which is why it only
gets to either enjoy
the 100 or the 40 reward,
but then that's it for the day.
It doesn't get to earn
additional rewards after that.
Now instead of going left,
the robot could also
choose to go to the right,
in which case from state 4,
it would first have
a reward of zero,
and then it'll move right
and get to state 5,
have another reward of zero,
and then it will get to this
other terminal
state on the right,
state 6 and get a reward of 40.
But going left and going
right are the only options.
One thing the robot could
do is it can start from
state 4 and decide to
move to the right.
It goes from state 4-5,
gets a reward of zero in state
4 and a reward of
zero in state 5,
and then maybe it changes its
mind and decides to start
going to the left as
follows, in which case,
it will get a reward of zero
at state 4, at state 3,
at state 2, and then the reward
of 100 when it gets to state 1.
In this sequence of
actions and states,
the robot is wasting
better time.
So this maybe isn't such a
great way to take actions,
but it is one choice that
the algorithm could pick,
but hopefully you
won't pick this one.
To summarize, at
every time step,
the robot is in some state,
which I'll call S,
and it gets to choose an action,
and it also enjoys some rewards,
R of S that it gets
from that state.
As a result of this action,
it to some new state S prime.
As a concrete example,
when the robot was in state
4 and it took the action,
go left, maybe didn't
enjoy the reward of
zero associated with that state
4 and it won't have
any new state 3.
When you learn about
specific reinforcement
learning algorithms,
you see that these four things,
the state, action, the
reward and next state,
which is what happens
basically every
time you take an
action that just
be a core elements of
what reinforcement
learning algorithms will
look at when deciding
how to take actions.
Just for clarity,
the reward here,
R of S, this is the reward
associated with this state.
This reward of
zero is associated
with state 4 rather
than with state 3.
That's the formalism of how
a reinforcement learning
application works.
In the next video,
let's take a look
at how we specify
exactly what we want
the reinforcement
learning algorithm to do.
In particular, we'll talk
about an important idea in
reinforcement learning
called the return.
Let's go on to the next video