Reinforcement learning is
an exciting set of technologies.
In fact, when I was working on my
PhD thesis reinforcement learning
was the subject of my thesis.
So I was and
still am excited about these ideas.
Despite all the research momentum and
excitement behind reinforcement learning
though, I think there is a bit or
maybe sometimes a lot of hype around it.
So what I hope to do is share with you
a practical sense of where reinforcement
learning is today in terms of
his utility for applications.
One of the reasons for some of the hype
about reinforcement learning is, it turns
out many of the research publications
have been on simulated environments.
And having worked in both simulations and
on real robots myself,
I can tell you that it's much easier
to get a reinforcement learning album
to work in a simulation or
in a video game than in a real robot.
So a lot of developers have commented
that even after they got it to work in
simulation, it turned out to
be surprisingly challenging
to get something to work in
the real world or the real robot.
And so if you apply these
algorithms to a real application,
this is one limitation that I hope you pay
attention to to make sure what you do does
work on the real application.
Second, despite all the media coverage
about reinforcement learning,
today there are far fewer applications of
reinforcement learning than supervised and
unsupervised learning.
So if you are building
a practical application,
the odds that you will find
supervised learning or
unsupervised learning useful or
the right tool for the job,
is much higher than the odds that you
would end up using reinforcement learning.
I have used reinforcement learning a few
times myself especially on robotic control
applications, but in my day to day applied
work, I end up using supervising and
supervised learning much more.
There is a lot of exciting research
in reinforcement learning right now,
and I think the potential of
reinforcement learning for
future applications is very large.
And reinforcement learning still
remains one of the major pillars of
machine learning.
And so having it as a framework as
you develop your own machine learning
algorithms, I hope will make you
more effective at building working
machine learning systems as well.
So I hope you've enjoyed this week's
materials on reinforcement learning, and
specifically I hope you have fun getting
the lunar lander to land for yourself.
I hope will be a satisfying experience
when you implement an algorithm and
then see that lunar lander land safely on
the moon because of code that you wrote.
That brings us towards the end
of this specialization.
Let's go on to the last