Let me summarize where we are.
If you can compute
the state action value
function Q of S,
A, then it gives you a way to
pick a good action
from every scene.
Just pick the action A,
that gives you the largest
value of Q of S,A.
The question is,
how do you compute
these values Q of S,A?
In reinforcement learning,
there's a key equation called
the Bellman equation
that will help us to
compute the state
action value function.
Let's take a look at
what is this equation.
As a reminder, this is the
definition of Q of S, A.
It's return if we
start in state S,
take the action a once and they
behave optimally after that.
In order to describe
the Bellman equation,
I'm going to use the
following notation.
I'm going to use S to
denote the current state.
Next, I'm going to use R of S
to denote the rewards
of the current state.
For our little MDP example,
we will have that r
of one State1 is 100.
The reward of State
2 is 0, and so on.
The reward of State 6 is 40.
I'm going to use
the alphabet A to denote
the current action,
the action that you take in
the state S. After you
take the action a,
you get to some new state.
For example, if you're in State
4 and you take the action left,
then you get to State 3.
I'm going to use
S prime to denote
the state you get to after
taking that action a
from the current state S.
I'm also going to use A prime to
denote the action that you
might take in state S prime,
the new steady you got to.
The notation
convention, by the way,
is that S,A correspond to the
current state and action.
When we add the prime,
that's the next state,
then the next action.
The Bellman equation
is the following.
It says that Q of S,A,
that is the return
under this set of
assumptions that's
equal to r of S,
says reward you get for
being in that state plus
the discount factor Gamma times
max over all possible actions,
a prime of q of S prime,
the new state you just got to,
and then a prime.
There's a lot going
on in this equation.
Let's first take a
look at some examples.
We'll come back to see why
this equation might make sense.
Let's look at an example.
Let's look at Q of
State 2 and action.
Apply Bellman Equation to
this to see what
value it gives us.
If the current state is state
two and that the
action is to go right,
then the next day you get to,
after going write S prime
would be the State 3.
The Bellman equation
says Q of 2,
right is R of S. This R State 2,
which is just the rewards
zero plus the discount
factor Gamma,
which we set to 0.5
in this example,
times max of the Q values in
state S prime in State 3.
This is going to be the
max of 25 and 6.25,
since this is max
over a prime of
q of S prime comma a prime.
This is taking the
larger of 25 or
6.25 because those are the
two choices for State 3.
This turns out to be equal
to zero plus 0.5 times 25,
which is equal to 12.5,
which fortunately is Q of two
and then the action right.
Let's look at just
one more example.
Let me take the
State 4 and see what
is Q of State 4 if you
decide to go left.
In this case, the
current state is
four current action
is to go left.
The next state, if you can
start from four going left.
You end up also at State 3.
Let us prime this three
again, the Bellman Equation,
we'll say this is equal to
R of S. Our State four,
which is zero plus 0.5
the discount factor
Gamma of max over a
prime of q of S prime.
That is the State 3
again, comma a prime.
Once again, the Q values
for State 3 are 25 and
6.25 and the larger
of these is 25.
This works out to be our
40 plus 0.5 times 25,
which is again equal to 12.5.
That's why q of four
with the action
left is also equal to 12.5,
just one note, if you're
in a terminal state,
then Bellman Equation
simplifies to q of SA equals to
r of S because there's
no state S prime and so that
second term would go away.
Which is why Q
of S,A in the terminal
states is just 100,
100 or 40 40.
If you wish feel free to pause
the video and apply the
Bellman Equation to
any other state action in
this MDP and check for yourself
if this math works out.
Just to recap, this is how
we had define Q of S,A.
We saw earlier that the
best possible return from
any state S is max
over a Q of S,A.
In fact, just to rename SNA,
it turns out that the
best possible return
from a state S prime,
is max over S prime of a prime.
I didn't really do anything
other than rename S,
S prime and a to a prime.
But this will make some of
the intuitions a little
bit easier later.
But for any state S prime,
like State 3, the best
possible return from, say,
State 3 is the max over
all possible actions of
Q of S prime E prime.
Here again is the
Bellman equation.
The intuition that this
captures is if you're starting
from state s and
you're going to take
action a and then act
optimally after that,
then you're going to see
some sequence of
rewards over time.
In particular, the return will
be computed from the
reward at the first step,
plus Gamma times reward
at the second step
plus Gamma squared
times reward at
the third step, and so on.
Plus dot, dot, dot until you
get to the terminal state.
What Bellman equation says
is this sequence of rewards,
what the discount factor is,
can be broken down
into two components.
First, this R of s,
that's the reward
you get right away.
In the reinforcement
learning literature,
this is sometimes also
called the immediate reward,
but that's what R_1 is.
It's the reward you get for
starting out in some state
s. The second term
then is the following;
after you start in state
s and take action a,
you get to some
new state s prime.
The definition of Q of s,
a assumes we're going to
behave optimally after that.
After we get to s prime,
we are going to behave
optimally and get
the best possible return
from the state s prime.
What this is, max of a prime
of Q of s prime a prime,
this is the return from
behaving optimally,
starting from the state s prime.
That's exactly what we
had written up here,
is the best possible return
for when you start
from state s prime.
Another way of phrasing this is
this total return down here
is also equal to R_1 plus,
and then we're going to
factor out Gamma in the map,
is Gamma times R_2 plus,
and instead of Gamma
squared is just Gamma times
R_3 plus Gamma squared
times R_4 plus dot dot dot.
Notice that if you were
starting from state s prime,
the sequence of rewards
you get will be R_2,
R_3, then R_4, and so on.
That's why this expression here,
that's the total return
if you were to start
from state s prime.
If you were to behave optimally,
then this expression should be
the best possible return for
starting from state s prime,
which is why this sequence of
discount rewards
equals that max of
a prime of Q of s prime a
prime and there were also
leftover with this extra
discount factor Gamma there,
which is why Q of s,
a is also equal to this
expression over here.
In case you think this
is quite complicated and
you aren't following
all the details,
don't worry about it.
So long as you apply
this equation,
you will manage to get
the right results.
But the high level intuition
I hope you take away is that
the total return you get
in the reinforcement learning
problem has two parts.
The first part is this reward
that you get right away,
and then the second part is
Gamma times the return
you get starting from
the next state s prime.
As these two
components together,
R of s plus Gamma times the
return from the next state,
that is equal to the
total return from the
current state s. That
is the essence of the
Bellman equation.
Just to relate this back
to our earlier example,
Q of 4, left.
That's the total
return for starting
State 4 and going left.
If you were to go left in State
4 the rewards you get
are 0 in State 4,
0 in State 3,
0 in State 2, and then 100,
which is why the
total return is this;
0.5 squared plus 0.5
cubed, which was 12.5.
What Bellman equation
is saying is
that we can break this
up into two pieces.
There is this zero,
which is R of the state four,
and then plus 0.5 times
this other sequence,
0 plus 0.50 plus 0.5
squared times 100.
But if you look at
what this sequence is,
this is really the
optimal return from
the next state s
prime that you got to
after taking the action
left from state four.
That's why this is equal
to the reward 4 plus
0.5 times the optimal
return from State 3.
Because if you were to
start from State 3,
the rewards you
get would be zero
followed by zero
followed by 100,
so this is optimal return from
State 3 and that's why this is
just R of 4 plus 0.5 max over
a prime Q of State 3, a prime.
I know the Bellman equation,
this is somewhat complicated
equation breaking down
your total returns into
the reward you're
getting right away.
The immediate reward plus
Gamma times the returns from
the next state s prime.
If it makes sense to you,
but not fully, it's okay.
Don't worry about it.
You can still apply
Bellman's equations
to get a reinforcement
learning algorithm
to work correctly,
but I hope that at least
the high level intuition
of why breaking
down the rewards into
what you get right
away plus what you
get in the future.
I hope that makes sense.
Before moving on to
develop a reinforcement
learning algorithm,
we have coming up next
an optional video on
Stochastic Markov
decision processes or
on reinforcement learning
applications where the actions,
if you take, can have a
slightly random effect.
Take look at the optional
video if you wish.
Then after that, we'll start to
develop a reinforcement