You saw in the last video,
what are the states of
reinforcement
learning application,
as well as how depending
on the actions
you take you go through
different states,
and also get to enjoy
different rewards.
But how do you know if a
particular set of rewards is
better or worse than a
different set of rewards?
The return in
reinforcement learning,
which we'll define
in this video,
allows us to capture that.
As we go through this,
one analogy that you
might find helpful
is if you imagine
you have a five-dollar
bill at your feet,
you can reach down and pick up,
or half an hour across town,
you can walk half an hour and
pick up a 10-dollar bill.
Which one would you
rather go after?
Ten dollars is much
better than five dollars,
but if you need to
walk for half an hour
to go and get that
10-dollar bill,
then maybe it'd be more
convenient to just pick up
the five-dollar bill instead.
The concept of a return captures
that rewards you can get
quicker are maybe
more attractive than
rewards that take you
a long time to get to.
Let's take a look at
exactly how that works.
Here's a Mars Rover example.
If starting from state
4 you go to the left,
we saw that the
rewards you get would
be zero on the first
step from state 4,
zero from state 3,
zero from state 2,
and then 100 at state
1, the terminal state.
The return is defined as the sum
of these rewards but weighted
by one additional factor,
which is called the
discount factor.
The discount factor is a number
a little bit less than 1.
Let me pick 0.9 as
the discount factor.
I'm going to weight the reward
in the first step is just zero,
the reward in the second
step is a discount factor,
0.9 times that reward,
and then plus the discount
factor^2 times that reward,
factor^3 times that reward.
If you calculate this out,
this turns out to be 0.729
times 100, which is 72.9.
The more general formula
for the return is that if
your robot goes through
some sequence of
states and gets reward
R_1 on the first step,
and R_2 on the second step,
and R_3 on the third step,
and so on,
then the return is R_1 plus
the discount factor Gamma,
this Greek alphabet Gamma
which I've set to
0.9 in this example,
the Gamma times R_2
plus Gamma^2 times R_3
plus Gamma^3 times R_4,
and so on, until you get
to the terminal state.
What the discount factor
Gamma does is it has
the effect of making
the reinforcement
learning algorithm
a little bit impatient.
Because the return
gives full credit to
the first reward is 100
percent is 1 times R_1,
but then it gives a
little bit less credit to
the reward you get
at the second step
is multiplied by 0.9,
and then even less
credit to the reward you
get at the next time step R_3,
and so on, and so
getting rewards
sooner results in a higher
value for the total return.
In many reinforcement
learning algorithms,
a common choice for
the discount factor will be
a number pretty close to 1,
like 0.9, or 0.99,
or even 0.999.
But for illustrative purposes
in the running example
I'm going to use,
I'm actually going to use
a discount factor of 0.5.
This very heavily
down weights or
very heavily we say discounts
rewards in the future,
because with every additional
parsing timestamp,
you get only half
as much credit as
rewards that you would have
gotten one step earlier.
If Gamma were equal to 0.5,
the return under the example
above would have been
0 plus 0.5 times 0,
replacing this equation on top,
plus 0.5^2 0 plus
0.5^3 times 100.
That's lost reward because
state 1 to terminal state,
and this turns out to
be a return of 12.5.
In financial applications,
the discount factor also has
a very natural interpretation as
the interest rate or the
time value of money.
If you can have a dollar today,
that may be worth
a little bit more
than if you could only get
a dollar in the future.
Because even a dollar today
you can put in the bank,
earn some interest,
and end up with
a little bit more
money a year from now.
For financial
applications, often,
that discount factor
represents how much less
is a dollar in the future where
I've compared to a dollar today.
Let's look at some concrete
examples of returns.
The return you get
depends on the rewards,
and the rewards depends
on the actions you take,
and so the return depends
on the actions you take.
Let's use our usual example
and say for this example,
I'm going to always
go to the left.
We already saw
previously that if
the robot were to
start off in state 4,
the return is 12.5 as
we worked out on
the previous slide.
It turns out that if it were
to start off in say three,
the return would be
25 because it gets
to the 100 reward
one step sooner,
and so it's discounted less.
If it were to start
off in state 2,
the return would be 50.
If it were to just start
off and state 1, well,
it gets the reward
of 100 right away,
so it's not discounted low.
The return if we
were to start out in
state 1 will be 100,
and then the return in
these two states are 6.25.
It turns out if you
start off in state 6,
which is terminal state,
you just get the reward
and thus the return of 40.
Now, if you were to take a
different set of actions,
the returns would
actually be different.
For example, if we were to
always go to the right,
if those were our actions,
then if you were to start in
state 4, get a reward of 0.
Then you get to state
5, get a reward of 0,
and it gets to state 6,
and get a reward of 40.
In this case, the return
would be 0 plus 0.5,
the discount factor times 0
plus 0.5 squared times 40,
and that turns out to be
equal to 0.5 squared is 1/4,
so 1/4 of 40 is 10.
The return from this state,
from state 4 is 10.
If you were to take actions,
always go to the right.
Through similar reasoning,
the return from
this state is 20,
this state is five,
the return from
this state is 2.5,
and then the return,
the determinant state is is 140.
By the way,
if these numbers don't
fully make sense,
feel free to pause the video and
double-check the
math and see if you
can convince yourself that these
are the appropriate
values for the return.
For if you start from
different states,
and if you were to
always go to the right.
We see that it would
The return you expect to get
is lower for most states.
Maybe always going
to the right isn't
as good an idea as always
going to the left.
But it turns out that we
don't have to always
go to the left,
always go to the right.
We could also decide if
you're in state 2, go left.
If your in state 3, go left.
If you're in state 4, go left.
But if you're in state 5,
then you're so close
to this reward.
Let's go right.
This will be a different
way of choosing
actions to take based on
what state you're in.
It turns out that the return
you get from the different
states will be 100, 50, 25,
12.5, 20, and 40.
Just to illustrate one case.
If you were to start
off in state 5,
here you would go to the right,
and so the rewards
you get would be
zero first in state
5, and then 4.
The return is zero,
the first reward,
plus the discount factor is
0.5 times 40, which is 20,
which is why the return
from this status
20 if you take
actions shown here.
To summarize, the return in
reinforcement
learning is the sum
of the rewards that
the system gets,
weighted by the discount factor,
where rewards in the
far future are weighted
by the discount factor
raised to a higher power.
Now, this actually has
an interesting
effect when you have
systems with negative rewards.
In the example we went through,
all the rewards were
zero or positive.
But if there are any
rewards are negative,
then the discount
factor actually
incentivizes the system to
push out the negative rewards
as far into the
future as possible.
Taking a financial example,
if you had to pay someone $10,
maybe that's a negative
reward of minus 10.
But if you could postpone
payment by a few years,
then you're actually better off
because $10 a few
years from now,
because of the interest
rate is actually worth
less than $10 that
you had to pay today.
For systems with
negative rewards,
it causes the algorithm
to try to push
out the make the rewards
as far into the
future as possible.
For financial applications
and for other applications,
that actually turns out
to be right thing for
the system to do.
You now know what
is the return in
reinforcement learning,
let's go on to the next video to
formalize the goal of