Many robotic control
applications,
including the lunar
lander application
that you work on in
the practice lab,
have continuous state spaces.
Let's take a look at what that
means and how to generalize
the concept we've
talked about to
these continuous state spaces.
A simplify Mars rover
example we use,
I use a discrete set of states,
and what that means is that
simplify Mars rover could
only be in one of six
possible positions.
But most robots can be
in more than one of
six or any discrete
number of positions,
instead, they can be in any of
a very large number of
continuous value positions.
For example, if the Mars rover
could be anywhere on a line,
so its position was indicated
by a number ranging from
0-6 kilometers where any
number in between is valid.
That would be an example of
a continuous state space,
because the position would be
represented by a
number such as that is
2.7 kilometers along or
4.8 kilometers or any other
number between zero and six.
Let's look at another example.
I'm going to use
for this example,
the application of
controlling a car or a truck.
Here's a toy car,
Russia toy truck.
This one belongs to my daughter.
If you're building a
self-driving car or
self-driving truck and you want
to control this to
drive smoothly,
then the state of this truck
might include a few
numbers such as this,
x position, its y position,
maybe it's orientation.
What way is it facing?
Assuming the truck
stays on the ground,
you probably don't need to worry
about how tall is,
how high up it is.
This is state will include x,
y, and is angle Theta,
as well as maybe its
speeds in x-direction,
the speed in the y-direction,
and how quickly it's turning.
Is it turning at one degree
per second or is it turning at
30 degrees per second
or is it turning
really quickly at 90
degrees per second?
For a truck or a car,
the state might include
not just one number,
like how many kilometers of
this along on this line,
but they might
includes six numbers,
is x position,
is y position, is orientation,
which I'm going to denote
using Greek alphabet Theta,
as well its velocity
in the x-direction,
which I will denote using x dot,
so that means how quickly is
this x-coordinate changing,
y dot how quickly is the y
coordinate changing,
and then finally,
Theta dot, which
is how quickly is
the angle of the car changing.
Whereas for the 60
Mars rover example,
the state was just one
of six possible numbers.
It could be one, two,
three, four, five or six.
For the car, the state would
comprise this vector
of six numbers,
and any of these
numbers can take on
any value within is valid range.
For example, Theta should range
between zero and 360 degrees.
Let's look at another example.
What if you're building
a reinforcement
learning algorithm to
control an autonomous
helicopter,
how would you characterize
the position of a helicopter?
To illustrate, I
have with me here
a small toy helicopter.
The positioning of
the helicopter would
include is x position,
such as how far north or south
is a helicopter, is y position.
Maybe how far on the east-west
axis is the helicopter,
and then also z, the height of
the helicopter above ground.
But other than the position,
the helicopter also has
an orientation, and
conventionally,
one way to capture
its orientation
is with three
additional numbers,
one of which captures of
the row of the helicopter.
Is it rolling to the
left or the right?
The pitch, is it pitching
forward or pitching
up, pitching back,
and then finally the yaw which
is west the compass
orientation is it facing.
If facing north or
east or south or west?
To summarize, the state
of the helicopter
includes is position in the
say, north-south direction,
is positioned in the
east-west direction,
y is height above ground,
and also the row,
the pitch, and also
that yaw of helicopter.
To write this down,
the state therefore includes
the position x, y, z,
and then the row pitch,
and yaw denoted with
the Greek alphabets
Phi, Theta and Omega.
But to control the helicopter,
we also need to know its
speed in the x-direction,
in the y-direction, and
in the z direction,
as well as its rate of turning,
also called the
angular velocity.
How fast is this row
changing and how fast is
this pitch changing and how
fast is its yaw changing?
This is actually the state
used to control
autonomous helicopters.
Is this list of 12 numbers
that is input to a policy,
and the job of a
policy is look at
these 12 numbers and decide
what's an appropriate action
to take in the helicopter.
So any continuous state
reinforcement learning problem or
a continuous state
Markov decision process,
continuously MTP.
The state of the
problem isn't just one
of a small number of
possible discrete values,
like a number from 1-6.
Instead, it's a
vector of numbers,
any of which could take any
of a large number of values.
In the practice
lab for this week,
you get to implement for
yourself a reinforcement
learning algorithm
applied to a simulated
lunar lander application.
Landing something on
the moon is simulation.
Let's take a look in
the next video at
what that application entails,
since there will be another