[MUSIC]
Thanks for joining me here at Stanford
University, with Professor Chelsea Finn,
who is with both the computer science and
the electrical engineering departments.
Chelsea is a research lab
that does cutting edge work,
applying machine learning,
especially reinforcement learning,
to a range of robotics applications.
So I'm really glad to
have you here Chelsea.
>> Happy to be here.
>> So, I know that before you settled
into working on computer science and
machine learning, you actually considered
a lot of career options ranging
from biology to aerospace to computer
science and electric engine.
So, what made you make this choice?
Yeah, so I was always drawn to engineering
because I really like solving puzzles and
solving problems.
And when I arrived at MIT for
my undergraduate,
I was considering different
engineering majors.
And what really drew me first
to computer science was that,
it gives you a lot of flexibility in terms
of the different paths that you can do.
Essentially computer science empowers you
to build lots of different things with
software, with code and with that,
I could eventually go into biology.
If I wanted to, I could go into robotics,
there's all sorts of really exciting
things you can do with computer science.
So that landed me in computer science and
then once I decided on that, I really
enjoyed a lot of the math that goes behind
AI like probability and statistics.
And I was also really drawn to this
challenge of how can we build a computer,
that can see like humans do.
That can perceive things and images and
can take actions in the world, yeah.
>> So it was almost as if your choice
was if you do computer science,
you could do anything.
And so that makes it, I guess what mason
said software is eating the world.
And I think Jen Huang said
AI is eating software,
and it feels like when you
work in machine learning,
you get to poke your nose in all
corners of the world and do fun things.
>> Absolutely, I think machine learning
is a really exciting place to be.
And I mentioned that computer science is
very flexible and opens lots of doors, and
I think that machine learning
is very similar to that.
There's so many different things you
can do with machine learning, and so
many different applications.
I'm really excited about
applications in robotics.
But, we've seen lots of
different applications in
language processing in biology and
in other fields.
>> So your specialization,
of the many things you do,
a large fraction of your
work is in robotics.
And, when people look at
the popular media or social media,
you see these videos of for example,
humanoid robots jumping up and
down and doing and
they do incredible things.
How should one think about what robots
really can and cannot do today?
Because there are these amazing demo
videos that looks like can do almost
anything.
But, how should one decide
what is actually doable?
>> Yeah, the videos that we see
online from Boston Dynamics for
example of robots doing back flips or
doing Parkour and of course.
Are really impressive,
because they look really complicated.
It's really easy in some ways
anthropomorphize the robot and
think that if you saw a person doing that,
that would be very impressive.
And they would probably be able to do
lots of other really impressive things.
And the catch is that in
robotics in those videos and
in many impressive
demonstrations of robotics.
The robot was set up for
that particular environment, and
it was tuned to do well with that set up.
And if you change something
about the environment,
about the setup about what it's supposed
to do, then the demo no longer works.
The the robot will fall flat.
So, the really the big challenge with
robotics is getting robots to generalize,
to be able to handle lots of different
scenarios with lots of different objects,
with lots of different environments.
And right now, robots can do things in
very controlled environments like in
factories and
they are very useful in factories.
And, what I'm really excited about and
what's really hard in robotics is
giving them the flexibility in generality
that of the skills that humans can do.
>> Just to dig a little bit more
into the specific one off one
environment thing before
going into generality.
When someone sees the next cool robotics
demo, how should they think about it or
what the questions they
should ask themselves?
>> Yeah, so I think that the first
question that someone can ask is,
what will happen if something
changes in the environment.
What will happen if you move a block or
if you put the robot in a slightly
different position when it starts.
Oftentimes you don't see those kinds
of tests of the system's robustness or
resilience to those variations.
And, if you do start seeing those those
demos where actually you kind of poke
the robot, or you change the environment
a little bit and it still works.
That's when I think we
can be really impressed.
>> Cool, so a lot of your work has
specifically been on making robots robust,
to generalize or
apply to lots of different environments.
Just tell me more about that work and
how you approach this problem.
>> Definitely, so in other areas of
machine learning we've seen huge successes
where we take a very large data set.
Like you take all of Wikipedia, and
you train a neural network to be able
to model the data in that very large and
broad data set.
And in robotics, one thing that I'm
excited about is if we can somewhat
replicate that sort of success.
If we can collect a similarly
diverse data set and
allow robots to learn from that data set.
Now, this is challenging for a couple of
reasons, one is that we don't already have
an existing data set, we don't have
Wikipedia for robot motor control.
There isn't data lying on the internet,
of how exactly to move a robot's
fingers to tie shoes, for example.
So we don't have tons of diverse
data already, but fortunately,
robots in principle should be
able to collect data themselves.
And, that is an opportunity because
it means that we might be able to
collect a large amount of diverse data,
by allowing the robots to
collect their own data.
But it's also a challenge because it means
that we need to figure out how to allow
robots to collect data that's useful,
and diverse.
And so, there's lots of different things
that we explore in terms of approaching
this problem, some is allowing
robots to collect their own data in
lots of different environments.
Some is showing demonstrations to a robot,
of how to perform a task.
We've also explored a little bit of
how to use data from the internet,
like videos of humans to show
a robot how to do a task.
And incorporating all of these different
data sources to allow robots to, well,
once they've hopefully seen very
diverse data sets like this.
They might be able to generalize not
just to the one scenario that they saw,
in a lab environment but
possibly the real world in the long term.
>> One of the things we've seen is
machine learning reinforcement learning,
our rooms are great at
playing video games.
Because you can get, essentially infinite
data playing a video game with yourself.
What do you think of
the role of simulation.
Yeah, so we've definitely
seen lots of successes of AI
systems doing very well at video games.
And simulation is somewhat similar
because we can collect lots of data in
simulation as well.
One challenge with simulation is that,
the physics in the simulation engine are
not exactly the same as the real world.
We know generally the laws of physics but,
the friction on a table, for example,
may not be exactly known.
Or the friction between
the grooves on a cap and
a water bottle if you try
to **** a water bowl,
modeling that is very difficult and
there are it's prone to errors.
And then when you try to train a policy in
that simulator to close a water bottle,
for example, And
then deploy it in the real world.
It actually doesn't work because
of those errors in the simulation.
So I think it's a promising data source.
But because of these inaccuracies and
this challenge of transferring something
that was learned in
simulation to the real world.
I don't think it's the only
approach that we should bet on.
I think that we should try to
leverage lots of real data.
>> And I want to be surprising
to someone watching this,
why is it so
hot to simulate the real world?
It's just a lot of bottles
two pieces of plastic and
somehow we can't seem to figure out what's
going on with two pieces of plastic.
>> Yeah.
So
I think that there's lots of challenges.
I mean, first is just modeling
the low level physics.
A lot of simulation engines out there,
they will model time at a certain and
in reality, time is much more
fluid than operating at like 100 Hertz or
something like that.
And to actually accurately model these
things, you may need to actually model at
a very fine time discrimination and
that gets very expensive.
And then your simulator may actually
be slower than actually running
things in the real world.
And then it's no longer useful in
comparison to collecting data in
the real world.
And then the second thing is
the real world is super diverse.
And so actually creating the content
of all of the kind of objects that you
encounter even in everyday life.
When you're eating lunch or
when you're kind of cleaning up a table,
creating all of that content is
actually a really manual effort.
And usually in machine learning systems,
you want to kind of do away with
the things that require
a lot of manual effort.
And try to automate and automate things so
that they can be scaled up.
>> Yeah.
And in fact, in terms of
the diversity of environments today,
factories work great in robots where
the environment is relatively controlled,
relatively few unexpected
things happening on average.
I know some of your work has been looking
to send robots into people's homes and
do things in people's kitchens.
That's one of the most uncontrolled
environments in the world to say,
you say a bit more about that.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
So I think that the controlled
environments are the ones where we've seen
a lot of success.
And in the long term, I would love
to see robots that could go into any
environment like a home or
an office and be useful to people.
And to do that, we want to actually start
collecting data in those environments.
Often time in robotics research,
we collect the data once in a lab
environment and learn based on that data.
But if we only collect real data in a lab,
we're never going to actually get
the robots out into the real world.
So we're trying to start data collection
efforts, actually putting robots into
the real world so that they see the
diversity of all these different homes.
Rather than kind of the narrow
data that you see in the lab.
>> So I want to get your gut about one
thing which is you talked about wanting to
get a robot to go into a brand new
home and make a bowl of cereal, right?
Challenging to liquids, cereal fridge.
What's your gut about how
many different homes,
how many different kitchens
a robot will need to see.
So how many training examples do you
think a robot will need in order to have
a good chance of doing on the N
plus first on the next kitchen?
>> Yeah.
So
I think it really depends
on how hard the task is.
If the task is as simple as I don't know,
maybe pressing a button on the microwave,
then I think that you may not
need quite as much data for that.
But I think even for a new kitchen,
you probably need still quite a large
number of kitchens in order to generalize
to a new one, maybe 20 maybe 100.
If it's a task that's more complex,
like making a bowl of cereal, it's
something that's super simple to people.
But it's actually really hard for
robots because there's lots
of different steps involved.
For that, I think you need more data.
And probably also more kitchens as well,
maybe in the thousands.
And I also think that even if we had
thousands of kitchens of data or
tens of thousands might guess is that the
problem still wouldn't be solved fully.
We've seen applications like autonomous
driving where there's tons of data and
the problem isn't quite yet solved.
So I think we also need to try to
go beyond the data distribution and
also allow robots to adapt on
the fly in a new environment.
>> Well, thousands, that's higher
than my gut but that's interesting to
see how it plays out and so
on the theme of making robots more robust.
I know a lot of your research
work was also on meta learning or
learning how to learn rather than us
telling computer this is a learning
algorithm to how they get a computer
to even get better at learning.
Can you say a bit about that.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
So, part of the motivation is that
if a robot encounters a new kitchen,
we don't want it to just run what
it learned in that new kitchen.
It may actually need to adapt and
learn on the fly.
It may need to, for example, if it's
trying to open the door to a pantry and
the door is a little bit different.
It may need to take a little
bit of experience and trial and
error on that door in order
to figure out how to open it.
And we want to allow systems to do
this sort of learning process on
the fly at test time in new scenarios.
And unfortunately, if you just run machine
learning from scratch at test time on
a very small amount of data
that won't work very well.
You need large amounts of data
in order to learn something.
So what metal learning tries to do is
it tries to take experience in previous
kitchens or previous tasks.
And optimize for
the ability to learn new things,
the ability to learn new things based on
having learned lots of previous things.
>> So for example, what best learning
rate which wish to adapt to new
kitchen setting and
lots of other things, one could tune.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
So the simplest setting is if
you're only optimizing for
one parameter,
like the learning rate in a new situation.
And in more complex metal learning
algorithms, you can sort of optimize for
the entire learning algorithm.
>> So I think if you as one of the world
experts in meta learning, in fact,
if I remember this is a big
part of your PhD thesis.
Which you did way back with Peter,
who was my PhD student at Standard.
And so just say more about
how meta learning works.
>> Yeah.
So
there's a few different
approaches to metal learning.
But the approach that was in my PhD
thesis was essentially putting a learning
problem inside another learning problem.
So it's actually forms
this bilevel optimization,
this two level learning problem where
you are actually trying to optimize for
all of the parameters in
this inner learning problem.
Such that you could achieve faster
learning or more efficient learning.
>> Yeah, I remember reading some
early papers and very impressive.
So lots of software algorithms,
machine learning algorithms,
reinforcement learning algorithms.
One part of your work is
you also run a robotics lab
with robots running around robot arms.
I'm curious for someone that has not yet
spent a lot of time in a robotics lab.
Can you tell us what is it like if
a student were to join your lab,
what's it like to show up and work in
the morning and work in a robotics lab?
>> Yeah.
So in the lab, it's not all that different
from running machine learning
experiments where you run code,
you try to train a model and
then evaluate that model.
But in addition to those everyday things,
there's also interfacing
with the real robot.
So oftentimes a lot of projects
might start with the simulation and
start iterating on algorithms.
Using a physics engine that might involve
actually kind of designing aspects of
the simulation to test
the hypotheses you want to test.
And also sometimes products won't
involve that simulation step or
maybe you've already
iterated in simulation.
And on the real robot, there is everything
from setting up the control stack.
Such that you can actually command
the robot to move to a certain position,
to setting up the cameras,
to collecting data with the robot.
You might be collecting data by
using like a V R controller, for
example, to tell the robot to
move to certain positions.
And then also actually when it comes
time to evaluate a model, it involves
actually running that on the robot and
seeing what the robot does in real life.
It's a pretty fun process at least for me,
I think it's very rewarding to actually
see the robot do something rather
than just see some numbers or
some accuracy of your model.
But it's also requires a little bit of
persistence because robots can break down.
You might have a motor that breaks, you
may not have set up the camera correctly.
It might be giving you all zeros for
example.
There's many more bugs that can come
up than in a system without a robot.
>> So, number of people have had
experience debugging software and
then there's debugging machine learning
algorithms which has different
practices and ideas.
And then can you say a bit about what
debugging hardware in a robotics
lab is like?
>> Definitely.
I mean, in general, with debugging,
you want to rule out
possible sources of errors,
possible sources of bugs and
often times you might have a guess that
it is from the software or the hardware.
And from there, I think that many of
the machine learning things will apply.
You want to look at your data.
And because a lot of the data is
actually collected in the lab,
it may not be from a data set, then there
may be something tha is wrong about it.
And you may want to actually look at
the images that the robot is seeing,
maybe visualize some of the features
that your model has learned.
I guess one thing that we did
recently is we wanted to actually
deploy a policy on
multiple different robots.
And so we would actually replay
actions on a robot and make sure that
the robot was reproducing a certain
motion that we wanted it to reproduce.
How you debug depends
a lot on the problem.
I don't know if there's any one way or any
kind of single bug that comes up the most
because there's all sorts
of sources of bugs.
But yeah, that gives us a little bit
of a sense for what it looks like.
>> And I thought one of the lovely and
frustrating things about robotics as
opposed to software is in software.
If you make a mistake,
you can always revert back to
the early version of software.
But that time that you do something and
your robot breaks and then you go, boy,
that's another two months of work or
something to rebuild that.
That's a unique experience in hardware.
>> Definitely.
And because we're doing a lot of
work on the software side of things,
we typically try to get robots that won't
break, like nice high end robots so
that we can worry more about the software
and less about the hardware.
But if there are cases where a robot might
break, we try to get robots where you can
pretty easily swap out parts
where if one motor breaks,
you could just swap in a new motor rather
than having to repurpose the whole thing.
But certainly there,
there's lots of challenges that come up.
>> Yeah.
And
you know,
I used to fly autonomous helicopters.
So every time a helicopter crash,
fortunately, we manage to keep it safe and
away from people, then this is a well
frankly destroyed helicopter and then we
have to just go build a new one but it's
nice when you go to do that too often.
>> Yeah.
Fortunately, arms do not crash too much.
>> I see.
Yeah.
Yeah, maybe I should have chosen,
working on that instead isn't it.
So in your robotics lab,
one tool of choice that you've often
used is reinforcement learning.
Can you say a bit about the practical
lessons, tips and tricks for how to
apply reinforcement learning amazing
algorithms to your heart by robots.
>> Yeah.
So,
reinforcement learning is
a really appealing framework for
robotics because in principle,
it would allow a robot to learn something
completely on its own through trial and
error from data that it collected itself.
And so it's something that we're
really excited about for that reason,
but it's also really challenging for
a number of reasons.
So first reinforcement learning
typically assumes that
you're given some reward signal,
some feedback.
And if you're trying to learn how
to play a game, like play a pong or
another Atari game, you can just use
the score as a reward function and
just try to maximize your score.
But the real world
doesn't give you a score.
It doesn't give the robot a score
when it tries to learn something.
And instead the robot might need
to learn its own reward function.
It might need to learn what it means to
accomplish a task at the same time as also
trying to learn how to accomplish
that task in the physical world.
So that's one big challenge and
one way that we approach it.
Another challenge is typically
in this trial and error.
>> And so how do you learn the reward?
Like from a demonstration?
How, how do you learn the reward?
Yeah.
>> So we learned it in a few
different ways.
We often give it at least give it some
examples of what success looks like.
And we also sometimes give it
a full demonstration of this is
an example of what we want you to do.
And then you can get into techniques
like inverse reinforcement learning,
which you worked on a long
time ago as well and
actually try to invert
the reinforcement learning process and
try to figure out what reward
function underlies this behavior.
So beyond learning, reward functions,
another challenge is autonomy in
the process of reinforcement learning.
So typically, you think of it as
a trial-and-error process where you try to
solve the task and
then you want to try it again.
And in between trying the task and
trying it again,
you need to somehow get back
to some starting point.
And maybe for example, if you're
trying to learn how to do a back flip,
trying it again will involve
standing up after you fall down.
But actually,
sometimes learning that resetting
behavior is also quite challenging.
And there is this challenging interplay
between learning how to do the task and
also learning how to recover from all
the ways that you failed at the task in
the entire process of doing that.
>> It's really automating the research
process so that you run repeat experiments
without having to lug a robot around
every single time to put it back.
>> Exactly.
Yeah.
>> Cool, really cool.
And in fact, in your application
of reinforcement learning,
I think you're among the earliest
researchers to do more or
less or completely end to end robotics.
End to end reinforcement learning.
Can you say a bit about what that
was like in the early days and
why you went that route?
>> Yeah.
So at the start of my PhD,
deep learning was just
starting to become popular.
After Alex Net was showing that you
can do very well with deep neural
networks trained end to end for
computer vision.
And I had just arrived at Berkeley for
my phD.
There were some people that were
working on reinforcement learning
with neural networks.
And I was pretty excited about that work
and I wanted to see in the past work,
it was all blind.
The robot wasn't using cameras in any way.
And I wanted to see if we could learn
a neural network that directly maps from
the images taken by the robot's camera to
the torques applied to the robots joints.
And in that first project,
it was a lot of work to try to
actually get that initial result.
But we were excited to see that we
actually could get a single neural network
that could learn something like
screwing a cap on a bottle or
putting a coat hanger on a coat rack with
a single neural network mapping directly
from pixels to torques.
And it was a pretty exciting result.
It was definitely very
different from what the rest
of the robotics community was working on.
And I think the, the paper that we worked
on was actually rejected twice because
people didn't like deep learning,
roboticists didn't like that these
neural networks were very black box and
you couldn't understand them.
But eventually it got published and
it was accepted.
And now it's actually become a much more
prominent paradigm in robotics where
a lot more people are now trading neural
networks to represent the policy,
to represent how the robot chooses
actions based on the camera images.
>> I think that early work you did was
quite visionary and set an important hope,
set an important new direction for
the field.
What's your prediction for
where this will go?
Do you think the percentage of practical
robotics work that this train end to end?
How much do you think that
will continue to go up or not?
>> Yeah, I certainly think that it
will continue to grow quite a bit.
Still not all of the robotics research
community is looking at these kinds of
approaches, in part because there
are useful techniques in control theory
that are useful, especially in controlled
scenarios, like we talked about.
But I think that it will certainly grow.
I think that especially as the machine
learning field continues to make really
impressive advances, I hope that that
will convince more people that this
sort of paradigm is really promising for
robotics as well, especially in terms of
handling the vast degree of variety in
objects and environments in the world.
In terms of looking forward, in terms
of understanding what might happen in
the next 10 or 20 years in robotics,
one thing that I'm really excited about
that we touched on a little bit, is trying
to train robots on broader datasets.
A lot of the field of robot learning
is still collecting a dataset for
a project in a lab and
then training on that small data set.
It's small because it has to be,
because you collected it for that project.
And I think if we imagine that if computer
vision researchers had to collect
image net for
every single project that they did,
they probably wouldn't be
making that much progress.
And so, my prediction at least for for the
coming years is to move towards a paradigm
where we reuse data sets a lot, we use
much larger datasets, and ideally are kind
of sharing data sets across institutions,
across robot platforms.
And scaling up the data that these
systems are trained on such that
they can generalize more broadly.
>> That's an exciting vision.
And how do we get there?
For images, everyone uses PNG files,
and GIF files, and
JPEG files, so, the data is highly
portable and highly shareable.
If different research labs just
have different pieces of hardware,
how do you make that happen for robotics?
>> Yeah, so, it's definitely challenging.
The place that we're starting that
I'm quite excited about is, first,
trying to actually have a little bit of
consensus, bring the community together
to say, okay, let's start with this robot
platform with roughly this setup so
that we can at least standardize on some
of it, and then try to collect lots and
lots of diverse data on that
fairly standardized platform.
Start from there, and then if we're
able to get some signs of life and
some positive success from collecting
a broad dataset with those standardized
choices, then starting to standardize
less and less and move on.
Maybe the same robot but
with a different control stack, and
then maybe starting to move towards
different versions of that robot,
different grippers, and ultimately lots of
different robots and lots of environments.
>> Cool, yep, great,
this is exciting vision.
So, this is one of the things
you're doing in robotics.
Just looking more broadly, with all
the work you do in reinforcement learning,
some not even apply to robotics but
other applications, where do you hope for
enforcement learning and
robotics will go in the next many years?
>> Yeah, so, I think that, I mean,
I'm hoping that it will move towards these
reusable datasets and very broad datasets.
I also think that even beyond robotics,
I think that there's lots of other
applications of reinforcement
learning as well.
So, for example, in some of our recent
work, we applied reinforcement learning,
and actually meta reinforcement learning,
a combination of meta learning and
reinforcement learning, to education
to give feedback on student work,
where students would program a game
like Breakout and then the system would
actually play the game and find the bugs
that the students made and give them
feedback on how to improve their program
and how to continue to learn how to code.
>> Now, that's very cool.
In fact, robots are so visual, sometimes
it's easy to forget that reinforcement
learning is a general technique for
decision making with delayed rewards.
That's useful for
many things other than robots.
Frankly, when I see more robots,
I used to try to get all my
students to learn to solder.
I don't know if that was a-
>> I learned how to solder an undergrad,
although I don't think I actually
ever used that in my robotics work.
Wow, I see.
Maybe things have moved on,
but I had to, yeah.
>> I think we would just buy robots
that didn't need some soldering.
>> So, your journey has led
you to do cutting edge work in
reinforcement learning and robotics.
I'm curious what advice you would have for
someone looking to break into
reinforcement learning or to robotics.
Not everyone owns a cool robot,
that an easy program, but
how should someone get started?
>> Yeah, my main advice would just
be to try to get your feet wet,
and just try to build something,
try to program and code something up.
There's lots of different
things that you can do.
And I think that learning by
trying to build something,
by trying to do something,
is one of the coolest ways to learn
because you have a certain goal in mind.
>> But would you build something
using a simulated robot or
do you think you should
just build a little robot?
>> I think that starting with a simulated
robot is probably the easiest and
there's less of a learning curve and
less things that you have to do,
you don't have to go out and buy hardware.
That said, I think that also trying to
work a little bit with hardware
right off the bat is great, and
it definitely teaches you about how hard
robotics is, robotics is really hard.
But also, by kind of struggling
to get the robot to do something,
it makes it all that much more rewarding
when it actually does something cool,
when it does something
that you wanted it to do.
And, I don't know, some of the robots
that we use are fairly expensive.
But nowadays, there's actually lots of
robots that are fairly inexpensive that
people can buy, or you can kind of build
your own robot by connecting wheels and
a camera or maybe even a smartphone
together to build something.
I actually got started with LEGO
robotics in middle school and
you could also build robots out
of LEGO and get started that way.
>> Yes, actually, I remember I went to
LEGO robotics competitions when I was in
middle school or something.
That was interesting set of experiences.
So, to someone taking the machine
learning specialization,
if their goal is to work
in enforcement learning and
robotics, what else would
you recommend they look at?
What are the other resources
you think would be helpful?
>> Definitely, so there are resources
in terms of just learning about
reinforcement learning, and
there are kind of courses online,
there's also kind of course videos,
there's textbooks like Sutton Barto.
And so, those are lots of resources.
I also think that there are lots of,
I don't know, videos online,
tutorials ,code bases,
you can actually check out a physics
engine like the Majko Physics Engine,
which is freely available, and
try to kind of explore with that.
So, yeah, those are a few resources.
There's also one thing that
we use a lot to interface
with robots is called
the Robot Operating System, or ROS.
And so,
learning about that can also be useful.
>> That came out of my research lab
wayback working with with a garage.
Yeah, good times.
Sorry, I didn't mean to interrupt.
>> Yeah, so, I think that those
are some of the resources, and yeah,
not too much more than that.
>> Cool, yeah, very cool.
With the world moving forward and
evolving, it feels like the number of path
for someone wanting to get involved
in this is even growing and
it probably gets a little bit easier every
year for someone to enter this field.
So, this is exciting time to be in.
>> Yeah, definitely.
>> Thanks for
joining me here at Stanford University.
I'm with Professor Chelsea Finn who
is with both the computer science and
the electrical engine departments, and
leads a research group that does cutting
edge work on applying
reinforcement learning and
machine learning to robotics and
other applications.
Thanks for joining us, Chelsea.
>> Yeah, happy to be here.