Let's formalize how
a reinforcement learning
algorithm picks actions.
In this video, you'll
learn about what is
a policy in reinforcement
learning algorithm.
Let's take a look.
As we've seen, there are
many different ways that you
can take actions in the
reinforcement learning problem.
For example, we could decide
to always go for
the nearer reward,
so you go left if this
leftmost reward is
nearer or go right if this
rightmost reward is nearer.
Another way we could choose
actions is to always go for
the larger reward or
we could always go
for smaller reward,
doesn't seem like a good idea,
but it is another option,
or you could choose to go left
unless you're just one step
away from the lesser reward,
in which case, you
go for that one.
In reinforcement learning,
our goal is to come up with
a function which is
called a policy Pi,
whose job it is to take as input
any state s and map it
to some action a that
it wants us to take.
For example, for this
policy here at the bottom,
this policy would say that
if you're in state 2,
then it maps us to
the left action.
If you're in state 3,
the policy says go left.
If you are in state 4 also go
left and if you're in
state 5, go right.
Pi applied to state S,
tells us what action it wants
us to take in that state.
The goal of reinforcement
learning is to find a policy Pi
or Pi of S that tells
you what action to
take in every state so as
to maximize the return.
By the way, I don't
know if policy is
the most descriptive
term of what pi is,
but it's one of
those terms that's
become standard in
reinforcement learning.
Maybe calling Pi a
controller rather than
a policy would be
more natural
terminology but policy
is what everyone in
reinforcement learning
now calls this.
In the last video, we've gone
through quite a few concepts in
reinforcement learning from
states to actions to reward,
to returns, to policies.
Let's do a quick
review of them in
the next video and
then we'll go on to
start developing algorithms
for finding that policies.