Welcome to this final week of
the machine learning specialization.
It's a little bit bittersweet for
me that we're approaching the end of this
specialization, but
I'm looking forward to this week,
sharing with you some exciting
ideas about reinforcement learning.
In machine learning, reinforcement
learning is one of those ideas that while
not very widely applied in
commercial applications yet today,
is one of the pillars of machine learning.
And has lots of exciting research backing
it up and improving it every single day.
So let's start by taking a look at
what is reinforcement learning.
Let's start with an example.
Here's a picture of
an autonomous helicopter.
This is actually the Stanford autonomous
helicopter, weighs 32 pounds and
it's actually sitting
in my office right now.
Like many other autonomous helicopters,
it's instrumented with an onboard
computer, GPS, accelerometers,
and gyroscopes and
the magnetic compass so it knows where
it is at all times quite accurately.
And if I were to give you
the keys to this helicopter and
ask you to write a program to fly it,
how would you do so?
Radio controlled helicopters are
controlled with joysticks like these and
so the task is ten times per second you're
given the position and orientation and
speed and so on of the helicopter.
And you have to decide how to move these
two control sticks in order to keep
the helicopter balanced in the air.
By the way,
I've flown radio controlled helicopters
as well as quad rotor drones myself.
And radio controlled helicopters
are actually quite a bit harder to fly,
quite a bit harder to
keep balanced in the air.
So how do you write a program
to do this automatically?
Let me show you a fun
video of something we got
a Stanford autonomous helicopter to do.
Here's a video of it flying under
the control of a reinforcement learning
algorithm.
And let me play the video.
I was actually the cameraman that day and
this is the helicopter flying
on the computer control and
if I zoom out the video,
you see the trees planted in the sky.
So using reinforcement learning,
we actually got this helicopter
to learn to fly upside down.
We told it to fly upside down.
And so reinforced learning has been
used to get helicopters to fly a wide
range of stunts or
we call them aerobatic maneuvers.
By the way, if you're interested
in seeing other videos,
you can also check them out at this URL.
So how do you get a helicopter to fly
itself using reinforcement learning?
The task is given the position of
the helicopter to decide how to
move the control sticks.
In reinforcement learning,
we call the position and orientation and
speed and so
on of the helicopter the state s.
And so the task is to find a function that
maps from the state of the helicopter
to an action a, meaning how far to
push the two control sticks in order
to keep the helicopter balanced in
the air and flying and without crashing.
One way you could attempt this
problem is to use supervised learning.
It turns out this is not a great approach
for autonomous helicopter flying.
But you could say, well if we could get
a bunch of observations of states and
maybe have an expert human pilot tell
us what's the best action y to take.
You could then train a neural
network using supervised learning to
directly learn the mapping from
the states s which I'm calling x here,
to an action a which I'm
calling the label y here.
But it turns out that when the helicopter
is moving through the air is
actually very ambiguous, what is
the exact one right action to take.
Do you tilt a bit to the left or
a lot more to the left or
increase the helicopter
stress a little bit or a lot?
It's actually very difficult to get
a data set of x and the ideal action y.
So that's why for a lot of task of
controlling a robot like a helicopter and
other robots, the supervised learning
approach doesn't work well and
we instead use reinforcement learning.
Now a key input to a reinforcement
learning is something called the reward or
the reward function which tells
the helicopter when it's doing well and
when it's doing poorly.
So the way I like to think of the reward
function is a bit like training a dog.
When I was growing up,
my family had a dog and
it was my job to train the dog or
the puppy to behave.
So how do you get a puppy to behave well?
Well, you can't demonstrate
that much to the puppy.
Instead you let it do its thing and
whenever it does something good,
you go, good dog.
And whenever they did something bad,
you go, bad dog.
And then hopefully it learns by itself
how to do more of the good dog and
fewer of the bad dog things.
So training with the reinforcement
learning algorithm is like that.
When the helicopter's flying well,
you go, good helicopter and
if it does something bad like crash,
you go, bad helicopter.
And then it's the reinforcement learning
algorithm's job to figure out how to get
more of the good helicopter and
fewer of the bad helicopter outcomes.
One way to think of why
reinforcement learning is so
powerful is you have to tell it what
to do rather than how to do it.
And specifying the reward function rather
than the optimal action gives you a lot
more flexibility in how
you design the system.
Concretely for flying the helicopter,
whenever it is flying well,
you may give it a reward of plus
one every second it is flying well.
And maybe whenever it's flying poorly
you may give it a negative reward or
if it ever crashes, you may give it a very
large negative reward like negative 1,000.
And so this would incentivize
the helicopter to spend a lot more
time flying well and
hopefully to never crash.
But here's another fun video.
I was using the good dog bad dog analogy
for reinforcement learning for many years.
And then one day I actually managed
to get my hands on a robotic dog and
could actually use this reinforcement
learning good dog bad dog
methodology to train a robot
dog to get over obstacles.
So this is a video of a robot dog
that using reinforcement learning,
which rewards it, moving toward
the left of the screen has learned
how to place its feet carefully or
climb over a variety of obstacles.
And if you think about what it
takes to program a dog like this,
I have no idea,
I really don't know how to tell it
what's the best way to place its
legs to get over a given obstacle.
All of these things were figured out
automatically by the robot just by giving
it rewards that incentivizes it,
making progress toward the goal
on the left of the screen.
Today, reinforcement learning has been
successfully applied to a variety of
applications ranging
from controlling robots.
And in fact later this week in the
practice lab, you implement for yourself
a reinforcement learning algorithm to
land a lunar lander in simulation.
It's also been used for
factory optimization.
How do you rearrange things in
the factory to maximize throughput and
efficiency as well as
financial stock trading.
For example, one of my friends was
working on efficient stock execution.
So if you decided to sell a million
shares over the next several days, well,
you may not want to dump a million shares
on the stock market suddenly because
that will move prices against you.
So what's the best way to sequence out
your trades over time so that you can sell
the shares you want to sell and hopefully
get the best possible price for them?
Finally, there have also been many
applications of reinforcement
learning to playing games, everything
from checkers to chess to the card
game of bridge to go as well as for
playing many video games.
So that's reinforcement learning.
Even though reinforcement learning
is not used nearly as much
as supervised learning, it is still
used in a few applications today.
And the key idea is rather than you
needing to tell the algorithm what is
the right output y for every single input,
all you have to do instead is specify
a reward function that tells it when it's
doing well and when it's doing poorly.
And it's the job of the algorithm to
automatically figure out how to choose
good actions.
With that, let's now go into
the next video where we'll formalize
the reinforcement learning problem and
also start to develop algorithms for