In the last video, you saw how
if you have features
for each movie,
such as features x_1 and x_2
that tell you how much is
this a romance movie and how
much is this an action movie.
Then you can use basically
linear regression
to learn to predict
movie ratings.
But what if you don't have
those features, x_1 and x_2?
Let's take a look at how
you can learn or come up
with those features x_1
and x_2 from the data.
Here's the data
that we had before.
But what if instead of
having these numbers
for x_1 and x_2,
we didn't know in advance what
the values of the features
x_1 and x_2 were?
I'm going to replace them with
question marks over here.
Now, just for the
purposes of illustration,
let's say we had somehow already
learned parameters
for the four users.
Let's say that we
learned parameters w^1
equals 5 and 0 and b^1
equals 0, for user one.
W^2 is also 5, 0 b^2, 0.
W^3 is 0,
5 b^3 is 0,
and for user four W^4 is also 0,
5 and b^4 0, 0.
We'll worry later about
how we might have
come up with these
parameters, w and b.
But let's say we
have them already.
As a reminder, to predict
music j's rating on movie i,
we're going to use
w^j dot product,
the features of x_i plus b^j.
To simplify this example,
all the values of b are
actually equal to 0.
Just to reduce a
little bit of writing,
I'm going to ignore b for
the rest of this example.
Let's take a look at
how we can try to guess
what might be reasonable
features for movie one.
If these are the parameters
you have on the left,
then given that Alice
rated movie one, 5,
we should have that w^1.x^1
should be about equal to
5 and w^2.x^2 should
also be about equal to 5
because Bob rated it 5.
W^3.x^1 should be close to 0
and w^4.x^1 should be
close to 0 as well.
The question is, given
these values for w
that we have up here,
what choice for x_1 will cause
these values to be right?
Well, one possible
choice would be if
the features for
that first movie,
were 1, 0 in which case,
w^1.x^1 will be equal to 5,
w^2.x^1 will be equal
to 5 and similarly,
w^3 or w^4 dot product with
this feature vector x_1
would be equal to 0.
What we have is that if you
have the parameters for
all four users here,
and if you have four ratings
in this example that you
want to try to match,
you can take a reasonable
guess at what lists a feature
vector x_1 for movie one that
would make good predictions
for these four
ratings up on top.
Similarly, if you have
these parameter vectors,
you can also try to come up with
a feature vector x_2
for the second movie,
feature vector x_3
for the third movie,
and so on to try to make the
algorithm's predictions on
these additional movies close
to what was actually the
ratings given by the users.
Let's come up with a cost
function for actually
learning the values
of x_1 and x_2.
By the way, notice
that this works only
because we have parameters
for four users.
That's what allows us to try
to guess appropriate
features, x_1.
This is why in a typical
linear regression application
if you had just a single user,
you don't actually have
enough information to figure
out what would be the features,
x_1 and x_2, which is why in
the linear regression contexts
that you saw in course 1,
you can't come up with features
x_1 and x_2 from scratch.
But in collaborative filtering,
is because you have ratings from
multiple users of the same
item with the same movie.
That's what makes it
possible to try to
guess what are possible
values for these features.
Given w^1, b^1, w^2, b^2,
and so on through
w^n_u and b^n_u,
for the n subscript u users.
If you want to learn
the features x^i for
a specific movie,
i is a cost function we
could use which is that.
I'm going to want to minimize
squared error as usual.
If the predicted rating by
user j on movie i
is given by this,
let's take the
squared difference
from the actual
movie rating y,i,j.
As before, let's sum
over all the users j.
But this will be a sum over
all values of j, where r, i,
j is equal to I. I'll add
a 1.5 there as usual.
As I defined this as a
cost function for x^i.
Then if we minimize this
as a function of x^i
you be choosing the
features for movie i.
So therefore all the users
J that have rated movie i,
we will try to minimize the
squared difference between
what your choice of features
x^i results in terms of
the predicted movie rating minus
the actual movie rating
that the user had given it.
Then finally, if we want to
add a regularization term,
we add the usual
plus Lambda over 2,
K equals 1 through n,
where n as usual
is the number of
features of x^i squared.
Lastly, to learn
all the features
x1 through x^n_m because
we have n_m movies,
we can take this
cost function on
top and sum it over
all the movies.
Sum from i equals 1 through
the number of movies
and then just take
this term from above
and this becomes
a cost function for learning
the features for all of
the movies in the dataset.
So if you have parameters
w and b, all the users,
then minimizing this cost
function as a function
of x1 through x^n_m
using gradient descent
or cellular algorithm,
this will actually allow you
to take a pretty good guess
at learning good
features for the movies.
This is pretty remarkable
for most machine
learning applications
the features had to be
externally given but
in this algorithm,
we can actually learn the
features for a given movie.
But what we've done
so far in this video,
we assumed you had
those parameters w and b
for the different users.
Where do you get those
parameters from?
Well, let's put together
the algorithm from
the last video for learning
w and b and what we
just talked about in this
video for learning x and
that will give us our
collaborative filtering algorithm.
Here's the cost function
for learning the features.
This is what we had
derived on the last slide.
Now, it turns out that if
we put these two together,
this term here is exactly
the same as this term here.
Notice that sum over
j of all values
of i is that r,i,j
equals 1 is the
same as summing
over all values of
i with all j where
r,i,j is equal to 1.
This summation is
just summing over
all user movie pairs
where there is a rating.
What I'm going to do is put
these two cost functions
together and have
this where I'm just writing
out the summation more
explicitly as summing
over all pairs i and j,
where we do have a rating
of the usual squared cost
function and then let
me take the regularization term
from learning the
parameters w and b,
and put that here and take
the regularization term from
learning the features
x and put them
here and this ends up being
our overall cost function
for learning w, b, and x.
It turns out that
if you minimize
this cost function as a
function of w and b as y as x,
then this algorithm
actually works.
Here's what I mean. If
we had three users and
two movies and if you have
ratings for these four movies,
but not those two,
over here does,
is it sums over all the users.
For user 1 has determined
the cost function for this,
for user 2 has determined
for user 3 has determined
the cost function for this.
We're summing over
users first and
then having one term for
each movie where
there is a rating.
But an alternative way to
carry out the summation
is to first look at movie 1,
that's what this
summation here does,
and then to include all the
users that rated movie 1,
and then look at movie
2 and have a term
for all the users that
had rated movie 2.
You see that in both cases
we're just summing over
these four areas where
the user had rated the
corresponding movie.
That's why this summation
on top and this
summation here are
the two ways of summing over
all of the pairs where the
user had rated that movie.
How do you minimize
this cost function
as a function of w, b, and x?
One thing you could do is
to use gradient descent.
In course 1 when we learned
about linear regression,
this is the gradient descent
algorithm you had seen,
where we had the
cost function J,
which is a function of
the parameters w and b,
and we'd apply gradient
descent as follows.
With collaborative filtering,
the cost function is in
a function of just w and
b is now a function of w,
b, and x. I'm using
w and b here to denote
the parameters for all
of the users and x here just
informally to denote the
features of all of the movies.
But if you're able to take
partial derivatives with respect
to the different parameters,
you can then continue to update
the parameters as follows.
But now we need to optimize
this with respect to x as well.
We also will want
to update each of
these parameters x using
gradient descent as follows.
It turns out that
if you do this,
then you actually find
pretty good values
of w and b as well as x.
In this formulation
of the problem,
the parameters of w and b,
and x is also a parameter.
Then finally, to learn
the values of x,
we also will update x as x
minus the partial derivative
respect to x of the cost w,
b, x. I'm using the
notation here a little bit
informally and not keeping
very careful track of the
superscripts and subscripts,
but the key takeaway I
hope you have from this is
that the parameters to
this model are w and b,
and x now is also a parameter,
which is why we minimize
the cost function as
a function of all three of
these sets of parameters,
w and b, as well as x.
The average we derived is
called collaborative filtering,
and the name
collaborative filtering
refers to the sense that
because multiple users have
rated the same movie
collaboratively,
given you a sense of what
this movie maybe like,
that allows you to guess what
are appropriate features
for that movie,
and this in turn allows you to
predict how other users that
haven't yet rated
that same movie
may decide to rate
it in the future.
This collaborative filtering is
this gathering of data
from multiple users.
This collaboration between
users to help you predict
ratings for even other
users in the future.
So far, our problem
formulation has used
movie ratings from 1- 5
stars or from 0- 5 stars.
A very common use case of
recommended systems is when you
have binary labels such
as that the user favors,
or like, or interact
with an item.
In the next video, let's take
a look at a generalization
of the model that you've seen
so far to binary labels.
Let's go see that