How does PCA work?
If you have a dataset with
two features, x_1 and x_2.
Initially, your
data is plotted or
represented using
axes x_1 and x_2.
But you want to replace
these two features
with just one feature.
How can you choose a new axis,
let's call it the z-axis,
that is somehow a good
feature for capturing,
of representing the data?
Let's take a look at
how PCA does this.
Here's the data sets with
five training examples.
Remember, this is an
unsupervised learning algorithm
so we just have x_1 and x_2,
there is no label y.
An example here like this
may have coordinates x_1
equals 10 and x_2 equals 8.
If we don't want to
use the x_1, x_2 axes,
how can we pick some
different axis with which to
capture what's in
the data or with
which to represent the data?
One note on preprocessing,
before applying the next few
steps of PCA the features
should be first
normalized to have
zero mean and I've
already done that here.
If the features x_1 and
x_2 take on very
different scales,
for example, if you remember
our housing example,
if x_1 was the size of
a house in square feet,
and x_2 was the number
of bedrooms then
x_1 could be 1,000 or
a couple of thousand,
whereas x_2 is a small number.
If the features take on
very different scales,
then you will first
perform feature
scaling before applying
the next few steps of PCA.
Assuming the features have been
normalized to have zero mean,
so subtract the mean from
each feature and
then maybe apply
feature scaling as well
so the ranges are
not too far apart.
What does PCA do next?
To examine what PCA does,
let me remove the
x_1 and x_2 axes so
that we're just left with
the five training examples.
This dot here
represents the origin.
The position of zero
on this plot still.
What we have to do
now with PCA is,
pick one axis instead
of the two axes that
we had previously
with which to capture
what's important about
these five examples.
If we were to choose this
axis to be our new z-axis,
it's actually the
same as the x_1 axis
just for this example.
Then what we're saying is
that for this example,
we're going to just
capture this value,
this coordinate on the z-axis.
For the second example,
we're going to
capture this value,
and then this will
and so on for all five examples.
Another way of
saying this is that
we're going to take
each of these examples
and project it down to
a point on the z-axis.
The word project refers to that
you're taking this example
and bringing it to
the z-axis using
this line segment
that's at a 90-degree
angle to the z-axis.
This little box here
is used to denote that
this line segment is at
90 degrees to the z-axis.
The term project
just means you're
taking a point and finding
this corresponding
point on the z-axis
using this line segment
that's at 90 degrees.
Picking this direction as a
z-axis is not a bad choice,
but there's some
even better choices.
This choice isn't
too bad because
when you project your
examples onto the z-axis,
you still capture quite a lot
of the spread of the data.
These five points here,
they're pretty spread apart
so you're still
capturing a lot of
the variation or a lot of
the variance in the
original dataset.
By that I mean these five
points are quite spread
apart and so the variance
or variation among
these five points,
the projections of the data onto
the z-axis is decently large.
What that means is we're
still capturing quite a lot
of the information in the
original five examples.
Let's look at some other
possible choices for the axis z.
Here's another choice. This is
actually not a great choice.
But if I were to choose
this as my z axis,
then if I take
those same five examples
and project them
down to the z-axis,
I end up with these five points.
You notice that compare it
to the previous choice,
these five points are
quite squished together.
The amount they are
differing from each other,
or their variance or the
variation is much less.
What this means is
with this choice of z,
you're capturing much less
of the information in
the original dataset
because you've
partially squish all
five examples together.
Let's look at one last choice,
which is if I choose
this to be the z-axis.
This is actually a better choice
than the previous
two that we saw,
because if we take
the data's projections
onto the z-axis,
we find that these
dots over here,
they're actually
quite far apart.
We're capturing a lot
of the variation,
a lot of the information
in the original dataset,
even though we're now using
just one coordinate or one
number to represent or to
capture each of the
training examples instead
of two numbers or two
coordinates, X_1 and X_2.
In the PCA algorithm,
this axis is called the
principal component.
In the z-axis that when you
project the data onto it,
you end up with the largest
possible amounts of variance.
If you were to reduce the data
to one axis or to one feature,
this principal component
is actually a good choice,
and this is what PCA will do.
If you want to reduce the data
to one-dimensional feature,
then it will choose this
principal component.
Let me show you a
visualization of how
different choices of the
axis affects the projection.
Here we have 10
training examples,
and as we slide
this slider here,
and you can play with this
in one of the optional
labs yourself.
As you slide the slider here,
the angle of the z-axis changes.
What you're seeing
on the left is
each of the examples
projected via
that short line segment at
90 degrees to the z-axis.
Here on the right is that
projection of the data,
meaning the value of these
10 examples, z-coordinate.
You notice that when I set
the axis to about here,
the points are quite
squished together.
So this posses less of
the automation of
the original data.
Whereas if I set the
z-axis say to this,
then these points
vary much more.
This is capturing much more of
the information in
the original dataset.
That's why the principal
component corresponds
to setting the z-axis
to about here.
This is the choice that PCA
would make if you asked it to
reduce the data
to one dimension.
Machine learning library,
like scikit-learn,
which you'll hear more
about in the next video,
can help you automatically
find the principal component.
But let's take a little bit
deeper into how that works.
Here are my x_1 and x_2 axis.
Here's one training
example with coordinates 2
on the x_1 axis and
three on the x_2 axis.
Let's say that PCA has found
this direction for the z-axis.
What I'm drawing here,
this little arrow is a length 1
vector pointing in
the direction of
this z-axis that PCA will
choose or that we have chosen.
It turns out this length 1
vector is the vector 0.710,
0.71 rounded off a bit.
It's actually 0.707 and then
a bunch of other digits.
Given this example with
coordinates 2,3 on the x_1,
x_2 axis, how do we project
this example onto the z-axis?
It turns out the
formula for doing
so is to take a dot product
between the vector 2,3 and
this vector 0.71, 0.71.
If you do that,
2,3 dot product with 0.71,
0.71 turns out to be 2 times
0.71 plus 3 times 0.71,
which is equal to 3.55.
What that means is the
distance from the origin
of this point over here is 3.55,
which means that if
we were to represent
or to use one number to try
to capture this example,
that one number is 3.55.
So far, we have talked about
how to use PCA to reduce
data down to one dimension
or down to one number.
We did so by finding the
principal component,
also called sometimes the
first principal component.
In this example, we had found
this as the first axis.
It turns out that if you
were to pick a second axis,
the second axis
will always be at
90 degrees to the first axis.
If you were to choose
even a third axis,
then the third axis will be at
90 degrees to the first
and the second axis.
By the way, in mathematics,
90 degrees is sometimes
called perpendicular.
The term perpendicular
just means at 90 degrees.
Mathematicians will sometimes
say the second axis,
z_2, is at
90 degrees or is perpendicular
to the first axis, z_1.
If you choose additional axes,
they're also at 90 degrees
or perpendicular to
z_1 and z_2 and to any other
axes that PCA will choose.
If you had 50 features and
wanted to find three
principal components,
then if that's the first axis,
the second axis will be
at 90 degrees to it.
Then the third axis will also be
at 90 degrees to the first
and the second axis.
Now, one question
I'm often asked is,
how is PCA different
from linear regression?
It turns out PCA is
not linear regression,
is a totally
different algorithm.
Let me explain why.
With linear regression,
which is a supervised
learning algorithm,
you have data x and y.
Here's a data set where
the horizontal axis is
the feature x and the vertical
axis here is the label y.
With linear regression
you're trying to fit
a straight line so that
the predicted value is as
close as possible to the
ground truth label y.
In other words, you're trying
to minimize the length of
these little line segments which
are in the vertical direction.
They just aligned
with the y axis.
In contrast, in PCA,
there is no ground
truth label y.
You just have unlabeled data,
X1 and X2,
and furthermore, you're
not trying to fit
a line to use X1 to predict X2.
Instead, the average
treats X1 and X2 equally.
We're trying to
find this axis Z,
that it turns out we end up
making these little
line segments
small when you project
the data onto Z.
In linear regression,
there is one number Y,
which is given very
special treatment.
We're always trying
to measure distance
between the fitted line and Y,
which is why these distances are
measured just in the
direction of the y-axis.
Whereas in PCA, you can
have a lot of features,
X1, X2, maybe all the
way up to X50 if you
have 50 features.
All 50 features are
treated equally.
We're just trying
to find an axis
Z so that when the data is
projected onto the axis Z
using these line
segments that you still
retain as much of the variance
of the original
data as possible.
I know that when I plot these
things in two-dimensions,
we've just two
features, which is,
I can draw on a flat
computer monitor.
These arrows look like
maybe they're a
little bit similar.
But when you have more
than two features,
which is most of the case,
the difference between
linear regression and
PCA and what the algorithms
do is very large.
These algorithms are used for
totally different purposes and
give you very different answers.
When linear regression
is used to predict
a target output Y and
PCA is trying to take
a lot of features and treat
them all equally and reduce
the number of axis needed
to represent the data well.
It turns out that maximizing
the spread of these
projections will
correspond to minimizing
the distances
of these line segments,
the distances to
the points have to
move to be projected down to Z.
To illustrate the
difference between
linear regression and
PCA in another way,
if you have a data set
that looks like this,
linear regression,
all it can do is
fit a line that looks like that.
Whereas if your data
set looks like this,
PCA will choose this to be
the principal component.
So you should use
linear regression
if you're trying
to predict the value of y,
and you should use PCA
if you're trying to
reduce the number of
features in your data set,
say to visualize it.
Finally, before we
wrap up this video,
there's one more thing you
could do with PCA, which is,
recall this example which
was at coordinates 2,3.
We found that if you
projected to the z-axis,
you end up with 3.55.
One thing you could do is if you
have an example
where Z equals 3.55,
given just this one
number Z, 3.55,
can we try to figure out what
was the original example?
It turns out that there's a step
in PCA called reconstruction,
which is to try to go from
this one number Z equals 3.55
back to the original
two numbers, X1 and X2.
It turns out you don't
have enough information to
get back X1 and X2 exactly,
but you can try to
approximate it.
In particular, the formula is,
you would take this number 3.55,
which is Z, and multiply
it by the length one vector
that we had just now,
which is 0.71, 0.71.
This ends up to be 2.52,
2.52, which is this
point over here.
We can approximate the
original training example,
which was a coordinates 2,
3 with this new point here,
which is at 2.52, 2.52.
The difference between
the original point and
the projected point is this
little line segment here.
In this case is not a
bad approximation 2.52,
2.52 is not that far from 2, 3.
With just one number,
we could get a reasonable
approximation to
the coordinates of the
original training example.
This is called the
reconstruction step of PCA.
To summarize, the PCA
algorithm looks at
your original data and
chooses one or more new axis,
Z or maybe Z1 and Z2,
to represent your
data and by taking
your original data
set and projecting
it onto your new axis or axis.
This gives you a smaller
set of numbers so you
can plot if wished to
visualize your data.
You're seeing the math.
Let's now take a look at how you
can implement this in code.
In the next video, we'll
look at how you can use PCA
yourself using the
scikit-learn library.