Even though recommender
systems have been very
profitable for some
businesses, that happens,
some use cases that have left
people and society
at large worse off.
However, you use
recommender systems or
for that matter other
learning algorithms,
I hope you only do
things that make
society at large and
people better off.
Let's take a look at some of
the problematic use cases
of recommender systems,
as well as ameliorations to
reduce harm or to
increase the amount of
good that they can do.
As you've seen in
the last few videos,
there are many ways of
configuring a recommender system.
When we saw binary labels,
the label y could be,
does a user engage
or did they click
or did they explicitly
like an item?
When designing a
recommender system,
choices in setting the goal
of the recommender system
and a lot of choices and
deciding what to
recommend to users.
For example, you can
decide to recommend to
users movies most likely to be
rated five stars by that
user. That seems fine.
That seems like a
fine way to show
users movies that
they would like.
Or maybe you can recommend to
the user products that they
are most likely to purchase.
That seems like a
very reasonable use
of a recommender system as well.
Versions of recommender
systems can also be
used to decide what
ads to show to a user.
One thing you could do is
to recommend or really to
show to the user as the most
likely to be clicked on.
Actually, what many
companies will do
is try to show as
likely to click on
and where the
advertiser had put in
a high bid because
for many ad models,
the revenue that the company
collects depends on
whether the ad was
clicked on and what the
advertiser had bid per-click.
While this is a
profit-maximizing strategy,
there are also some possible
negative implications
of this type of advertising.
I'll give a specific
example on the next slide.
One other thing that
many companies do is
try to recommend products that
generate the largest profit.
If you go to a website and
search for a product today,
there are many websites
that are not showing you
the most relevant
product or the product
that you are most
likely to purchase.
But is instead
trying to show you
the products that will generate
the largest profit
for the company.
If a certain product is
more profitable for them,
because they can buy it more
cheaply and sell it
at a higher price,
that gets ranked higher
in the recommendations.
Now, many companies view a
pressure to maximize profit.
This doesn't seem like
an unreasonable thing to
do but on the flip side,
from the user perspective,
when a website recommends
to you a product,
sometimes it feels
it could be nice if
the website was transparent with
you about the criteria
by which it is deciding
what to show you.
Is it trying to maximize
their profits or
trying to show you things
that are most useful to you?
On video websites or
social media websites,
a recommender system can also
be modified to try to show
you the content that leads
to the maximum watch time.
Specifically, websites that are
an ad revenue tend to have
an incentive to keep you on
the website for a long time.
Trying to maximize the time you
spend on the site is one way for
the site to try to get more of
your time so they can
show you more ads.
Recommender systems today
are used to try to maximize
user engagement or to
maximize the amount of
time that someone spends on
a site or a specific app.
Whereas the first two of
these seem quite innocuous,
the third, fourth, and fifth,
they may be just fine.
They may not cause
any harm at all.
Or they could also be
problematic use cases
for recommender systems.
Let's take a deeper
look at some of
these potentially
problematic use cases.
Let me start with the
advertising example.
It turns out that
the advertising
industry can sometimes be
an amplifier of some of the
most harmful businesses.
They can also be an
amplifier of some of the
best and the most
fruitful businesses.
Let me illustrate with a good
example and a bad example.
Take the travel industry.
I think in the travel industry,
the way to succeed is to try to
give good travel
experiences to users,
to really try to serve users.
Now it turns out that if there's
a really good travel company,
they can sell you a trip to
fantastic destinations and make
sure you and your friends and
family have a lot of fun.
Then a good travel business,
I think will often end up
being more profitable.
The other business
is more profitable.
They can then bid
higher for ads.
It can afford to pay
more to get users.
Because it can afford
to bid higher for ads
an online advertising
site will show
its ads more often and drive
more users to this good company.
This is a virtuous cycle
where the more users
you serve well,
the more profitable
the business,
and the more you
can bid more for
ads and the more traffic
you get and so on.
Just virtuous circle will
maybe even tend to hope
the good travel companies
do even better
statistically example.
Let's look at the
problematic example.
The payday loan industry tends
to charge extremely
high-interest rates,
often to low-income individuals.
One of the ways to do well in
the payday loan business
is to be really
efficient as squeezing customers
for every single dollar
you can get out of them.
If there's a payday loan company
that is very good at
exploiting customers,
really squeezing customers
for every single dollar,
then that company will
be more profitable.
Thus they can be higher for ads.
Because they can get
bid higher for ads
they will get more
traffic sent to them.
This allows them to squeeze
even more customers and
explore even more
people for profit.
This in turn, also increase
a positive feedback loop.
Also, a positive feedback loop
that can cause the
most exploitative,
the most harmful
payday loan companies
to get sent more traffic.
This seems like the
opposite effect
than what we think would
be good for society.
I don't know that there's
an easy solution to this.
These are very
difficult problems
that recommend the
system's phase.
One amelioration might be to
refuse to set ads from
exploitative businesses.
Of course, that's easy to say.
But how do you define what is
an exploitative business
and what is not,
is a very difficult question.
But as we build
recommender systems for
advertising or for other things,
I think these are
questions that each one
of us working on
these technologies
should ask ourselves so that we
can hopefully invite open
discussion and debate,
get multiple opinions
from multiple people,
and try to come up with
design choices that allows
our systems to try to do much
more good than potential harm.
Let's look at some
other examples.
It's been widely reported
in the news that
maximizing user
engagement such as
the amount of time that
someone watches
videos on a website
or the amount of time someone
spends on social media.
This has led to
large social media
and video sharing sites to
amplify conspiracy theories
or hate and toxicity
because conspiracy theories
and certain types of
hate toxic content is highly
engaging and causes people to
spend a lot of time on it.
Even if the effect of
amplifying conspiracy
theories amplify
hidden toxicity turns out to be
harmful to individuals
and to society at large.
One amelioration for this
partial and imperfect
is to try to filter out
problematic contents
such as hate speech,
fraud, scams, maybe certain
types the violent content.
Again, the definitions of
what exactly we should filter
out is surprisingly
tricky to develop.
Entices a set of
problems that I think
companies and individuals and
even governments have to
continue to wrestle with.
Just one last example.
When a user goes to
many absolute websites,
I think users think
the Apple website
I tried to recommend to
the user thinks that
they will like.
I think many users don't
realize that many apps and
websites are trying to
maximize their profit
rather than necessarily
the user's enjoyment of
the media items that
are being recommended.
I would encourage you and
other companies if
at all possible,
to be transparent
with users about
a criteria by which you're
deciding what to
recommend to them.
I know this isn't always
easy, but ultimately,
I hope that being more
transparent with
users about why we're
showing them and why
will increase trust and
also cause our systems to
do more good for society.
Recommender systems are
very powerful technology,
a very profitable, a very
lucrative technology.
There are also some
problematic use cases.
If you are building one
of these systems using
recommender technology or
really any other machine
learning or other technology.
I hope you think through
not just the benefits
you can create,
but also the possible harm and
invite diverse perspectives
and discuss and debate.
Please only build things
and do things that
you really believe can
be society better off.
I hope that collectively,
all of us in the eye can
only do work that makes
people better off.
Thanks for listening.
We have just one
more video to go in
recommender systems in
which we take a look at
some practical tips
for how to implement
a content-based filtering
algorithm in TensorFlow.
Let's go on to that last