In this video, we'll take a look at how
you can use TensorFlow to implement
the collaborative filtering algorithm.
You might be used to thinking
of TensorFlow as a tool for
building neural networks.
And it is.
It's a great tool for
building neural networks.
And it turns out that TensorFlow
can also be very hopeful for
building other types of
learning algorithms as well.
Like the collaborative
filtering algorithm.
One of the reasons I like using TensorFlow
for talks like these is that for
many applications in order to
implement gradient descent,
you need to find the derivatives of
the cost function, but TensorFlow
can automatically figure out for you what
are the derivatives of the cost function.
All you have to do is implement the cost
function and without needing to know
any calculus, without needing
to take derivatives yourself,
you can get TensorFlow with
just a few lines of code
to compute that derivative term, that can
be used to optimize the cost function.
Let's take a look at how all this works.
You might remember this diagram
here on the right from course one.
This is exactly the diagram that
we had looked at when we talked
about optimizing w.
When we were working through our
first linear regression example.
And at that time we had set b=0.
And so
the model was just predicting f(x)=w.x.
And we wanted to find the value of w
that minimizes the cost function J.
So the way we were doing that was
via a gradient descent update,
which looked like this,
where w gets repeatedly updated as w minus
the learning rate alpha
times the derivative term.
If you are updating b as well,
this is the expression you will use.
But if you said b=0,
you just forgo the second update and
you keep on performing this gradient
descent update until convergence.
Sometimes computing this derivative or
partial derivative term can be difficult.
And it turns out that
TensorFlow can help with that.
Let's see how.
I'm going to use a very simple cost
function J=(wx-1) squared.
So wx is our simplified f w of x and
y is equal to 1.
And so this would be the cost
function if we had f(x) equals
wx,y equals 1 for
the one training example that we have, and
if we were not optimizing
this respect to b.
So the gradient descent algorithm
will repeat until convergence
this update over here.
It turns out that if you implement
the cost function J over here,
TensorFlow can automatically compute for
you this derivative term and
thereby get gradient descent to work.
I'll give you a high level overview of
what this code does, w=tf.variable(3.0).
Takes the parameter w and
initializes it to the value of 3.0.
Telling TensorFlow that w is
a variable is how we tell
it that w is a parameter
that we want to optimize.
I'm going to set x=1.0, y=1.0, and the
learning rate alpha to be equal to 0.01.
And let's run gradient dissent for
30 iterations.
So in this code will still do for iter in
range iterations, so for 30 iterations.
And this is the syntax to get TensorFlow
to automatically compute the rotors
for you.
TensorFlow has a feature
called a gradient tape.
And if you write this with tf
our gradient tape as tape f.
This is compute f(x) as w*x and
compute J as f(x)-y squared.
Then by telling TensorFlow
how to compute to costJ, and
by doing it with the gradient
taped syntax as follows,
TensorFlow will automatically
record the sequence of steps.
The sequence of operations
needed to compute the costJ.
And this is needed to enable
automatic differentiation.
Next TensorFlow will have saved
the sequence of operations in tape,
in the gradient tape.
And with this syntax,
TensorFlow will automatically
compute this derivative term,
which I'm going to call dJdw.
And TensorFlow knows you want to
take the derivative respected w.
That w is the parameter you want to
optimize because you had told it so
up here.
And because we're also
specifying it down here.
So now the computer derivatives,
finally you can carry out this
update by taking w and
subtracting from it the learning rate
alpha times that derivative term
that we just got from up above.
TensorFlow variables,
tier variables requires special handling.
Which is why instead of setting
w to be w minus alpha times
the derivative in the usual way,
we use this assigned add function.
But when you get to the practice lab,
don't worry about it.
We'll give you all the syntax you need
in order to implement the collateral
filtering algorithm correctly.
So notice that with the gradient
tape feature of TensorFlow,
the main work you need to do is to tell
it how to compute the cost function J.
And the rest of the syntax
causes TensorFlow to
automatically figure out for
you what is that derivative?
And with this TensorFlow we'll start
with finding the slope of this,
at 3 shown by this dash line.
Take a gradient step and update w and
compute the derivative again and
update w over and
over until eventually it gets to
the optimal value of w,
which is at w equals 1.
So this procedure allows you to
implement gradient descent without ever
having to figure out yourself how
to compute this derivative term.
This is a very powerful feature
of TensorFlow called Auto Diff.
And some other machine learning packages
like pytorch also support Auto Diff.
Sometimes you hear people
call this Auto Grad.
The technically correct term is Auto Diff,
and
Auto Grad is actually the name of
the specific software package for
doing automatic differentiation, for
taking derivatives automatically.
But sometimes if you hear someone refer to
Auto Grad, they're just referring to this
same concept of automatically
taking derivatives.
So let's take this and look at how
you can implement to collaborative
filtering algorithm using Auto Diff.
And in fact, once you can compute
derivatives automatically,
you're not limited to
just gradient descent.
You can also use a more powerful
optimization algorithm,
like the adam optimization algorithm.
In order to implement the collaborative
filtering algorithm TensorFlow,
this is the syntax you can use.
Let's starts with specifying
that the optimizer is keras
optimizers adam with learning
rate specified here.
And then for say, 200 iterations,
here's the syntax as before
with tf gradient tape, s tape,
you need to provide code to compute
the value of the cost function J.
So recall that in collaborative filtering,
the cost function J takes is
input parameters x, w, and
b as well as the ratings mean normalized.
So that's why I'm writing y norm, r(i,j)
specifying which values have a rating,
number of users or nu in our notation,
number of movies or nm in our notation or
just num as well as
the regularization parameter lambda.
And if you can implement
this cost function J,
then this syntax will cause TensorFlow
to figure out the derivatives for you.
Then this syntax will cause TensorFlow to
record the sequence of operations used to
compute the cost.
And then by asking it to give
you grads equals tape.gradient,
this will give you the derivative of the
cost function with respect to x, w, and b.
And finally with the optimizer
that we had specified up on top,
as the adam optimizer.
You can use the optimizer with
the gradients that we just computed.
And does it function in python is just a
function that rearranges the numbers into
an appropriate ordering for
the applied gradients function.
If you are using gradient descent for
collateral filtering,
recall that the cost function J would
be a function of w, b as well as x.
And if you are applying gradient descent,
you take the partial
derivative respect the w.
And then update w as follows.
And you would also take the partial
derivative of this respect to b.
And update b as follows.
And similarly update
the features x as follows.
And you repeat until convergence.
But as I mentioned earlier
with TensorFlow and
Auto Diff you're not limited
to just gradient descent.
You can also use a more powerful
optimization algorithm like the adam
optimizer.
The data set you use in the practice
lab is a real data set comprising
actual movies rated by actual people.
This is the movie lens dataset and
it's due to Harper and Konstan.
And I hope you enjoy running this
algorithm on a real data set of movies,
and ratings and see for yourself
the results that this algorithm can get.
So that's it.
That's how you can implement
the collaborative filtering algorithm in
TensorFlow.
If you're wondering why do
we have to do it this way?
Why couldn't we use a dense layer and
then model compiler and model fit?
The reason we couldn't use that old recipe
is, the collateral filtering algorithm and
cost function, it doesn't neatly
fit into the dense layer or
the other standard neural network
layer types of TensorFlow.
That's why we had to implement
it this other way where we would
implement the cost function ourselves.
But then use TensorFlow's tools for
automatic differentiation,
also called Auto Diff.
And use TensorFlow's implementation
of the adam optimization algorithm
to let it do a lot of the work for
us of optimizing the cost function.
If the model you have is a sequence
of dense neural network layers or
other types of layers
supported by TensorFlow, and
the old implementation recipe of
model compound model fit works.
But even when it isn't, these tools
TensoFlow give you a very effective way to
implement other learning
algorithms as well.
And so I hope you enjoy playing more with
the collateral filtering exercise in
this week's practice lab.
And looks like there's a lot of code and
lots of syntax, don't worry about it.
Make sure you have what you need to
complete that exercise successfully.
And in the next video, I'd like to also
move on to discuss more of the nuances of
collateral filtering and specifically the
question of how do you find related items,
given one movie,
whether other movies similar to this one.