I hope you enjoyed
the videos on how you
can build your own
recommender system.
Before we wrap up
this week in this and
a few other optional videos
I'd like to share with
you an unsupervised
learning algorithm
called principal
components analysis.
This is an algorithm that is
commonly used for visualization.
Specifically, if you
have a dataset with
a lot of features,
say 10 features or
50 features or even
thousands of features,
you can't plot 1,000
dimensional data.
PCA, or principal
components analysis
is an algorithm that lets
you take data with a lot
of features, 50, 1,000,
even more, and reduce
the number of features
to two features,
maybe three features,
so that you
can plot it and visualize it.
Is commonly used by
data scientists to
visualize the data,
to figure out what
might be going on.
Let's take a look at how PCA,
principal components
analysis works.
To describe PCA, I'm going
to use as a running example,
if you have data from a
collection of passenger cars,
and passenger cars can
have a lot of features.
You may know the length of
the car or the width of the car,
maybe the diameter of the wheel,
or maybe the height of the car,
and many other features of cars.
If you want to reduce
the number of features
so you can visualize it,
how can you use PCA to do so?
For the first example,
let's say you're given a
dataset with two features.
The feature x_1 is the
length of the car,
like so, and the
second feature x_2,
is the width of the car,
which is measured like so.
It turns out that
in most countries,
because of constraints
about the width
of the road the cars drive on,
width of the car
which has got to fit
within the width of the
road of a single lane,
tends not to vary that much.
For example, in
the United States,
most cars are,
let's call it about
1.8 meters wide,
that's just under six feet.
If you were to have
a collection of
cars and the dataset of
the length and
width of the cars,
you will find that the
dataset might look like this,
where x_1 varies quite a bit
because some cars are really
long and x_2 varies
relatively little.
If you want to reduce the
number of features, well,
one thing you could do is
let us take x_1 because
x_2 varies relatively
little from car to car.
It turns out that
PCA is an algorithm
that when applied to
this data set will
more or less automatically
decide to just take x_1,
but it can do much
more than that.
Let's look at a second example
where here x_1 is again
the length of the car,
and let's say that
in this dataset,
x_2 is the diameter
of the wheel.
The diameter of the wheel
does vary a little bit.
If you were to plot the data,
it might look like this.
But again, if you want to
simplify this dataset
to just one feature,
you might decide, let's
just take x_1 and
forget x_2 and PCA when
applied to this dataset.
Well, again, more or less,
cause you to just
check the feature x_1.
In both the examples we saw,
only one of the two
features seemed
to have a meaningful
degree of variation.
Here's a more complex example.
Say the feature x_1 is
the length of the car,
so that varies quite a bit,
and the feature x_2 here
is the height of the car,
which also varies quite a bit.
Some cars are much
taller than other cars.
If you were to plot the data,
you might get a dataset
that looks like this,
where some cars are bigger and
they tend to be
longer and taller,
and some cars are a
little bit smaller.
They tend to be not as
long and not as tall.
If you wanted to
reduce the number of
features, what should you pick?
You don't want to pick
just x_1, the length,
and ignore x_2 the height
and you also don't
want to pick just x_2,
the height, and ignore
x_1, the length.
It seems as if both x_1 and
x_2 have useful information.
In this graph,
x_1 and x_2 are the
two axes of this plot.
Instead of being
limited to taking
either the x_1 axis
or the x_2 axis,
what if we had a third axis.
I'm going to call this
new axis the z-axis.
To be clear, this is not
sticking out of this diagram.
This is a combination
of x_1 and x_2.
This is not a z-axis
that's sticking out in
the third dimension.
This z-axis lies flat
within this plot.
But why do we have
the z-axis which
corresponds to something
about the size of the car?
Given a car like this one
over here, its coordinate,
meaning the value
on the x-axis tells
us the length of the car
and the coordinate is just,
what is this distance?
Similarly its
coordinate, meaning,
what is this distance on
the x_2 axis tells us what
is the height of the car.
If we're now going to
use the z-axis instead
as one feature to capture what
we know about this car
then is coordinate on
the z-axis, meaning
this distance.
That tells us roughly what
is the size of the car.
We'll formalize this in
the next few videos.
But the idea of PCA is to
find one or more new axes,
such as z so that when you
measure your datas
coordinates on the new axis,
you end up still with
very useful information
about the car.
But maybe now,
instead of needing
two numbers corresponding to
the coordinates on
X_1 and X_2 axes,
the length and height.
You now need a few
numbers, in this case,
only one number instead of two,
to capture roughly
the size of the car.
In the example,
we've used so far,
we were trying to reduce
the data from two numbers,
X_1 and X_2 down to one number,
the coordinate on the z-axis.
In practice, PCA
is usually used to
reduce a very large
number of features,
say 10, 20,
50, even thousands of features,
down to maybe two or three
features so that you can
visualize the data in a
two-dimensional or in a
three-dimensional plot.
But for this video,
because I could only draw on
a two-dimensional screen.
I'm going to use mainly
two or three-dimensional
data sets
as my examples.
Let's look at one more example.
In this visualization, we
have a three-dimensional data
set and notice that I can
rotate the data set here,
so you can see it in 3D.
But notice if I rotate
the data set like this,
well, most of this data,
even though it is in 3D,
it actually lives on
a very thin surface.
It's almost as if
all the data lies
on a two-dimensional pancake,
even though the pancake
lives in this
three-dimensional space.
A PCA, what you can do is,
instead of having
three features, x_1,
x_2, x_3,
reduce it to two numbers,
which we're going to
call Z_1 and Z_2.
When you do that,
you can then visualize
the data on this Z_1,
Z_2 axis and this becomes
a convenient way to visualize
this data if you had to,
say print on a piece of paper.
I couldn't dynamically rotate
it like you'll seeing
me do on the screen.
Here's one more example.
If you have data about
the development status of
many different countries,
you might have for example
data about different countries,
GDP, and that's feature x_1.
In addition, Let's
say we also have
the per capita GDP and also
a measure of their Human
Development Index.
The Human Development
Index was developed
to measure the overall
progress of how well
people in a country might be
doing based on things
like the lifespan and
education and so on
or you might separately
have a feature
corresponding to
the life expectancy
in different countries
and so on and so forth.
If for each country
you have 50 features,
how can you visualize this
data because you can't plot
50 dimensional data on
a two-dimensional
computer monitor.
What PCLS will do is take
these 50 features,
X_1,X_2,X_3,X_4,
and so on and compress it
down to two features
which I'm going to call
Z_1 and Z_2 and you can then
plot these different countries
values of z_1 and z_2.
You might find for example
that Z_1 loosely corresponds
to how big is the country
and what is this total GDP?
Because larger countries
tend to have a higher GDP,
because large countries
have many people,
tend to have a larger economy
and perhaps you find that Z_2
corresponds roughly
to the per person GDP
or the amount of economic
activity per person.
For example, the United States,
which is a relatively
large country and has
relatively high per
person economic activity
may be somewhere up here
to the up and right of
this plot and a country
like Singapore,
where I live many years as well,
is a smaller country but it has
relatively high per
person economic activity.
Take on a lower value
on the z_1 axis,
but still a relatively high
value on the z_2 axis.
Whereas a country like
this would be maybe
a smaller country with
lower per person
economic activity.
Whereas the country like this
may be a large country with
lower per person economic
activity and a figure like
this lets you take
a large number of
features, 50 features.
Sometimes we also say
that's 50 dimensional data.
It just means we
have 50 features and
reduce that to two features
or sometimes we say
is two-dimensional data because
you can then plot it on
this two-dimensional plot
like you're seeing here.
Whenever I get a new data set,
one of the things I'll often
want to do is to visualize
the data since that helps me
understand what the
data looks like,
what do the countries look like,
or what do the cars seem
like in this data set
or whatever data you
may be examining.
You find also that
visualizing the data set will
sometimes help you figure out
something funny's going
on in this datas.
Something unexpected
is happening.
PCA is a powerful algorithm
for taking data with
a lot of features,
with a lot of dimensions
or high-dimensional data,
and reducing it to two
or three features to
two or three dimensional
data so you can plot
it and visualize it and better
understand what's in your data.
That's what the PCA
algorithm can do for you.
In the next video,
let's start to
take a look at how