In this video, we'll start
to develop a second type of
recommender system called
a content-based
filtering algorithm.
To get started, let's
compare and contrast
the collaborative filtering
approach that we'll be
looking at so far with
this new content-based
filtering approach.
Let's take a look.
With collaborative filtering,
the general approach is that
we would recommend items to
you based on ratings of
users who gave similar
ratings as you.
We have some number of users
give some ratings
for some items,
and the algorithm
figures out how to use
that to recommend
new items to you.
In contrast, content-based
filtering takes
a different approach to
deciding what to
recommend to you.
A content-based
filtering algorithm
will recommend items
to you based on
the features of users and
features of the items
to find a good match.
In other words, it
requires having some
features of each user,
as well as some features of
each item and it uses
those features to try to
decide which items and
users might be a good
match for each other.
With a content-based
filtering algorithm,
you still have data where
users have rated some items.
Well, content-based filtering
will continue to use r, i,
j to denote whether
or not user j has
rated item i and will
continue to use y i,
j to denote the rating
that user j is given
item i if it's defined.
But the key to
content-based filtering is that
we will be able to
make good use of
features of the user
and of the items to
find better matches than
potentially a pure collaborative
filtering approach
might be able to.
Let's take a look
at how this works.
In the case of movie
recommendations,
here are some
examples of features.
You may know the
age of the user,
or you may have the
gender of the user.
This could be a one-hot feature
similar to what you saw
when we were talking
about decision trees where you
could have a one-hot
feature with
the values based on whether
the user's
self-identified gender
is male or female or unknown,
and you may know the
country of the user.
If there are about 200 countries
in the world then also be
a one-hot feature with
about 200 possible values.
You can also look at
past behaviors of
the user to construct
this feature vector.
For example, if you look at
the top thousand movies
in your catalog,
you might construct a thousand
features that tells you of
the thousand most
popular movies in
the world which of these
has the user watch.
In fact, you can also take
ratings the user might
have already given in order
to construct new features.
It turns out that if you
have a set of movies
and if you know what
genre each movie is in,
then the average rating
per genre that the
user has given.
Of all the romance movies
that the user has rated,
what was the average rating?
Of all the action movies
that the user has rated,
what was the average rating?
And so on for all
the other genres.
This too can be a powerful
feature to describe the user.
One interesting thing about
this feature is that it
actually depends on the ratings
that the user had given.
But there's nothing
wrong with that.
Constructing a
feature vector that
depends on the user's ratings is
a completely fine way to
develop a feature vector
to describe that user.
With features like these
you can then come up
with a feature vector
x subscript u,
use as a user superscript
j for user j.
Similarly, you can also
come up with a set of
features for each
movie of each item,
such as what was the
year of the movie?
What's the genre or genres
of the movie of known?
If there are critic
reviews of the movie,
you can construct one
or multiple features to
capture something about what
the critics are saying
about the movie.
Or once again, you
can actually take
user ratings of the movie
to construct a feature of,
say, the average
rating of this movie.
This feature again
depends on the ratings
that users are given but again,
does nothing wrong with that.
You can construct a feature for
a given movie that
depends on the ratings
that movie had received,
such as the average
rating of the movie.
Or if you wish,
you can also have
average rating per country or
average rating per user
demographic as they
want to construct other types of
features of the movies as well.
With this, for each movie,
you can then construct
a feature vector,
which I'm going to
denote x subscript m,
m stands for movie,
and superscript i for movie i.
Given features like this,
the task is to try to
figure out whether
a given movie i is going to
be good match for user j.
Notice that the
user features and
movie features can be
very different in size.
For example, maybe the
user features could be
1500 numbers and
the movie features
could be just 50 numbers.
That's okay too. In
content-based filtering,
we're going to develop an
algorithm that learns to
match users and movies.
Previously, we were predicting
the rating of user j on movie
i as wj dot products
of xi plus bj.
In order to develop
content-based filtering,
I'm going to get rid of bj.
It turns out this won't hurt
the performance of the
content-based filtering at all.
Instead of writing wj for a
user j and xi for a movie i,
I'm instead going to just
replace this notation with vj_u.
This v here stands for a vector.
There'll be a list of
numbers computed for
user j and the u subscript
here stands for user.
Instead of xi,
I'm going to compute a
separate vector subscript m,
to stand for the movie and
for movie is what a
superscript stands for.
Vj_u as a vector as
a list of numbers
computed from the
features of user j
and vi_m is a list of
numbers computed from
the features like
the ones you saw on
the previous slide of movie i.
If we're able to come up with
an appropriate choice
of these vectors,
vj_u and vi_m,
then hopefully the dot product
between these two
vectors will be
a good prediction of
the rating that user
j gives movie i.
Just illustrate what
a learning algorithm
could come up with.
If v, u, that is a user vector,
turns out to capture
the user's preferences,
say is 4.9,
0.1, and so on.
Lists of numbers like that.
The first number captures
how much do they
like romance movies.
Then the second number
captures how much do they
like action movies and so on.
Then v_m, the movie
vector is 4.5, 0.2,
and so on and so forth
of these numbers
capturing how much is
this a romance movie,
how much is this an
action movie, and so on.
Then the dot product,
which multiplies these lists of
numbers element-wise
and then takes a sum,
hopefully, will give
a sense of how much
this particular user will
like this particular movie.
The challenges given features
of a user, say xj_u,
how can we compute
this vector vj_u that
represents succinctly or
compactly the
user's preferences?
Similarly given
features of a movie,
how can we compute vi_m?
Notice that whereas x_u
and x_m could be
different in size,
one could be very long
lists of numbers,
one could be much shorter list,
v here have to be the same size.
Because if you want to take
a dot product
between v_u and v_m,
then both of them have to
have the same dimensions such as
maybe both of these
are say 32 numbers.
To summarize, in
collaborative filtering,
we had number of users give
ratings of different items.
In contrast, in
content-based filtering,
we have features of users
and features of items and we
want to find a way to find
good matches between the
users and the items.
The way we're going to do so
is to compute these vectors,
v_u for the users and v_m for
the items over the movies,
and then take dot
products between
them to try to
find good matches.
How do we compute
the v_u and v_m?
Let's take a look at