Today's recommended systems will sometimes
need to pick a handful of items to
recommend.
From a catalog of thousands or millions or
10s of millions or even more items.
How do you do this efficiently
computationally, let's take a look.
Here's in your network we've been
using to make predictions about
how a user might rate an item.
Today a large movie streaming site
may have thousands of movies or
a system that is trying to
decide what ad to show.
May have a catalog of millions
of ads to choose from.
Or a music streaming sites may have 10s
of millions of songs to choose from.
And large online shopping
sites can have millions or
even 10s of millions of
products to choose from.
When a user shows up on your website,
they have some feature Xu.
But if you need to take thousands
of millions of items to feed
through this neural network in
order to compute in the product.
To figure out which products
you should recommend,
then having to run neural
network inference.
Thousands of millions of times every
time a user shows up on your website
becomes computational e infeasible.
Many law scale recommended
systems are implemented as two
steps which are called the retrieval and
ranking steps.
The idea is during the retrieval
step will generate
a large list of plausible item candidates.
That tries to cover a lot of possible
things you might recommend to the user and
it's okay during the retrieval step.
If you include a lot of items that
the user is not likely to like and
then during the ranking
step will fine tune and
pick the best items to
recommend to the user.
So here's an example, during the retrieval
step we might do something like.
For each of the last 10
movies that the user has
watched find the 10 most similar movies.
So this means for
example if a user has watched
the movie I with vector VIM
you can find the movies
hey with vector VKM that
is similar to that.
And as you saw in the last video
finding the similar movies,
the given movie can be pre computed.
So having pre computed the most
similar movies to give a movie,
you can just pull up the results
using a look up table.
This would give you an initial set of
maybe somewhat plausible movies to
recommend to user that just
showed up on your website.
Additionally you might
decide to add to it for
whatever are the most viewed
three genres of the user.
Say that the user has watched
a lot of romance movies and
a lot of comedy movies and
a lot of historical dramas.
Then we would add to the list of
possible item candidates the top 10
movies in each of these three genres.
And then maybe we will also
add to this list the top
20 movies in the country of the user.
So this retrieval step can
be done very quickly and
you may end up with a list of 100 or
maybe 100s of plausible movies.
To recommend to the user and
hopefully this list will
recommend some good options.
But it's also okay if it includes some
options that the user won't like at all.
The goal of the retrieval step
is to ensure broad coverage to
have enough movies at least
have many good ones in there.
Finally, we would then take all the items
we retrieve during the retrieval step and
combine them into a list.
Removing two cookers and removing items
that the user has already washed or
that the user has already purchased and
that you may not want to
recommend to them again.
The second step of this
is then the ranking step.
During the ranking step you will take the
list retrieved during the retrieval step.
So this may be just hundreds
of possible movies and
rank them using the learned model.
And what that means is you will
feed the user feature vector and
the movie feature actor
into this neural network.
And for each of the user movie
pairs compute the predicted rating.
And based on this, you now have
all of the se 100 plus movies,
the ones that the user is most
likely to give a high rating to.
And then you can just display the rank
list of items to the user depending on
what you think the user will give.
The highest rating to one
additional optimization is that
if you have computed VM.
For all the movies in advance,
then all you need to do is to do inference
on this part of the neural network
a single time to compute VU.
And then take that VU they just computed
for the user on your website right now.
And take the inner product between VU and
VM.
For the movies that you have
retrieved during the retrieval step.
So this computation can be
done relatively quickly.
If the retrieval step just
brings up say 100s of movies,
one of the decisions you need to make for
this album is how many items do you want
to retrieve during the retrieval step?
To feed into the more
accurate ranking step.
During the retrieval step,
retrieving more items will tend
to result in better performance.
But the algorithm will end up
being slower to analyze or
to optimize the trade off between
how many items to retrieve
to retrieve 100 or 500 or 1000 items.
I would recommend carrying out offline
experiments to see how much retrieving
additional items results in
more relevant recommendations.
And in particular,
if the estimated probability that YIJ.
Is equal to one according to
your neural network model.
Or if the estimated rating of Y
being high of the retrieve items
according to your model's prediction
ends up being much higher.
If only you were to retrieve say 500
items instead of only 100 items,
then that would argue for
maybe retrieving more items.
Even if it slows down the album a bit.
But with the separate retrieval step and
the ranking step, this allows
many recommended systems today to give
both fast as well as accurate results.
Because the retrieval step tries to
prune out a lot of items that are just
not worth doing the more detailed
influence and inner product on.
And then the ranking step makes
a more careful prediction for
what are the items that the user is
actually likely to enjoy so that's it.
This is how you make your
recommended system work efficiently
even on very large catalogs of movies or
products or what have you.
Now, it turns out that as commercially
important as our recommended systems,
there are some significant ethical
issues associated with them as well.
And unfortunately there have been
recommended systems that have
created harm.
So as you build your
own recommended system,
I hope you take an ethical approach and
use it to serve your users.
And society as large as
well as yourself and
the company that you might be working for.
Let's take a look at the ethical issues
associated with recommended systems in