If you come to an
online shopping website
and you're looking
at a specific item,
say maybe a specific book,
the website may show
you things like,
"Here are some other
books similar to this
one" or if you're browsing
a specific movie,
it may say, "Here are
some other movies
similar to this one."
How do the websites do that?,
so that when you're
looking at one item,
it gives you other similar or
related items to consider.
It turns out the collaborative
filtering algorithm
that we've been talking
about gives you a nice way to
find related items.
Let's take a look.
As part of the collaborative
filtering we've discussed,
you learned features
x^(i) for every item i,
for every movie i
or other type of
item they're
recommending to users.
Whereas early this week,
I had used a hypothetical
example of the features
representing how much a movie
is a romance movie
versus an action movie.
In practice, when you
use this algorithm to
learn the features
x^(i) automatically,
looking at the
individual features x_1,
x_2, x_3,
you find them to be
quite hard to interpret.
Is quite hard to learn
features and say,
x_1 is an action movie
and x_2 is as a foreign
film and so on.
But nonetheless, these
learned features,
collectively x_1, x_2, x_3,
other many features,
and you have collectively
these features
do convey something about
what that movie is like.
It turns out that given
features x^(i) of item i,
if you want to find other items,
say other movies
related to movie i,
then what you can do is try
to find the item k with
features x^(k) that
is similar to x^(i).
In particular, given a
feature vector x^(k),
the way we determine
what are known as
similar to the feature x^(i) is
as follows: is the sum from
l equals 1 through n with
n features of x^(k)_l
minus x^(i)_l square.
This turns out to be the
squared distance between
x^(k) and x^(i) and in math,
this squared distance
between these two vectors,
x^(k) and x^(i),
is sometimes written
as follows as well.
If you find not just
the one movie with
the smallest distance between
x^(k) and x^(i) but find say,
the five or 10 items with
the most similar
feature vectors,
then you end up finding
five or 10 related items
to the item x^(i).
If you're building a website
and want to help users find
related products to
a specific product
they are looking at,
this would be a nice
way to do so because
the features x^(i) give a
sense of what item i is about,
other items x^(k) with
similar features will turn
out to be similar to item i.
It turns out later this week,
this idea of finding
related items will be a small
building blocks that we'll
use to get to
an even more powerful
recommended system as well.
Before wrapping up this section,
I want to mention
a few limitations of
collaborative filtering.
In collaborative filtering, you
have a set of items and so
the users and the users have
rated some subset of items.
One of this
weaknesses is that is
not very good at the
cold start problem.
For example, if there's a
new item in your catalog,
say someone's just
published a new movie
and hardly anyone has
rated that movie yet,
how do you rank the new item
if very few users
have rated it before?
Similarly, for new users
that have rated
only a few items,
how can we make sure we show
them something reasonable?
We could see in
an earlier video,
how mean normalization can help
with this and it
does help a lot.
But perhaps even better ways to
show users that rated
very few items,
things that are likely
to interest them.
This is called the
cold start problem,
because when you
have a new item,
there are few users have rated,
or we have a new user that's
rated very few items,
the results of collaborative
filtering for that item
or for that user may
not be very accurate.
The second limitation of
collaborative filtering
is it doesn't give you
a natural way to use
side information
or additional information
about items or users.
For example, for a given
movie in your catalog,
you might know what is
the genre of the movie,
who had a movie stars,
whether it is a studio,
what is the budget, and so on.
You may have a lot of
features about a given movie.
For a single user,
you may know something
about their demographics,
such as their age,
gender, location.
They express preferences,
such as if they tell
you they like certain
movies genres
but not other movies genres,
or it turns out if you know
the user's IP address,
that can tell you a lot
about a user's location,
and knowing the user's
location might also help
you guess what might the
user be interested in,
or if you know whether
the user is accessing
your site on a mobile
or on a desktop,
or if you know what web
browser they're using.
It turns out all of these
are little cues you can get.
They can be surprisingly
correlated with the
preferences of a user.
It turns out by the way,
that it is known that users,
that use the Chrome
versus Firefox versus
Safari versus the
Microsoft Edge browser,
they actually behave in
very different ways.
Even knowing the user
web browser can give you
a hint when you have collected
enough data of what this
particular user may like.
Even though
collaborative filtering,
we have multiple users give
you ratings of multiple items,
is a very powerful
set of algorithms,
it also has some limitations.
In the next video,
let's go on to
develop content-based
filtering algorithms,
which can address a lot
of these limitations.
Content-based filtering
algorithms are
a steady art technique used in
many commercial
applications today.
Let's go take a look