In this video, we'll take a
look at how you can use the
scikit-learn library
to implement PCA.
These are the main steps.
First, if your features take
on very different
ranges of values,
you can perform
pre-processing to
scale the features to take on
comparable ranges of values.
If you were looking
at the features of
different countries,
those features take on very
different ranges of values.
GDP could be in
trillions of dollars,
whereas other features
are less than 100.
Feature scaling in applications
like that would be
important to help PCA find a
good choice of axes for you.
The next step then is to
run the PCA algorithm to
"fit" the data to obtain
two or three new axes,
Z_1, Z_2, and maybe Z_3.
Here I'm assuming you want
two or three axes if you
want to visualize the
data in 2D or 3D.
If you have an
application where you
want more than two
or three axes,
the PCA implementation can
also give you more than
two or three axes,
it's just that it'd then
be harder to visualize.
In scikit-learn, you will
use the fit function,
or the fit method in
order to do this.
The fit function in PCA
automatically carries
out mean normalization,
it subtracts out the
mean of each feature.
So you don't need to
separately perform
mean normalization.
After running the fit function,
you would get the new axes, Z_1,
Z_2, maybe Z_3, and in PCA,
we also call these the
principal components,
where Z_1 is the first
principal component,
Z_2 the second
and Z_3 the third
principal component.
After that, I would
recommend taking
a look at how much each
of these new axes,
or each of these new
principal components
explains the variance
in your data.
I'll show a concrete example of
what this means on
the next slide,
but this lets you get
a sense of whether
or not projecting
the data onto these axes help
you to retain most
of the variability,
or most of the information
in the original dataset.
This is done using the explained
variance ratio function.
Finally, you can transform,
meaning just project the
data onto the new axes,
onto the new
principal components,
which you will do with
the transform method.
Then for each training example,
you would just have
two or three numbers,
you can then plot those
two or three numbers
to visualize your data.
In detail, this is what
PCA in code looks like.
Here's the dataset X
with six examples.
X equals NumPy array,
the six examples over here.
To run PCA to reduce this
data from two numbers, X_1,
X_2 to just one number Z,
you would run PCA and ask it
to fit one principal component.
N components here
is equal to one,
and fit PCA to X. Pca_1
here is my notation
for PCA with a single
principle component,
with a single axis.
It turns out, if you
were to print out
pca_1.explained_variance_ratio,
this is 0.992.
This tells you that
in this example
when you choose one axis,
this captures 99.2 percent
of the variability or of
the information in
the original dataset.
Finally, if you want
to take each of
these training samples and
project it to a single number,
you would then call this,
and this will output
this array with
six numbers corresponding to
your six training examples.
For example, the first
training example 1,1,
projected to the
Z-axis gives you
this number, 1.383, so on.
So if you were to visualize
this dataset using
just one dimension,
this will be the number I
use to represent
the first example.
The second example is projected
to be this number and so on.
I hope you take a
look at the optional
lab where you see that
these six examples
have been projected
down onto this axis,
onto this line which is now Y.
All six examples now lie
on this line that
looks like this.
The first training example,
which was 1,1,
has been mapped to this example,
which has a distance of
1.38 from the origin,
so that's why this is 1.38.
Just one more quick example.
This data is
two-dimensional data,
and we reduced it
to one dimensions.
What if you were to compute
two principal components?
Starts with two-dimensions,
and then also end up
with two-dimensions.
This isn't that useful for
visualization but it
might help us understand
better how PCA and how
they code for PCA works.
Here's the same code
except that I've
changed n components to two.
I'm going to ask
the algorithm to
find two principal components.
If you do that the pca_2 explain
ratio becomes 0.992, 0.008.
What that means is that z_1,
the first principle components,
still continuous explain 99.2
percent of the variance,
Z_2 the second
principle components,
or the second axis,
explains 0.8 percent
of the variance.
These two numbers
together add up to one.
Because while this data
is two-dimensional,
so the two axes,
Z_1 and Z_2,
together they
explain 100 percent
of the variance in the data.
If you were to
transform our project
the data onto the
Z_1 and Z_2 axes,
this is what you get,
with now the first
training example is
napped too these two numbers,
corresponding to its
projection onto z_1,
and z_2, and the second example,
which is this projected
onto z_1 and z_2,
becomes these two numbers.
If you were to reconstruct
the original data
roughly this is z_1,
and this z_2,
then the first training
example which was a [1,
1] has a distance of
1.38 on the z_1 axis,
has this number and
the distance here of
0.29 hence this distance
on the z_2 axis,
and the reconstruction
actually looks
exactly the same as
the original data.
Because, if you
reduce or not really
reduce two-dimensional data
to two-dimensional data,
there is no approximation
and you can get back to
your original dataset,
with the projections
onto z_1 and z_2.
This is what the code
to run PCA looks like.
I hope you take a look at
the optional lab where you can
play with this more yourself.
Also try varying the
parameters look at
a specific example to deepen
your intuition about
how PCA works.
Before wrapping up,
I'd like to share
a little bit of advice
for applying PCA.
PCA is frequently used for
visualization where you reduce
data to two or three
numbers so you can plot it.
Like you saw in an earlier
video with the data
on different countries so you
can visualize
different countries.
There are some other
applications of
PCA that you may
occasionally hear about.
That used to be more popular,
maybe 10,15, 20 years ago
but much less so now.
Another possible use of
PCA is data compression.
For example, if you have
a database of lots
of different cars,
and you have 50
features per car,
but it's just taking
up too much space on
your database or maybe
transmitting 50 numbers
over the Internet,
just takes too long.
Then one thing you
could do is reduce
these 50 features to a
smaller number of features.
It could be 10 features with
10 axes or 10
principal components.
You can visualize 10-dimensional
data that easily,
but this is 1/5 of
the storage space,
or maybe 1/5 over the network
transmission costs needed.
Many years ago I saw
PCA use for this
application and more often,
but today with modern storage
being able to store
pretty large datasets
and modern networking,
able to transmit faster and
more data than ever before.
I see this use much less often
as an application of PCA.
One of the applications
of PCA that again
used to be more common
maybe 10 years ago,
20 years ago, but
much less so now is
using it to speed up
training of a supervised
learning model.
Where the idea is,
if you had 1,000 features,
and having a 1,000 features may
the supervised learning
algorithm runs you slowly.
Maybe you can reduce it
to 100 features using PCA
and then your dataset is
basically smaller and
your supervised learning
algorithm may run faster.
This used to make a difference
in the running time
of some of the older generations
of learning algorithms,
such as if you have had a
support vector machines.
This will speed up a
support vector machine.
But it turns out with modern
machine learning algorithms,
algorithms like deep learning,
this doesn't actually
hold that much,
and is much more common to
just take the
high-dimensional dataset,
and feed it into say
your neural network.
Rather than run PCA because
PCA has some computational
cost as well.
You may hear about this in some
of the other research papers,
but I don't really see
this done much anymore.
But the most common
thing that I use
PCA for today is
visualization and then I
find it very useful to reduce
the dimensional data
to visualize it.
Thanks for sticking
with me through
the end of the optional
videos for this week,
I hope you enjoy learning about
PCA and that you
find a useful when
you get a new
dataset for reducing
the dimension of the dataset
to two or three dimensions
so you can visualize
it and hopefully
gain new insights
into your data sets.
There's helped me many times
understand my own datasets and I
hope that you find it
equally useful as well.
Thanks for watching
these videos and I
look forward to