A good way to develop
a content-based
filtering algorithm
is to use deep learning.
The approach you see in
this video is the way that
many important commercial
state-of-the-art content-based
filtering algorithms
are built today.
Let's take a look.
Recall that in our approach,
given a feature vector
describing a user,
such as age and
gender, and country,
and so on, we have to compute
the vector v_u, and similarly,
given a vector describing
a movie such as year of release,
the stars in the
movie, and so on,
we have to compute a vector v_m.
In order to do the former,
we're going to use
a neural network.
The first neural network will
be what we'll call
the user network.
Here's an example
of user network,
that takes as input the list
of features of the user, x_u,
so the age, the gender,
the country of the
user, and so on.
Then using a few layers,
say dense neural network layers,
it will output this vector
v_u that describes the user.
Notice that in this
neural network,
the output layer has 32 units,
and so v_u is actually
a list of 32 numbers.
Unlike most of the
neural networks
that we were using earlier,
the final layer is not
a layer with one unit,
it's a layer with 32 units.
Similarly, to compute
v_m for a movie,
we can have a movie
network as follows,
that takes as input
features of the movie and
through a few layers of
a neural network
is outputting v_m,
that vector that
describes the movie.
Finally, we'll predict the
rating of this user on
that movie as v_ u
dot product with v_m.
Notice that the user network
and the movie network can
hypothetically have
different numbers of
hidden layers and
different numbers
of units per hidden layer.
All the output layer needs to
have the same size of
the same dimension.
In the description
you've seen so far,
we were predicting the 1-5
or 0-5 star movie rating.
If we had binary labels,
if y was to the user
like or favor an item,
then you can also modify
this algorithm to output.
Instead of v_u.v_m,
you can apply the
sigmoid function
to that and use this to
predict the probability
that's y^i,j is 1.
To flesh out this notation,
we can also add
superscripts i and
j here if we want
to emphasize that
this is the prediction
by user j on movie
i. I've drawn here
the user network
and the movie network as two
separate neural networks.
But it turns out
that we can actually
draw them together in
a single diagram as if it
was a single neural network.
This is what it looks like.
On the upper portion
of this diagram,
we have the user network which
inputs x_u and ends
up computing v_u.
On the lower portion
of this diagram,
we have what was
the movie network,
the input is x_m and
ends up computing v_m,
and these two vectors are
then dot-product together.
This dot here
represents dot product,
and this gives us
our prediction.
Now, this model has
a lot of parameters.
Each of these layers of
a neural network has
a usual set of parameters
of the neural network.
How do you train all
the parameters of
both the user network
and the movie network?
What we're going to do is
construct a cost function J,
which is going to
be very similar to
the cost function that you
saw in collaborative filtering,
which is assuming
that you do have
some data of some users
having rated some movies,
we're going to sum
over all pairs i and
j of where you have labels,
where i,j equals 1
of the difference
between the prediction.
That would be v_u^j
dot product with
v_m^i minus y^ij squared.
The way we would
train this model
is depending on the parameters
of the neural network,
you end up with
different vectors
here for the users
and for the movies.
What we'd like to do is
train the parameters
of the neural network
so that you end up with
vectors for the users and for
the movies that results in
small squared error into
predictions you get out here.
To be clear, there's
no separate training procedure
for the user and movie networks.
This expression down here,
this is the cost
function used to train
all the parameters of the
user and the movie networks.
We're going to judge the two
networks according to how
well v_u and v_m predict y^ij,
and with this cost function,
we're going to use
gradient descent or
some other optimization
algorithm to tune
the parameters of the
neural network to cause
the cost function J to
be as small as possible.
If you want to
regularize this model,
we can also add the usual neural
network regularization term to
encourage the neural
networks to keep
the values of their
parameters small.
It turns out, after you've
trained this model,
you can also use this
to find similar items.
This is akin to
what we have seen
with collaborative
filtering features,
helping you find similar items
as well. Let's take a look.
V_u^j is a vector of
length 32 that describes
a user j that have
features x_ u^j.
Similarly, v^i_m is a vector
of length 32 that describes
a movie with these
features over here.
Given a specific movie,
what if you want to find
other movies similar to it?
Well, this vector v^i_m
describes the movie i.
If you want to find other
movies similar to it,
you can then look for other
movies k so that the distance
between the vector describing
movie k and the vector
describing movie i,
that the squared
distance is small.
This expression plays
a role similar to what
we had previously with
collaborative filtering,
where we talked about finding
a movie with features
x^k that was similar
to the features x^i.
Thus, with this approach,
you can also find items
similar to a given item.
One final note, this can be
pre-computed ahead of time.
By that I mean,
you can run a compute
server overnight to
go through the list of
all your movies and
for every movie,
find similar movies to
it, so that tomorrow,
if a user comes to
the website and
they're browsing
a specific movie,
you can already have
pre-computed to
10 or 20 most similar movies
to show to the
user at that time.
The fact that you can
pre-compute ahead of
time what's similar
to a given movie,
will turn out to be important
later when we talk about scaling
up this approach to a very
large catalog of movies.
That's how you can use
deep learning to build
a content-based
filtering algorithm.
You might remember when we
were talking about
decision trees
and the pros and cons of
decision trees versus
neural networks.
I mentioned that one
of the benefits of
neural networks is that
it's easier to take
multiple neural networks and
put them together to make them
work in console to
build a larger system.
What you just saw was
actually an example of that,
where we could take
a user network and
the movie network and
put them together,
and then take the inner
product of the outputs.
This ability to put
two neural networks
together this how we've
managed to come up with
a more complex architecture
that turns out to
be quite powerful.
One notes, if you're
implementing these
algorithms in practice,
I find that developers often
end up spending a lot
of time carefully
designing the features
needed to feed
into these content-based
filtering algorithms.
If we end up building one of
these systems commercially,
it may be worth
spending some time
engineering good features for
this application as well.
In terms of these applications,
one limitation
that the algorithm
as we've described
it is it can be
computationally very
expensive to run if you have
a large catalog of a lot of
different movies you
may want to recommend.
In the next video, let's
take a look at some of
the practical issues
and how you can modify
this algorithm to make a
scale that are working
on even very large
item catalogs.
Let's go see that