In the practice lab, you
see how to implement
content-based filtering
in TensorFlow.
What I'd like to
do in this video
is just set through
of you a few of
the key concepts in the code
that you get to play
with. Let's take a look.
Recall that our code
has started with
a user network as well
as a movie that's work.
The way you can implement
this in TensorFlow is,
it's very similar to
how we have previously
implemented a neural network
with a set of dense layers.
We're going to use
a sequential model.
We then in this example have
two dense layers with
the number of hidden
units specified here,
and the final layer has 32
units and output's 32 numbers.
Then for the movie network,
I'm going to call it
the item network,
because the movies
are the items here,
this is what the
code looks like.
Once again, we have coupled
dense hidden layers,
followed by this layer,
which outputs 32 numbers.
For the hidden layers, we'll use
our default choice of
activation function,
which is the relu
activation function.
Next, we need to tell
TensorFlow Keras how to
feed the user features
or the item features,
that is the movie features
to the two neural networks.
This is the syntax for doing so.
That extracts out the
input features for
the user and then
feeds it to the user
and that we had defined
up here to compute vu,
the vector for the user.
Then one additional step
that turns out to make
this algorithm work a bit
better is at this line here,
which normalizes the vector
vu to have length one.
This normalizes the length,
also called the l2 norm,
but basically the length of
the vector vu to
be equal to one.
Then we do the same thing
for the item network,
for the movie network.
This extract out the item
features and feeds it to
the item neural network
that we defined up there
This computes the
movie vector vm.
Then finally, the step also
normalizes that vector
to have length one.
After having computed vu and vm,
we then have to take
the dot product between
these two vectors.
This is the syntax for doing so.
Keras has a special layer type,
notice we had here tf
keras layers dense,
here this is tf
keras layers dot.
It turns out that there's
a special Keras layer,
they just takes a dot
product between two numbers.
We're going to use that to take
the dot product between
the vectors vu and vm.
This gives the output
of the neural network.
This gives the final prediction.
Finally, to tell keras
what are the inputs and
outputs of the model,
this line tells it that
the overall model is
a model with inputs
being the user features and
the movie or the item
features and the output,
this is output that we
just defined up above.
The cost function that we'll
use to train this model
is going to be the mean
squared error cost function.
These are the key
code snippets for
implementing content-based
filtering as a neural network.
You see the rest of the code in
the practice lab but
hopefully you'll be
able to play with
that and see how all these
code snippets fit together
into working TensorFlow
implementation
of a content-based
filtering algorithm.
It turns out that there's
one other step that I didn't
talk about previously,
but if you do this,
which is normalize the
length of the vector vu,
that makes the algorithm
work a bit better.
TensorFlows has this
l2 normalized motion
that normalizes the vector,
is also called normalizing
the l2 norm of the vector,
hence the name of the function.
That's it. Thanks for
sticking with me through
all this material on
recommender systems,
it is an exciting technology.
I hope you enjoy playing with
these ideas and codes in the
practice labs for this week.
That takes us to the lots of
these videos on
recommender systems and to
the end of the next to
final week for this
specialization.
I look forward to seeing
you next week as well.
We'll talk about the
exciting technology
of reinforcement learning.
Hope you have fun with
the quizzes and with
the practice labs and I
look forward to