Back in the first course,
you have seen how for linear regression,
future normalization can help
the algorithm run faster.
In the case of building
a recommended system
with numbers wide such as movie
ratings from one to five or
zero to five stars, it turns out your
algorithm will run more efficiently.
And also perform a bit better if you
first carry out mean normalization.
That is if you normalize the movie ratings
to have a consistent average value,
let's take a look at what that means.
So here's the data set
that we've been using.
And down below is the cost function
you used to learn the parameters for
the model.
In order to explain mean normalization,
Im ctually going to add fifth user
Eve who has not yet rated any movies.
And you see in a little bit that
adding mean normalization will
help the algorithm make better
predictions on the user Eve.
In fact, if you were to train
a collaborative filtering algorithm
on this data, then because we
are trying to make the parameters w
small because of this regularization term.
If you were to run
the algorithm on this dataset,
you actually end up with
the parameters w for the fifth user,
for the user Eve to be equal to [0
0] as well as quite likely b(5) = 0.
Because Eve hasn't rated any movies yet,
the parameters w and
b don't affect this first term in
the cost function because none of
Eve's movie's rating play a role in
this squared error cost function.
And so minimizing this means making
the parameters w as small as possible.
We didn't really regularize b.
But if you initialize b to 0 as the
default, you end up with b(%) = 0 as well.
But if these are the parameters for
user 5 that is for
Eve, then what the average
will end up doing is predict
that all of Eve's movies ratings
with be w(%).x for movie i + b(5).
And this is equal to 0 if w and
b above equals 0.
And so this algorithm will predict that
if you have a new user that has not yet
rated anything, we think they'll
rate all movies with zero stars and
that's not particularly hopeful.
So in this video, we'll see that
mean normalization will help this
algorithm come up with better
predictions of the movie ratings for
a new user that has not yet
rated any movies.
In order to describe mean normalization,
let me take all of the values here
including all the question marks for
Eve and put them in a two
dimensional matrix like this.
Just to write out all the ratings
including the question marks in a more
sustained and more compact way.
To carry out mean normalization,
what we're going to do is take
all of these ratings and for
each movie,
compute the average rating that was given.
So movie one had two 5s and two 0s and
so the average rating is 2.5.
Movie two had a 5 and a 0,
so that averages out to 2.5.
Movie three 4 and 0 averages out to 2.
Movie four averages out to 2.25 rating.
And movie five not that popular,
has an average 1.25 rating.
So I'm going to take all
of these five numbers and
gather them into a vector which I'm
going to call μ because this is the vector
of the average ratings that
each of the movies had.
Averaging over just the users that
did read that particular movie.
Instead of using these original 0
to 5 star ratings over here, I'm
going to take this and subtract from every
rating the mean rating that it was given.
So for example this movie rating was 5.
I'm going to subtract 2.5
giving me 2.5 over here.
This movie had a 0 star rating.
I'm going to subtract 2.25 giving
me a -2.25 rating and so on for all
of the now five users including the new
user Eve as well as for all five movies.
Then these new values on the right
become your new values of Y(i,j).
We're going to pretend that user 1 had
given a 2.5 rating to movie one and
the -2.25 rating to movie four.
And using this, you can then learn w(j),
b(j) and x(i) same as before for
user j on movie i,
you would predict w(j).x(i) + b(j).
But because we had subtracted off µi for
movie i during this mean
normalization step,
in order to predict not a negative star
rating which is impossible for
user rates from 0 to 5 stars.
We have to add back this µi which is
just the value we have subtracted out.
So as a concrete example,
if we look at what happens with user
5 with the new user Eve because
she had not yet rated any movies,
the average might learn parameters
w(5) = [0 0] and say b(5) = 0.
And so
if we look at the predicted rating for
movie one, we will predict that Eve will
rate it w(5).x1 + b(5) but this is 0 and
then + µ1 which is equal to 2.5.
So this seems more reasonable to think
Eve is likely to rate this movie
2.5 rather than think Eve will rate
all movie zero stars just because she
hasn't rated any movies yet.
And in fact the effect of this
algorithm is it will cause
the initial guesses for
the new user Eve to be just equal to
the mean of whatever other users
have rated these five movies.
And that seems more reasonable to
take the average rating of the movies
rather than to guess that all
the ratings by Eve will be zero.
It turns out that by normalizing
the mean of the different movies ratings
to be zero, the optimization algorithm for
the recommended system will also
run just a little bit faster.
But it does make the algorithm
behave much better for
users who have rated no movies or
very small numbers of movies.
And the predictions will
become more reasonable.
In this example,
what we did was normalize each of the rows
of this matrix to have zero mean and
we saw this helps when there's a new user
that hasn't rated a lot of movies yet.
There's one other alternative that
you could use which is to instead
normalize the columns of this
matrix to have zero mean.
And that would be
a reasonable thing to do too.
But I think in this application,
normalizing the rows so
that you can give reasonable ratings for
a new user seems more important
than normalizing the columns.
Normalizing the columns would hope if
there was a brand new movie that no one
has rated yet.
But if there's a brand new movie
that no one has rated yet,
you probably shouldn't show that movie
to too many users initially because you
don't know that much about that movie.
So normalizing columns the hope with
the case of a movie with no ratings
seems less important to me
than normalizing the rules
to hope with the case of a new user
that's hardly rated any movies yet.
And when you are building your own
recommended system in this week's
practice lab, normalizing just
the roles should work fine.
So that's mean normalization.
It makes the algorithm
run a little bit faster.
But even more important, it makes
the algorithm give much better, much
more reasonable predictions when there
are users that rated very few movies or
even no movies at all.
This implementation detail of mean
normalization will make your recommended
system work much better.
Next, let's go into the next video to
talk about how you can implement this for