Welcome to this second to last week of
the machine learning specialization.
I'm really happy that together,
almost all the way to the finish line.
What we'll do this week is
discuss recommended systems.
This is one of the topics that has
received quite a bit of attention
in academia.
But the commercial impact and
the actual number of practical use cases
of recommended systems seems to me to be
even vastly greater than the amount of
attention it has received in academia.
Every time you go to an online
shopping website like Amazon or
a movie streaming sites like Netflix or
go to one of the apps or
sites that do food delivery.
Many of these sites will recommend things
to you that they think you may want to buy
or movies they think you
may want to watch or
restaurants that they think
you may want to try out.
And for many companies,
a large fraction of sales is driven
by their recommended systems.
So today for many companies, the economics
or the value driven by recommended systems
is very large and so what we're doing this
week is take a look at how they work.
So with that let's dive in and take
a look at what is a recommended system.
I'm going to use as a running example, the
application of predicting movie ratings.
So say you run a large
movie streaming website and
your users have rated movies
using one to five stars.
And so in a typical recommended
system you have a set of users,
here we have four users Alice,
Bob Carol and Dave.
Which have numbered users 1,2,3,4.
As well as a set of movies Love at last,
Romance forever,
Cute puppies of love and then Nonstop
car chases and Sword versus karate.
And what the users have done is rated
these movies one to five stars.
Or in fact to make some of these
examples a little bit easier.
I'm not going to let them rate
the movies from zero to five stars.
So say Alice has rated Love and last
five stars, Romance forever five stars.
Maybe she has not yet
watched cute puppies of love so
you don't have a rating for that.
And I'm going to denote that
via a question mark and
she thinks nonstop car chases and sword
versus karate deserve zero stars bob.
Race at five stars has not watched that,
so
you don't have a rating
race at four stars, 0,0.
Carol on the other hand,
things that deserve zero stars has not
watched that zero stars and
she loves nonstop car chases and
swords versus karate and
Dave raise the movies as follows.
In the typical recommended system,
you have some number of users
as well as some number of items.
In this case the items are movies that
you want to recommend to the users.
And even though I'm using movies in this
example, the same logic or the same thing.
Work for recommending anything from
products or website myself to restaurants,
to even which media articles,
the social media articles to show,
to the user that may be
more interesting for them.
The notation I'm going to use is I'm going
to use nu to denote the number of users.
So in this example nu is equal to
four because you have four users and
nm to denote the number of movies or
really the number of items.
So in this example nm is equal to
five because we have five movies.
I'm going to set r(i,j)=1,
if user j has rated movie i.
So for example, use a one
Dallas Alice has rated movie one but
has not rated movie three and
so r(1,1) =1,
because she has rated movie one, but
r( 3,1)=0 because she has not
rated movie number three.
Then finally I'm going to use y(i,j).
J to denote the rating
given by user j to movie i.
So for example,
this rating here would be that movie three
was rated by user 2 to be equal to four.
Notice that not every user rates
every movie and it's important for
the system to know which users
have rated which movies.
That's why we're going to define
r(i,j)=1 if user j has rated movie i and
will be equal to zero if user
j has not rated movie i.
So with this framework for recommended
systems one possible way to approach
the problem is to look at the movies
that users have not rated.
And to try to predict how users would
rate those movies because then we can try
to recommend to users things that they
are more likely to rate as five stars.
And in the next video we'll start
to develop an algorithm for
doing exactly that.
But making one very special assumption.
Which is we're going to assume temporarily
that we have access to features or
extra information about the movies such
as which movies are romance movies,
which movies are action movies.
And using that will start
to develop an algorithm.
But later this week will actually come
back and ask what if we don't have these
features, how can you still
get the algorithm to work then?
But let's go on to the next video to