Many important applications
of recommended systems or
collective filtering algorithms
involved binary labels where instead of
a user giving you a one to five star or
zero to five star rating, they just
somehow give you a sense of they like
this item or they did not like this item.
Let's take a look at how to generalize
the algorithm you've seen to this setting.
The process we'll use to generalize the
algorithm will be very much reminiscent
to how we have gone from linear regression
to logistic regression, to predicting
numbers to predicting a binary label
back in course one, let's take a look.
Here's an example of a collaborative
filtering data set with binary labels.
A one the notes that the user liked or
engaged with a particular movie.
So label one could mean that Alice watched
the movie Love at last all the way to
the end and watch romance
forever all the way to the end.
But after playing a few minutes of nonstop
car chases decided to stop the video and
move on.
Or it could mean that she
explicitly hit like or
favorite on an app to indicate
that she liked these movies.
But after checking out
nonstop cloud chasers and
swords versus karate did not hit like.
And the question mark usually means
the user has not yet seen the item and so
they weren't in a position to decide
whether or not to hit like or
favorite on that particular item.
So the question is how can we take the
collaborative filtering average that you
saw in the last video and
get it to work on this daaset.
And by predicting how likely Alice,
Bob carol and
Dave are to like the items
that they have not yet rated,
we can then decide how much we should
recommend these items to them.
There are many ways of defining what is
the label one and what is the label zero,
and what is the label question mark in
collaborative filtering with binary
labels.
Let's take a look at a few examples.
In an online shopping website,
the label could denote whether or
not music they chose to purchase
an item after they were exposed to it,
after they were shown the item.
So one would denote that they purchase
it zero would denote that they did
not purchase it.
And the question mark would denote that
they were not even shown were not even
exposed to the item.
Or in a social media setting,
the labels one or
zero could denote did the user favorite or
like an item after they were shown it.
And question mark would be if they
have not yet been shown the item or
many sites instead of asking for
explicit user rating will use
the user behavior to try to
guess if the user like the item.
So for example, you can measure if a user
spends at least 30 seconds of an item.
And if they did, then assign that a label
one because the user found the item
engaging or
if a user was shown an item but
did not spend at least 30 seconds with it,
then a sign that a label zero.
Or if the user was not shown the item yet,
then assign it a question mark.
Another way to generate a rating
implicitly as a function
of the user behavior will be to see
that the user click on an item.
This is often done in online advertising
where if the user has been shown an ad,
if they clicked on it
assigned to the labor one,
if they did not click assigned to
the label zero and the question mark were
referred to if the user has not even
been shown that ad in the first place.
So often these binary labels will
have a rough meaningless follows.
A labor of one means that the user
engaged after being shown an item And
engaged could mean that they clicked or
spend 30 seconds or
explicitly favorite or
like to purchase the item.
A zero will reflect the user not
engaging after being shown the item,
the question mark will reflect the item
not yet having been shown to the user.
So given these binary labels,
let's look at how we can generalize our
algorithm which is a lot like linear
regression from the previous couple videos
to predicting these binary outputs.
Previously we were predicting
label yij as wj.xi+b.
So this was a lot like
a linear regression model.
For binary labels, we're going to predict
that the probability of yijb=1
is given by not wj.xi+b.
But it said by g of this formula,
we're now g(z) 1/1 +e to the -z.
So this is the logistic function just
like we saw in logistic regression.
And what we would do is take what was
a lot like a linear regression model and
turn it into something that would
be a lot like a logistic regression
model where will now predict
the probability of yij being
1 that is of the user having engaged
with or like the item using this model.
In order to build this algorithm,
we'll also have to modify the cost
function from the squared error
cost function to the cost function
that is more appropriate for
binary labels for
a logistic regression like model.
So previously, this was the cost
function that we had where this term
play their role similar to f(x),
the prediction of the algorithm.
When you now have binary labels,
yij when the labels are one or zero or
question mark, then the prediction f(x)
becomes instead of wj.xi+b j it becomes g
of this where g is the logistic function.
And similar to when we had
derived logistic regression,
we had written out
the following loss function for
a single example which was at the loss
if the algorithm predicts f(x) and
the true label was y, the loss was this.
It was -y log
f-y log 1-f.
This is also sometimes called
the binary cross entropy cost function.
But this is a standard cost function that
we used for logistic regression as was for
the binary classification problems
when we're training neural networks.
And so to adapt this to
the collaborative filtering setting,
let me write out the cost function
which is now a function of all
the parameters w and
b as well as all the parameters x
which are the features of
the individual movies or items of.
We now need to some over all
the pairs ij where riij=1 notice
this is just similar to
the summation up on top.
And now instead of this
squared error cost function,
we're going to use that loss function.
There's a function of f(x), yij.
Where f(x) here?
That's my abbreviation.
My shorthand for g(w) j.x1+ej.
As we plug this into here,
then this gives you the cost function
they could use for
collaborative filtering on binary labels.
So that's it.
That's how you can take
the linear regression,
like collaborative filtering algorithm and
generalize it to work with binary labels.
And this actually very significantly opens
up the set of applications you can address
with this algorithm.
Now, even though you've
seen the key structure and
cost function of the algorithm,
there are also some implementation,
all tips that will make your
algorithm work much better.
Let's go on to the next video to take a
look at some details of how you implement
it and some little modifications
that make the album run much faster.