Now that you've seen how the Gaussian or
the normal distribution works for
a single number, we're ready to build
our anomaly detection algorithm.
Let's dive in.
You have a training set x1 through xm,
where here each example
x has end features.
So, each example x is
a vector within numbers.
In the case of the airplane
engine example,
we had two features corresponding
to the heat and the vibrations.
And so, each of these excise would
be a two dimensional vector and
n would be equal to 2.
But for many practical applications
n can be much larger and
you might do this with dozens or
even hundreds of features.
Given this training set,
what we would like to do is to carry
out density estimation and
all that means is,
we will build a model or
estimate the probability for p(x).
What's the probability of
any given feature vector?
And our model for
p(x) is going to be as follows,
x is a feature vector with values x1,
x2 and so on down to xn.
And I'm going to model p(x)
as the probability of x1,
times the probability of x2,
times the probably of x3
times the probability of xn,
for the n th features
in the feature vectors.
If you've taken an advanced class
in probably in statistics before,
you may recognize that this equation
corresponds to assuming that
the features x1, x2 and so
on up to xm are statistically independent.
But it turns out this algorithm often
works fine even that the features
are not actually
statistically independent.
But if you don't understand what I
just said, don't worry about it.
Understanding physical independence is
not needed to fully complete discuss and
also, be able to very effectively
use anomaly detection algorithm.
Now, to fill in this
equation a little bit more,
we are saying that the probability of all
the features of this vector features x,
is the product of p(x) 1 and
p(x2) and so on up through p(xn).
And in order to model
the probability of x1,
say the heat feature in this example
we're going to have two parameters,
new 1 and sigma 1 or sigma squared is 1.
And what that means is we're going to
estimate, the mean of the feature x1 and
also the variance of feature x1 and
that will be new 1 and sigma 1.
To model p(x2) x2 is a totally different
feature measuring the vibrations
of the airplane engine.
We're going to have two
different parameters,
which I'm going to write as mu 2,
sigma 2 squared.
And it turns out this will correspond
to the mean or the average of
the vibration feature and the variance
of the vibration feature and so on.
If you have additional
features mu 3 sigma 3
squared up through mu n and
sigma n squared.
In case you're wondering why
we multiply probabilities,
maybe here's 1 example that
could build intuition.
Suppose for
an aircraft engine there's a 1/10
chance that it is really hot,
unusually hot and
maybe there is a 1 in 20 chance
that it vibrates really hard.
Then, what is the chance that it runs
really hot and vibrates really hard.
We're saying that the chance of that
is 1/10 times 1/20 which is 1/200.
So it's really unlikely to get an engine
that both fronts really hot and
vibrates really hard.
It's the product of these two probabilities
A somewhat more compact way to
write this equation up here,
is to say that this is equal to,
the product from j =1 through n of p(xj).
Would parameters mu j and sigma squared j.
And this symbol here is a lot like
the summation symbol except that
whereas the summation symbol
corresponds to addition, this
symbol here corresponds to multiplying
these terms over here for j =1 through n.
So let's put it all together
to see how you can build in
the nominee detection system.
The first step is to choose
features xi that you
think might be indicative
of anomalous examples.
Having come up with
the features you want to use,
you would then fit the parameters
mu 1 through mu n and
sigma square 1 through sigma squared n,
for the n features in your data set.
As you might guess, the parameter
mu j will be just the average
of xj of the feature j of all
the examples in your training set.
And sigma square j will be
the average of the square
difference between the feature and
the value mu j,
that you just computed.
And by the way,
if you have a vectorized implementation,
you can also compute mu as the average
of the training examples as follows,
we're here, x and mu are both vectors.
And so this would be the vectorized
way of computing mu 1 through mu and
all at the same time.
And by estimating these parameters
on your unlabeled training set,
you've now computed all
the parameters of your model.
Finally, when you are given a new example,
x test or
I'm just going to write
a new example as x here,
what you would do is compute p(x) and
see if it's large or small.
So p(x) as you saw on the last slide
is the product from j = 1 through
n of the probability of
the individual features.
So p(x) j with parameters mu j and
single square j.
And if you substitute in, the formula for
this probability, you end
up with this expression 1 over root 2 pi
sigma j of e to this expression over here.
And so xj are the features,
this is a j feature of your new example,
mu j and sigma j are numbers or parameters
you have computed in the previous step.
And if you compute out this formula,
you get some number for p(x).
And the final step is to see
a p(x) is less than epsilon.
And if it is then you flag
that it is an anomaly.
1 intuition behind what this album
is doing is that it will tend to
flag an example as anomalous if 1 or more
of the features are either very large or
very small relative to what it
has seen in the training set.
So for each of the features x j, you're
fitting a Gaussian distribution like this.
And so if even 1 of the features
of the new example was
way out here, say,
then P f xJ would be very small.
And if just 1 of the terms in this product
is very small, then this overall product,
when you multiply together will tend to be
very small and does p(x) will be small.
And what anomaly detection is
doing into the algorithm is
a systematic way of quantifying whether or
not this new example x
has any features that are unusually
large or unusually small.
Now, let's take a look at what all
this actually means on 1 example,
Here's the data set with features x 1 and
x 2.
And you notice that the features
x 1 take on a much larger range
of values than the features x 2.
If you were to compute the meme of
the Features x 1, you end up with five,
which is why you want is equal to 1.
And it turns out that for
this data said, if you compute sigma 1,
it will be equal to about 2.
And if you were to compute mu to
the average of the features on next
to the average is three and
similarly is variance or
standard deviation is much smaller,
which is why Sigma 2 is equal to 1.
So that corresponds to this
Gaussian distribution for
x 1 and
this Gaussian distribution for x 2.
If you were to actually
multiply p(x) 1 and p(x) 2,
then you end up with this three D
surface plot for p(x) where any point,
the height of this is the product
of p(x) 1 times p(x) 2.
For the corresponding values of x 1 and
x 2.
And this signifies that values where
p(x) is higher or more likely.
So, values near the middle
kind of here are more likely.
Whereas values far out here,
values out here are much less likely.
I have much lower chance.
Now, let me pick to test examples,
the first 1 here,
I'm going to write this x test 1 and
the second 1 down here as x test 2.
And let's see which of these 2 examples
the album will flag as anomalous.
I'm going to pick The Parameter
ε to be equal to 0.02.
And if you were to compute p(x) test 1,
it turns out to be about 0.4 and
this is much bigger than epsilon.
And so the album will say this looks okay,
doesn't look like an anomaly.
Whereas in contrast,
if you were to compute p(x) for
this point down here corresponding
to x 1 equals about eight and
x 2 equals about 0.5.
Kind of down here,
then p(x) test 2 is 0.0021.
So this is much smaller than epsilon.
And so the album will flag
this as a likely anomaly.
So, pretty much as you might hope it
decides that x test 1 looks pretty normal.
Whereas excess to which is much further
away than anything you see in the training
set looks like it could be an anomaly.
So you've seen the process of how to
build an anomaly detection system.
But how do you choose
the parameter epsilon?
And how do you know if your anomaly
detection system is working well in
the next video, let's dive a little
bit more deeply into the process of
developing and evaluating the performance
of an anomaly detection system.