In the earlier courses, courses one and two
of the specialization, you saw a lot of
supervised learning algorithms as taking
training set posing a cost function.
And then using grading descent or
some other algorithms to
optimize that cost function.
It turns out that the key
means algorithm that
you saw in the last video is also
optimizing a specific cost function.
Although the optimization algorithm that
it uses to optimize that is not creating
dissent is actually the algorithm that
you already saw in the last video.
Let's take a look at what all this means.
Let's take a look at what is
the cost function for a means,
to get started as a reminder
this is a notation we've been
using whereas CI is
the index of the cluster.
So CI is some number from one
Su K of the index of the cluster
to which training example XI
is currently assigned and
new K is the location
of cluster centroid k.
Let me introduce one
more piece of notation,
which is when lower case K equals CI.
So mu subscript CI is
the cluster centroid of
the cluster to which example
XI has been assigned.
So for example, if I were to look at some
training example C train example 10 and
I were to ask What's the location
of the constant century to which
the 10th training example
has been assigned?
Well, I would then look up C10.
This will give me a number from one to K.
That tells me was example 10
assigned to the red or the blue or
some other cluster centroid,
and then mu subscript C- 10 is
the location of the cluster centroid
to which extent has been assigned.
So armed with this notation,
let me now write out
the cost function that K means
turns out to be minimizing.
The cost function J,
which is a function of C1 through CM.
These are all the assignments of
points to clusters Androids as
well as new one through mu capsule K.
These are the locations of all
the clusters centroid is defined as
this expression on the right.
It is the average, so
one over M some from Michael's
one to him of the squared distance
between every training example XI
as I goes from one through M it
is a square distance between X I.
And Nu subscript C high.
So this quantity up here, in other words,
the cost function good for
Kenyans is the average squared distance
between every training example XI.
And the location of the cluster centroid
to which the training example exile has
been assigned.
So for this example up here we've
been measuring the distance
between X10 and mu subscript C10.
The cluster centroid to which extent has
been assigned and taking the square of
that distance and that would be one of the
terms over here that we're averaging over.
And it turns out that what the K means
album is doing is trying to find
assignments of points of clusters
centroid as well as find locations of
clusters centroid that
minimizes the squared distance.
Visually, here's what you
saw part way into the run
of K means in the earlier video.
And at this step the cost function.
If you were to computer it would be to
look at everyone at the blue points and
measure these distances and
computer square.
And then also similarly look at
every one of the red points and
compute these distances and
compute the square.
And then the average of the squares
of all of these differences for
the red and the blue points is
the value of the cost function J,
at this particular configuration
of the parameters for kings.
And what they will do on every
step is try to update the cluster
assignments C1 through
C30 in this example.
Or update the positions of
the cluster centralism, U1 and U2.
In order to keep on reducing
this cost function J.
By the way,
this cost function J also has a name in
the literature is called
the distortion function.
I don't know that this is a great name.
But if you hear someone talk about the key
news algorithm and the distortion or
the distortion cost function, that's
just what this formula J is computing.
Let's now take a deeper
look at the algorithm and
why the algorithm is trying to
minimize this cost function J.
Or why is trying to minimize
the distortion here on top of copied over
the cost function from the previous slide.
It turns out that the first part of K
means where you assign points to cluster
centroid.
That turns out to be trying
to update C1 through CM.
To try to minimize the cost
function J as much as possible
while holding new one through mu K fix.
And the second step, in contrast
where you move the custom centroid,
it turns out that is trying
to leave C1 through CM fix.
But to update new one through mu K to
try to minimize the cost function or
the distortion as much as possible.
Let's take a look at why this is the case.
During the first step, if you want to
choose the values of C1 through CM or
save a particular value of
Ci to try to minimize this.
Well, what would make Xi minus
mu CI as small as possible?
This is the distance or the square
distance between a training example XI.
And the location of the class is
central to which has been assigned.
So if you want to minimize this
distance or the square distance,
what you should do is assign
XI to the closest sanctuary.
So to take a simplified example,
if you have two clusters centroid say
close to central is one and two and
just a single training example, XI.
If you were to sign it
to cluster central one,
this square distance here would be
this large distance, well squared.
And if you were to sign it too close to
central to then this square distance would
be the square of this
much smaller distance.
So if you want to minimize this term,
you will take X I and
assign it to the closer centroid, which is
exactly what the album is doing up here.
So that's why the step where you sign
points to cluster century is choosing
the values for CI to try to minimize J.
Without changing, we went through
the UK for now, but just choosing
the values of C1 through CM to try to
make these terms as small as possible.
How about the second step of
the K-means algorithm that is to
move to clusters centroids?
It turns out that choosing mu K to be
average and the mean of the points
assigned is the choice of these terms
mu that will minimize this expression.
To take a simplified example,
say you have a cluster with just two
points aside to it shown as follows.
And so with the closest centroid here,
the average of the square
distances would be a distance of
one here squared plus this distance here,
which is 9 squared.
And then you take the average
of these two numbers.
And so that turns out to
be one half of 1 plus 81,
which turns out to be 41.
But if you were to take the average
of these two points, so
1+ 11/2, that's equal to 6.
And if you were to move
the cluster centroid over here to
middle than the average of
these two square distances,
turns out to be a distance of five and
five years.
So you end up with one half of 5 squared
plus 5 squared, which is equal to 25.
And this is a much smaller
average squared distance than 41.
And in fact, you can play around with
the location of this cluster centroid and
maybe convince yourself that
taking this mean location.
This average location in the middle
of these two training examples,
that is really the value that
minimizes the square distance.
So the fact that the K-means algorithm
is optimizing a cost function J
means that it is guaranteed to converge,
that is on every single iteration.
The distortion cost function should go
down or stay the same, but if it ever
fails to go down or stay the same,
in the worst case, if it ever goes up.
That means there's a bug in the code,
it should never go up because
every single step of K means
is setting the value CI and
mu K to try to reduce the cost function.
Also, if the cost function
ever stops going down,
that also gives you one way to
test if K means has converged.
Once there's a single duration
where it stays the same.
That usually means K means has converged
and you should just stop running the album
even further or in some rare cases
you will run K means for a long time.
And the cost function of the distortion
is just going down very, very slowly, and
that's a bit like great inter sent
where maybe running even longer might
help a bit.
But if the rate at which the cost function
is going down has become very, very slow.
You might also just say
this is good enough.
I'm just going to say it's
close enough to convergence and
not spend even more compute cycles
running the album for even longer.
So these are some of the ways that
computing the cost function is helpful
helps you figure out if
the album has converged.
It turns out that there's
one other very useful way
to take advantage of the cost function,
which is to use multiple different random
initialization of the cluster centroid.
It turns out if you do this, you can often
find much better clusters using K means,
let's take a look at the next