When building an anomaly
detection algorithm,
I found that choosing a good choice of
features turns out to be really important.
In supervised learning, if you don't
have the features quite right, or
if you have a few extra features that
are not relevant to the problem,
that often turns out to be okay.
Because the algorithm has to supervised
signal that is enough labels why for
the algorithm to figure out what features
ignore, or how to re scale feature and
to take the best advantage of
the features you do give it.
But for anomaly detection which runs,
or learns just from unlabeled data,
is harder for the anomaly to figure
out what features to ignore.
So I found that carefully choosing
the features, is even more important for
anomaly detection, than for
supervised learning approaches.
Let's take a look at this video as
some practical tips, for how to tune
the features for anomaly detection, to try
to get you the best possible performance.
One step that can help your
anomaly detection algorithm,
is to try to make sure the features
you give it are more or less Gaussian.
And if your features are not Gaussian,
sometimes you can change it to make
it a little bit more Gaussian.
Let me show you what I mean.
If you have a feature X,
I will often plot to hissed
a gram of the feature which you can
do using the python command PLT.
Though you see this in
the practice lab as well,
in order to look at
the history graham of the data.
This distribution here
looks pretty Gaussian.
So this would be a good candidate feature.
If you think this is a feature that
hopes distinguish between anomalies and
normal examples.
But quite often when you plot
a hissed a gram of your features,
you may find that the feature
has a distribution like this.
This does not at all look like
that symmetric bell shaped curve.
When that is the case, I would consider
if you can take this feature X,
and transform it in order
to make a more Gaussian.
For example, maybe if you were
to compute the log of X and
plot a hissed a gram of log of X,
look like this, and
this looks much more Gaussian.
And so if this feature was feature X one,
then instead of using the original
feature X one which looks like this on
the left, you might instead replace
that feature with log of X one,
to get this distribution over here.
Because when X one is made more Gaussian.
When anomaly detection models
P of X one using a Gaussian
distribution like that, is more
likely to be a good fit to the data.
Other than the log function,
other things you might do is, given
a different feature X two, you may replace
it with X two, log of X two plus one.
This would be a different
way of transforming X two.
And more generally, log of X two plus C,
would be one example of
a formula you can use, to change X
to try to make it more Gaussian.
Or for a different feature,
you might try taking the square root or
really the square would have
executed this X lead to the power of
one half,and you may change
that exponentially term.
So for a different feature X four,
you might use X four to the power
of one third, for example.
So when I'm building
an anomaly detection system,
I'll sometimes take a look at my features,
and if I see any highly non Gaussian
by plotting hissed a gram, I might
choose transformations like these or
others, In order to try
to make it more Gaussian.
It turns out a larger value of C, will end
up transforming this distribution less.
But in practice I just try
a bunch of different values of C,
and then try to take a look to pick one
that looks better in terms of making
the distribution more Gaussian.
Now, let me illustrate how I actually
do this and that you put a notebook.
So this is what the process of
exploring different transformations in
the features might look like.
When you have a feature X, you can
plot a hissed a gram of it as follows.
It actually looks like there's
a pretty cause hissed a gram.
Let me increase the number of
bins in my history gram to 50.
So bins equals 50 there.
That's what hissed a gram bins.
And by the way, if you want to change
the color, you can also do so as follows.
And if you want to try
a different transformation,
you can try for
example to plot X square root of X.
So X to the power of 0.5 with
again 50 hissed a gram bins,
in which case it might look like this.
And this actually looks
somewhat more Gaussian.
But not perfectly, and
let's try a different parameter.
So let me try to the power of 4.25.
Maybe I just a little bit too far.
It's the old 0.4 that
looks pretty Gaussian.
So one thing you could do is replace
X with excellent power of 0.4.
And so you would set X to be
equal to X to the power of 0.4.
And just use the value of X in
your training process instead.
Or let me show you another transformation.
Here, I'm going to try
taking the log of X.
So log of X spotted with 50 bins,
I'm going to use the numpy
log function as follows.
And it turns out you get an error,
because it turns out that excellent.
This example has some values
that are equal to zero, and
we'll log of zero is negative
infinity is not defined.
So common trick is to add just
a very tiny number there.
So exports 0.001, becomes non negative.
And so you get the hissed
gram that looks like this.
But if you want the distribution to
look more Gaussian, you can also
play around with this parameter,
to try to see if there's a value of that.
Cause user data to look more symmetric and
maybe look more Gaussian as follows.
And just as I'm doing right now
in real time, you can see that,
you can very quickly change these
parameters and plot the hissed gram.
In order to try to take a look and
try to get something a bit more Gaussian,
than was the original data next that
you saw in this hissed gram up above.
If you read the machine learning
literature, there are some ways to
automatically measure how close
these distributions are to Gaussian.
But I found it in practice,
it doesn't make a big difference,
if you just try a few values and
pick something that looks right to you,
that will work well for
all practical purposes.
So, by trying things out
in Jupiter notebook,
you can try to pick a transformation
that makes your data more Gaussian.
And just as a reminder,
whatever transformation you apply to
the training set, please remember to apply
the same transformation to your cross
validation and test set data as well.
Other than making sure that your
data is approximately Gaussian,
after you've trained your
anomaly detection algorithm,
if it doesn't work that well
on your trust validation set,
you can also carry out an error
analysis process for anomaly detection.
In other words, you can try to look at
where the algorithm is not yet doing well
whereas making errors, and then use that
to try to come up with improvements.
So as a reminder, what we want is for
P of X to be large.
For normal examples X, so
greater than equal to epsilon, and
p f X to be small or less than epsilon,
for the anomalous examples X.
When you've learned the model P
of X from your unlabeled data,
the most common problem that you may
run into is that, P of X is comparable
in value say is, large for
both normal and for anomalous examples.
As a concrete example,
if this is your data set,
you might fit that galaxy into it.
And if you have an example in your
cross validation set or test set,
that is over here, that is anomalous,
then this has a pretty high probability.
And in fact, it looks quite similar to
the other examples in your training set.
And so, even though this is an anomaly,
P of X is actually pretty large.
And so the algorithm will fail to flag
this particular example as an anomaly.
In that case, what I would normally do is,
try to look at that example and
try to figure out what is it that
made me think is an anomaly,
even if this feature X one took on values
similar to other training examples.
And if I can identify some
new feature say X two,
that helps distinguish this
example from the normal examples.
Then adding that feature, can help
improve the performance of the algorithm.
Here's a picture showing what I mean.
If I can come up with a new feature X two,
say, I'm trying to detect
fraudulent behavior, and if X one is
the number of transactions they make,
maybe this user looks like they're making
some of the transactions as everyone else.
But if I discover that this user has
some insanely fast typing speed,
and if I were to add a new feature X two,
that is the typing speed of this user.
And if it turns out that when I plot this
data using the old feature X one and
this new feature X two,
causes X two to stand out over here.
Then it becomes much easier for
the anomaly detection algorithm to
recognize an X two is an anomalous user.
Because when you have this new feature
X two, the learning anomaly may fit
a Gaussian distribution that assigns high
probability to points in this region,
a bit lower in this region, and
a bit lower in this region.
And so this example, because of
the very anomalous value of X two,
becomes easier to detect as an anomaly.
So just to summarize the development
process will often go through is,
to train the model and
then to see what anomalies in the cross
validation set the algorithm
is failing to detect.
And then to look at those examples
to see if that can inspire
the creation of new features that
would allow the algorithm to spot.
That example takes on unusually large or
unusually small values on the new
features, so that you can now successfully
flag those examples as anomalies.
Just as one more example, let's say you're
building an anomaly detection system to
monitor computers in the data center.
To try to figure out if a computer
may be behaving strangely and
deserves a closer look,
maybe because of a hardware failure, or
because it's been hacked into or
something.
So what you'd like to do is, to choose
features that might take on unusually
large or
small values in the event of an anomaly.
You might start off with features like X
one is the memory use, X two is the number
of disk accesses per second, then the CPU
load, and the volume of network traffic.
And if you train the algorithm,
you may find that it detects
some anomalies but
fails to detect some other anomalies.
In that case, it's not unusual to create
new features by combining old features.
So, for example, if you find that
there's a computer that is behaving
very strangely, but neither is CPU load
nor network traffic is that unusual.
But what is unusual is,
it has a really high CPU load,
while having a very low
network traffic volume.
If you're running the data center that
streams videos, then computers may have
high CPU load and high network traffic,
or low CPU load and no network traffic.
But what's unusual about this one
machine is a very high CPU load,
despite a very low traffic volume.
In that case,
you might create a new feature X five,
which is a ratio of CPU
load to network traffic.
And this new feature with hope,
the anomaly detection algorithm
flagged future examples like the specific
machine you may be seeing as anomalous.
Or you can also consider other features
like the square of the CPU load,
divided by the network traffic volume.
And you can play around with
different choices of these features.
In order to try to get it so that P of X
is still large for the normal examples but
it becomes small in the anomalies
in your cross validation set.
So that's it.
Thanks for
sticking with me to the end of this week.
I hope you enjoy hearing about
both clustering algorithms and
anomaly detection algorithms.
And that you also enjoy playing
with these ideas
in the practice labs.
Next week, we'll go on to talk
about recommender systems.
When you go to a website and
recommends products, or movies, or
other things to you.
How does that algorithm actually work?
This is one of the most commercially
important algorithms in machine learning
that gets talked about surprisingly little
but next week we'll take a look at how
these algorithms work so that you understand
the next time you go to the website and
then recommend something to you.
Maybe how that came about.
As was you'll be able to build other
algorithms like that for yourself as well.
So have fun with the labs and