In the last video, you saw
an illustration of the
k-means algorithm running.
Now let's write out the
K-means algorithm in
detail so that you'd
be able to implement
it for yourself.
Here's the K-means algorithm.
The first step is to
randomly initialize
K cluster centroids,
Mu 1 Mu 2,
through Mu k. In the
example that we had,
this corresponded
to when we randomly
chose a location for
the red cross and for
the blue cross corresponding
to the two cluster centroids.
In our example, K
was equal to two.
If the red cross was cluster
centroid one and the blue cross
was cluster centroid two.
These are just two indices
to denote the first and
the second cluster.
Then the red cross would
be the location of Mu 1
and the blue cross would
be the location of Mu 2.
Just to be clear, Mu 1 and Mu 2
are vectors which have
the same dimension as
your training examples,
X1 through say X30,
in our example.
All of these are lists of
two numbers or they're
two-dimensional
vectors or whatever
dimension the training data had.
We had n equals two
features for each of
the training examples
then Mu 1 and Mu
2 will also be
two-dimensional vectors,
meaning vectors with
two numbers in them.
Having randomly initialized
the K cluster centroids,
K-means will then
repeatedly carry
out the two steps that you
saw in the last video.
The first step is to
assign points to clusters,
centroids, meaning color,
each of the points,
either red or blue,
corresponding to assigning
them to cluster centroids one
or two when K is equal to two.
Rinse it out enough.
That means that we're going to,
for I equals one through m
for all m training examples,
we're going to set c^i to
be equal to the index,
which can be anything
from one to K of
the cluster centroid closest
to the training example x^i.
Mathematically you
can write this out
as computing the distance
between x^i and Mu k. In math,
the distance between two points
is often written like this.
It is also called the L2 norm.
What you want to
find is the value of
k that minimizes this,
because that corresponds to
the cluster centroid Mu k
that is closest to the
training example x^i.
Then the value of k
that minimizes this
is what gets set to c^i.
When you implement
this algorithm,
you find that it's
actually a little
bit more convenient to minimize
the squared distance because
the cluster centroid with
the smallest square
distance should be the
same as the cluster centroid
with the smallest distance.
When you look at
this week's optional
labs and practice labs,
you see how to implement
this in code for yourself.
As a concrete example,
this point up here is closer to
the red or two
cluster centroids 1.
If this was training
example x^1,
we will set c^1
to be equal to 1.
Whereas this point over here,
if this was the 12th
training example,
this is closer to
the second cluster
centroids the blue one.
We will set this,
the corresponding
cluster assignment
variable to two because it's
closer to cluster centroid 2.
That's the first step of
the K-means algorithm,
assign points to
cluster centroids.
The second step is to move
the cluster centroids.
What that means is for lowercase
k equals 1 to capital K,
the number of clusters.
We're going to set
the cluster centroid
location to be updated to
be the average or the
mean of the points
assigned to that
cluster k. Concretely,
what that means is,
we'll look at all
of these red points, say,
and look at their position on
the horizontal axis and look at
the value of the
first feature x^1,
and average that out.
Compute the average value on
the vertical axis as well.
After computing
those two averages,
you find that the mean is here,
which is why Mu 1,
that is the location that
the red cluster centroid
gets updated as follows.
Similarly, we will
look at all of
the points that were
colored blue, that is,
with c^i equals 2 and
computes the average of the
value on the horizontal axis,
the average of their feature x1.
Compute the average
of the feature x2.
Those two averages give you
the new location of the
blue cluster centroid,
which therefore moves over here.
Just to write those out in math.
If the first cluster
has assigned to
it training examples 1,5,6,10.
Just as an example.
Then what that means is you will
compute the average this way.
Notice that x^1, x^5, x^6,
and x^10 are training examples.
Four training examples,
so we divide by 4 and this gives
you the new location of Mu1,
the new cluster
centroid for cluster 1.
To be clear, each
of these x values
are vectors with two
numbers in them,
or n numbers in them if
you have n features,
and so Mu will also have
two numbers in it or
n numbers in it if you have
n features instead of two.
Now, there is one corner
case of this algorithm,
which is what happens if
a cluster has zero training
examples assigned to it.
In that case, the
second step, Mu k,
would be trying to compute
the average of zero points.
That's not well-defined.
If that ever happens,
the most common
thing to do is to
just eliminate that cluster.
You end up with K
minus 1 clusters.
Or if you really, really need
K clusters an alternative
would be to just
randomly reinitialize
that cluster centroid
and hope that it
gets assigned at
least some points
next time round.
But it's actually more
common when running
K-means to just
eliminate a cluster if no
points are assigned to it.
Even though I've
mainly been describing
K-means for clusters
that are well separated.
Clusters that may
look like this.
Where if you asked her
to find three clusters,
hopefully they will find these
three distinct clusters.
It turns out that K-means is
also frequently applied to
data sets where the clusters
are not that well separated.
For example, if you are
a designer and manufacturer
of cool t-shirts,
and you want to decide,
how do I size my small,
medium, and large t-shirts.
How small should a small be,
how large should a large be,
and what should a medium-size
t-shirt really be?
One thing you might
do is collect
data of people likely to
buy your t-shirts based on
their heights and weights.
You find that the height and
weight of people tend to
vary continuously
on the spectrum
without some very
clear clusters.
Nonetheless, if you
were to run K-means
with say, three
clusters centroids,
you might find
that K-means would
group these points
into one cluster,
these points into
a second cluster,
and these points into
a third cluster.
If you're trying to decide
exactly how to size your small,
medium, and large t-shirts,
you might then choose
the dimensions of
your small t-shirt
to try to make it
fit these individuals well.
The medium-size t-shirt to
try to fit these
individuals well,
and the large t-shirt to try to
fit these individuals well with
potentially the
cluster centroids
giving you a sense of what is
the most representative
height and weight that
you will want your three
t-shirt sizes to fit.
This is an example of K-means
working just fine and giving
a useful results even
if the data does
not lie in well-separated
groups or clusters.
That was the K-means
clustering algorithm.
Assign cluster centroids
randomly and then repeatedly
assign points to
cluster centroids
and move the cluster centroids.
But what this algorithm
really doing and do we think
this algorithm will
converge or they just
keep on running forever
and never converge.
To gain deeper intuition about
the K-means algorithm and
also see why we might hope
this algorithm does converge,
let's go on to the next
video where you see that
K-means is actually trying to
optimize a specific
cost function.
Let's take a look at