Let's look at our second
unsupervised learning algorithm.
Anomaly detection algorithms look at
an unlabeled dataset of normal events and
thereby learns to detect or
to raise a red flag for
if there is an unusual or
an anomalous event.
Let's look at an example.
Some of my friends were working on
using anomaly detection to detect
possible problems with aircraft
engines that were being manufactured.
When a company makes an aircraft engine,
you really want that aircraft
engine to be reliable and
function well because an aircraft engine
failure has very negative consequences.
So some of my friends were using
anomaly detection to check if
an aircraft engine after it was
manufactured seemed anomalous or
if there seemed to be
anything wrong with it.
Here's the idea, after an aircraft
engine rolls off the assembly line,
you can compute a number of different
features of the aircraft engine.
So, say feature x1 measures
the heat generated by the engine.
Feature x2 measures the vibration
intensity and so on and so forth for
additional features as well.
But to simplify the slide a bit,
I'm going to use just two features x1 and
x2 corresponding to the heat and
the vibrations of the engine.
Now, it turns out that aircraft
engine manufacturers don't make
that many bad engines.
And so the easier type of data
to collect would be if you have
manufactured m aircraft engines
to collect the features x1 and
x2 about how these m engines behave and
probably most of them are just
fine that normal engines rather than
ones with a defect or flow in them.
And the anomaly detection problem is,
after the learning algorithm
has seen these m examples of how
aircraft engines typically behave
in terms of how much heat is generated and
how much they vibrate.
If a brand new aircraft engine were
to roll off the assembly line and
it had a new feature vector given
by Xtest, we'd like to know
does this engine look similar to ones
that have been manufactured before?
So is this probably okay?
Or is there something really weird
about this engine which might
cause this performance to be suspect,
meaning that maybe we should
inspect it even more carefully
before we let it get shipped out and
be installed in an airplane and then
hopefully nothing will go wrong with it.
Here's how an anomaly
detection algorithm works.
Let me plot the examples x1 through
xm over here via these crosses
where each cross each data point in
this plot corresponds to a specific
engine with a specific amount of heat and
specific amount of vibrations.
If this new aircraft engine Xtest
rolls off the assembly lin,e and
if you were to plot these values of x1 and
x2 and
if it were here, you say, okay,
that looks probably okay.
Looks very similar to
other aircraft engines.
Maybe I don't need to
worry about this one.
But if this new aircraft
engine has a heat and
vibration signature that is
say all the way down here,
then this data point down here looks very
different than once we saw up on top.
And so we will probably say,
boy, this looks like an anomaly.
This doesn't look like the examples I've
seen before, we better inspect this more
carefully before we let this engine
get installed on an airplane.
How can you have an algorithm
address this problem?
The most common way to carry
out anomaly detection is
through a technique called
density estimation.
And what that means is, when you're given
your training sets of these m examples,
the first thing you do is build
a model for the probability of x.
In other words, the learning
algorithm will try to figure out what
are the values of the features x1 and
x2 that have high probability and
what are the values that are less
likely or have a lower chance or
lower probability of being
seen in the data set.
In this example that we have here,
I think it is quite likely to see examples
in that little ellipse in the middle, so
that region in the middle would have high
probability maybe things in this ellipse
have a little bit lower probability.
Things in this ellipse of this oval
have even lower probability and
things outside have
even lower probability.
The details of how you decide from
the training set what regions are higher
versus lower probability is something
we'll see in the next few videos.
And having modeled or
having learned to model for
p of x When you are given
the new test example Xtest.
What you will do is then compute
the probability of Xtest.
And if it is small or more precisely,
if it is less than some small
number that I'm going to call epsilon,
this is a greek alphabet epsilon.
So what you should think of as
a small number, which means that p of
x is very small or in other words,
the specific value of x that you saw for
a certain user was very unlikely, relative
to other users that you have seen.
But the p of Xtest is less than some small
threshold or some small number epsilon,
we will raise a flag to say
that this could be an anomaly.
So for example,
if Xtest was all the way down here,
the probability of an example landing all
the way out here is actually quite low.
And so hopefully p of Xtest for this value
of Xtest will be less than epsilon and
so we would flag this as an anomaly.
Whereas in contrast,
if p of Xtest is not less than epsilon,
if p of Xtest is greater
than equal to epsilon,
then we will say that it looks okay,
this doesn't look like an anomaly.
And that response to if you had an example
in here say where our model p of x will
say that examples near the middle here,
they're actually quite high probability.
There's a very high chance that the new
airplane engine will have features
close to these inner ellipses.
And so p of Xtest will be large for
those examples and
we'll say it's okay and
it's not an anomaly.
Anomaly detection is used
today in many applications.
It is frequently used in
fraud detection where for
example if you are running a website
with many different features.
If you compute xi to be the features
of user i's activities.
And examples of features might include,
how often does this user login and
how many web pages do they visit?
How many transactions are they making or
how many posts on
the discussion forum are they making
to what is their typing speed?
How many characters per second
do they seem able to type.
With data like this you can then
model p of x from data to model
what is the typical
behavior of a given user.
In the common workflow of fraud detection,
you wouldn't automatically turn off an
account just because it seemed anomalous.
But instead you may ask the security team
to take a closer look or put in some
additional security checks such as ask the
user to verify their identity with a cell
phone number or ask them to pass a capture
to prove that they're human and so on.
But algorithms like this are routinely
used today to try to find unusual or
maybe slightly suspicious activity.
So you can more carefully screen those
accounts to make sure there isn't
something fraudulent.
And this type of fraud detection is
used both to find fake accounts and
this type of algorithm is also used
frequently to try to identify financial
fraud such as if there's a very
unusual pattern of purchases.
Then that may be something well
worth a security team taking a more
careful look at.
Anomaly detection is also
frequently used in manufacturing.
You saw an example on the previous slide
with aircraft engine manufacturing.
But many manufacturers in multiple
continents in many, many factories were
routinely use anomaly detection to see
if whatever they just manufactured.
Anything from an airplane engine to
a printed circuit board to a smartphone
to a motor, to many,
many things to see if you've just
manufactured the unit that
somehow behaves strangely.
Because that may indicate that there's
something wrong with your airplane
engine or printed circuit boards or
what have you that might cause you to want
to take a more careful look before
you ship that object to the customer.
Is also used to monitor
computers in clusters and
in data centers where if X I are the
features of a certain machine I such as if
the features captured the memory users,
the number of disk accesses per second.
CPU load features can also be racial,
such as the ratio of CPU
load to network traffic.
Then if ever a specific computer behaves
very differently than other computers,
it might be worth taking a look at that
computer to see if something is wrong
with it.
Such as if it has had a hot test
failure or network hack failure or
something's wrong with it or
if maybe it has been hacked into.
Anomaly detection is one of those
algorithms that is very widely
used even though you don't seem to
hear people talk about it that much.
I remember the first time I worked on
the commercial application of anomaly
detection was when I was helping a telco
company put in place anomaly detection
to see when any one of the cell towers
was behaving in an unusual way.
Because that probably meant there was
something wrong with the cell tower and so
they want to get a technician to take so
hopefully that hope more people
get good cell phone coverage.
And I've also used anomaly detection to
find fraudulent financial transactions And
these days I often use it to help
manufacturing companies find anomalous
parts that they may have manufactured but
should inspect more often.
So it is a very useful tool
to have in your tool chest.
And in the next few videos we'll
talk about how you can build and
get these algorithms to work for yourself.
In order to get anonymous
detection albums to work,
we'll need to use a Gaussian
distribution to model the data p of x.
So, let's go on to the next video to