Welcome to this third
and final course of
this specialization on
unsupervised learning,
recommender systems, and
reinforcement learning.
Whereas in the first two courses,
we spent a lot of time
on supervised learning,
in this third and final course,
we'll talk about a new
set of techniques that
goes beyond supervised
learning and we'll
give you an extra set of
powerful tools that I
hope you enjoy adding to
your two sets and
by the time you
finish this course and
finish this specialization,
I think you'll be
well on your way to
being an expert in
machine learning.
Let's take a look.
This week we'll
start with supervised learning.
In particular, you'll learn
about clustering algorithms,
which is a way of grouping
data into clusters,
as well as anomaly detection.
Both of these are
techniques used
by many companies today,
in important commercial
applications.
By the end of this week,
you know how these
algorithms work
and be able to get them to
work with yourself as well.
In the second week,
you will learn about
recommender systems.
When you go to
a online shopping websites or
a video streaming website,
how does it recommend
products or movies to you?
Recommender systems is one of
the most commercially important
machine learning technologies,
is moving many
billions of dollars
worth of value or products
or other things around,
is one of the technologies
that receives
surprisingly little
attention from academia,
despite how important it is.
But in the second week,
I hope you learn
how these systems
work and be able to
implement one for yourself.
If you are curious about how
online ads systems work,
the description of
recommender systems
will also give you
a sense for how
those large online
ad tech companies
decide what ads to show you.
In the third and final
week of this course,
you'll learn about
reinforcement learning.
You may have read in the news
about reinforcement
learning being
great at playing a variety of
video games, even
outperforming humans.
I've also used reinforcement
learning many times myself
to control a variety
of different robots.
Even though reinforcement
learning is
a new and emerging
technology, that is,
the number of commercial
applications of
reinforcement learning
is not nearly as
large as the other techniques
covered in this week or in the
previous two courses of this
specialization, is a technology
that is exciting and is
opening up a new frontier to
what you can get learning
algorithms to do.
In the final week,
you implement reinforcement
learning yourself and
use it to land a
simulated moon lander.
When you see that working
for yourself with your own code,
later in this course,
I think you'll be
impressed by what
you can get reinforcement
learning to do.
I'm really excited
to be here with you
to talk about
unsupervised learning,
recommender systems, and
reinforcement learning.
Let's go on to the next
video where you learn about
an important unsupervised
learning algorithm