I'd like to share with you
some practical tips for
developing an anomaly
detection system.
One of the key ideas
will be that if you
can have a way to
evaluate a system,
even as it's being developed,
you'll be able to make
decisions and change
the system and improve
it much more quickly.
Let's take a look
at what that means.
When you are developing
a learning algorithm,
say choosing different
features or trying
different values of the
parameters like epsilon,
making decisions about
whether or not to change
a feature in a certain way or to
increase or decrease epsilon
or other parameters,
making those decisions is
much easier if you have
a way of evaluating the
learning algorithm.
This is sometimes called
real number evaluation,
meaning that if you can
quickly change the
algorithm in some way,
such as change a
feature or change
a parameter and have a way of
computing a number that tells
you if the algorithm
got better or worse,
then it makes it much
easier to decide
whether or not to stick
with that change
to the algorithm.
This is how it's often
done in anomaly detection.
Which is, even
though we've mainly
been talking about
unlabeled data,
I'm going to change
that assumption a bit
and assume that we have
some labeled data,
including just a small number
usually of previously
observed anomalies.
Maybe after making airplane
engines for a few years,
you've just seen a
few airplane engines
that were anomalous,
and for examples that
you know are anomalous,
I'm going to associate a label y
equals 1 to indicate
this anomalous,
and for examples that
we think are normal,
I'm going to associate
the label y equals 0.
The training set that
the anomaly detection
algorithm will learn from is
still this unlabeled training
set of x1 through xm,
and I'm going to think
of all of these examples
as ones that we'll just
assume are normal
and not anomalous,
so y is equal to 0.
In practice, you have
a few anomalous examples
where to slip into
this training set,
your algorithm will
still usually do okay.
To evaluate your algorithm,
come up with a way for you
to have a real
number evaluation,
it turns out to be very useful
if you have a small number
of anomalous examples so
that you can create a
cross validation set,
which I'm going
to denote x_cv^1,
y_cv^1 through
x_cv^mcv, y_cv^mcv.
This is similar
notation as you had
seen in the second course
of this specialization.
As similarly, have a test set
of some number of examples where
both the cross validation
and test sets hopefully
includes a few
anomalous examples.
In other words, the cross
validation and test sets will
have a few examples
of y equals 1,
but also a lot of examples
where y is equal to 0.
Again, in practice,
anomaly detection algorithm
will work okay if
there are some examples that
are actually anomalous,
but there were accidentally
labeled with y equals 0.
Let's illustrate this with
the aircraft engine example.
Let's say you have
been manufacturing
aircraft engines for
years and so you've
collected data from 10,000
good or normal engines,
but over the years you
had also collected data
from 20 flawed or
anomalous engines.
Usually the number of
anomalous engines,
that is y equals 1,
will be much smaller.
It will not be a typical to
apply this type of algorithm
with anywhere from,
say, 2-50 known anomalies.
We're going to take
this dataset and
break it up into a training set,
a cross validation set,
and the test set.
Here's one example.
I'm going to put 6,000
good engines into
the training set.
Again, if there are couple
of anomalous engines
that got slipped into this
set is actually okay,
I wouldn't worry too
much about that.
Then let's put 2,000
good engines and
10 of the known anomalies into
the cross-validation set,
and a separate 2,000 good and 10
anomalous engines
into the test set.
What you can do then is
train the algorithm
on the training set,
fit the Gaussian distributions
to these 6,000 examples
and then on the
cross-validation set,
you can see how many of
the anomalous engines
it correctly flags.
For example, you could use
the cross validation set
to tune the parameter
epsilon and set it
higher or lower depending
on whether the algorithm
seems to be reliably
detecting these 10 anomalies
without taking too
many of these 2,000 good
engines and flagging
them as anomalies.
After you have tuned the
parameter epsilon and
maybe also added
or subtracted or
tuned to features X_J you can
then take the algorithm and
evaluate it on your
test set to see
how many of these 10
anomalous engines it finds,
as well as how many
mistakes it makes by
flagging the good engines
as anomalous ones.
Notice that this is still
primarily an unsupervised
learning algorithm
because the training sets
really has no labels or
they all have labels
that we're assuming to
be y equals 0 and so we
learned from the
training set by fitting
the Gaussian distributions as
you saw in the previous video.
But it turns out
if you're building
a practical anomaly
detection system,
having a small number of
anomalies to use to evaluate
the algorithm that your
cross validation and test
sets is very helpful for
tuning the algorithm.
Because the number of flawed
engines is so small there's
one other alternative
that I often see
people use for
anomaly detection,
which is to not use a test set,
like to have just a training set
and a cross-validation set.
In this example, you will set
train on 6,000 good engines,
but take the remainder
of the data,
the 4,000 remaining good
engines as well as
all the anomalies,
and put them in the
cross validation set.
You would then tune
the parameters Epsilon
and add or subtract
fictious x_j to try to
get it to do as well as possible
as evaluated on the
cross validation set.
If you have very
few flawed engines,
so if you had only
two flawed engines,
then this really makes sense to
put all of that in the
cross validation set.
You just don't have
enough data to create
a totally separate test set
that is distinct from your
cross-validation set.
The downside of this alternative
here is that after you've
tuned your algorithm,
you don't have a fair
way to tell how well
this will actually do on
future examples because you
don't have the test set.
But when your dataset is small,
especially when the number
of anomalies you have,
your dataset is small,
this might be the best
alternative you have.
I see this done quite
often as well when
you just don't have enough data
to create a separate test set.
If this is the case,
just be aware that there's
a higher risk that you will have
over-fit some of your
decisions around Epsilon
and choice of features
and so on to the
cross-validation set
and so its performance on
real data in the future may not
be as good as you
were expecting.
Now, let's take
a closer look at how
to actually evaluate
the algorithm on your
cross-validation sets or
on the test set.
Here's what you'd do.
You would first fit the model
p of x on the training set.
This was a 6,000 examples
of goods engines.
Then on any cross validation
or test example x,
you would compute p of x and
you will predict y equals 1.
That is anomalous if p of x is
less than Epsilon and
you predict y is 0,
if p of x is greater than
or equal to Epsilon.
Based on this, you can now
look at how accurately
this algorithm's predictions on
the cross validation or test
set matches the labels,
y you have in the cross
validation or the test sets.
In the third week of
the second course,
we had had a couple of optional
videos on how to handle
highly skewed data distributions
where the number of
positive examples,
y equals 1, can be
much smaller than
the number of negative
examples where y equals 0.
This is the case as well for
many anomaly detection in
the applications where
the number of anomalies in
your cross-validation
set is much smaller.
In our previous example,
we had maybe 10 positive
examples and 2,000
negative examples because we had
10 anomalies and 2,000
normal examples.
If you saw those
optional videos,
you may recall
that we saw it can
be useful to compute things
like the true positive,
false positive, false negative,
and true negative [inaudible].
Also compute precision recall or
F_1 score and that these
are alternative metrics and
classification accuracy
that could work
better when your data
distribution is very skewed.
If you saw that video,
you might consider
applying those types of
evaluation metrics as
well to tell how well
your learning algorithm
is doing at finding
that small handful
of anomalies or
positive examples amidst
this much larger set
of negative examples of
normal plane engines.
If you didn't watch that video,
don't worry about it. It's okay.
The intuition I hope you get
is to use the cross-validation
set to just look at
how many anomalies
is finding and also
how many normal engines is
incorrectly flagging
as an anomaly.
Then to just use that to try to
choose a good choice for
the parameter Epsilon.
You find that the
practical process
of building an anomaly
detection system is much
easier if you actually have
just a small number of
labeled examples of
known anomalies.
Now, this does
raise the question,
if you have a few
labeled examples,
since you'll still be using
an unsupervised
learning algorithm,
why not take those
labeled examples
and use a supervised
learning algorithm instead?
In the next video,
let's take a look
at a comparison between
anomaly detection and
supervised learning
and when you might prefer
one over the other.