The k-means algorithm requires
as one of its inputs, k,
the number of clusters
you want it to find,
but how do you decide how
many clusters to used.
Do you want two clusters
or three clusters of
five clusters or 10
clusters? Let's take a look.
For a lot of
clustering problems,
the right value of K
is truly ambiguous.
If I were to show
different people the
same data set and ask,
how many clusters do you see?
There will definitely be
people that will say,
it looks like there are
two distinct clusters
and they will be right.
There would also be
others that will see
actually four distinct clusters.
They would also be right.
Because clustering is
unsupervised learning
algorithm you're not given
the quote right
answers in the form
of specific labels
to try to replicate.
There are lots of applications
where the data itself
does not give a clear indicator
for how many clusters
there are in it.
I think it truly is ambiguous if
this data has two or four,
or maybe three clusters.
If you take say, the red one
here and the two
blue ones here say.
If you look at the academic
literature on K-means,
there are a few techniques
to try to automatically
choose the number of
clusters to use for a
certain application.
I'll briefly mention one here
that you may see
others refer to,
although I had to say,
I personally do not use
this method myself.
But one way to try to
choose the value of K
is called the elbow method and
what that does is you would run
K-means with a
variety of values of
K and plot the cost function or
the distortion function J
as a function of the
number of clusters.
What you find is
that when you have
very few clusters,
say one cluster,
the distortion function or
the cost function J will be
high and as you increase
the number of clusters,
it will go down,
maybe as follows.
and if the curve looks like this,
you say, well, it looks
like the cost function
is decreasing
rapidly until we get
to three clusters
but the decrease is
more slowly after that.
Let's choose K equals
3 and this is called
an elbow, by the way,
because think of it as analogous
to that's your hand and
that's your elbow over here.
Plotting the cost function as
a function of K could help,
it could help you
gain some insight.
I personally hardly ever
use the the elbow
method myself to
choose the right
number of clusters
because I think for a
lot of applications,
the right number of
clusters is truly
ambiguous and you
find that a lot of
cost functions look
like this with
just decreases smoothly and it
doesn't have a clear
elbow by wish you
could use to pick the
value of K. By the way,
one technique that does
not work is to choose
K so as to minimize
the cost function
J because doing so
would cause you to almost
always just choose
the largest possible
value of K because having
more clusters will pretty much
always reduce the
cost function J.
Choosing K to minimize
the cost function J is
not a good technique.
How do you choose the
value of K and practice?
Often you're running K-means
in order to get clusters
to use for some later or
some downstream purpose.
That is, you're going to
take the clusters and do
something with those clusters.
What I usually do and
what I recommend you
do is to evaluate K-means
based on how well it performs
for that later
downstream purpose.
Let me illustrate to the
example of t-shirt sizing.
One thing you could
do is run K-means
on this data set to
find the clusters,
in which case you
may find clusters
like that and this would be
how you size your small,
medium, and large t-shirts,
but how many t-shirt
sizes should there be?
Well, it's ambiguous.
If you were to also run
K-means with five clusters,
you might get clusters
that look like this.
This will let shoe size
t-shirts according
to extra small,
small, medium, large,
and extra large.
Both of these are
completely valid
and completely fine groupings
of the data into clusters,
but whether you want to use
three clusters or
five clusters can
now be decided
based on what makes
sense for your t-shirt business.
Does a trade-off between how
well the t-shirts will fit,
depending on whether you have
three sizes or five sizes,
but there will be extra costs
as well associated with
manufacturing and
shipping five types of
t-shirts instead of three
different types of t-shirts.
What I would do in
this case is to run
K-means with K equals
3 and K equals 5
and then look at these
two solutions to
see based on the trade-off
between fits of t-shirts
with more sizes,
results in better fit versus
the extra cost of making
more t-shirts where making
fewer t-shirts is simpler
and less expensive to
try to decide what makes sense
for the t-shirt business.
When you get to the
programming exercise,
you also see there
an application
of K-means to image compression.
This is actually one of the
most fun visual examples
of K-means and there
you see that there'll
be a trade-off
between the quality of
the compressed image,
that is, how good
the image looks
versus how much you can
compress the image
to save the space.
In that program exercise,
you see that you can use
that trade-off to maybe
manually decide what's
the best value of K
based on how good do
you want the image to
look versus how large
you want the compress
image size to be.
That's it for the K-means
clustering algorithm.
Congrats on learning
your first unsupervised
learning algorithm.
You now know not just how
to do supervised learning,
but also unsupervised learning.
I hope you also have fun
with the practice lab,
is actually one of the
most fun exercises
I know of the K-means.
With that, we're
ready to move on to
our second unsupervised
learning algorithm,
which is a non-linear detection.
How do you look at
the data set and find
unusual or anomalous
things in it.
This turns out to be another,
one of the most commercially
important applications
of unsupervised learning.
I've used this myself many
times in many different
applications.
Let's go on to the next video to