In order to apply
anomaly detection,
we're going to need to use
the Gaussian distribution,
which is also called the
normal distribution.
When you hear me
say either Gaussian
distribution or
normal distribution,
they mean exactly
the same thing.
If you've heard the
bell-shaped distribution,
that also refers
to the same thing.
But if you haven't heard of
the bell-shaped distribution,
that's fine too.
But let's take a look at what is
the Gaussian or the
normal distribution.
Say x is a number,
and if x is a random number,
sometimes called the
random variable,
x can take on random values.
If the probability
of x is given by
a Gaussian or
normal distribution
with mean parameter Mu,
and with variance Sigma squared.
What that means is that
the probability of
x looks like a curve
that goes like this.
The center or the middle of
the curve is given
by the mean Mu,
and the standard deviation or
the width of this curve is
given by that variance
parameter Sigma.
Technically, Sigma is called
the standard deviation
and the square of
Sigma or Sigma squared is
called the variance
of the distribution.
This curve here shows what
is p of x or the
probability of x.
If you've heard of the
bell-shaped curve,
this is that bell-shaped
curve because a lot
of classic bells say
in towers were shaped like
this with the bell clapper
hanging down here,
and so the shape
of this curve is
vaguely reminiscent
of the shape of
the large bells that
you will still find in
some old buildings today.
Better looking than
my hand-drawn one.
There's a picture of
the Liberty Bell.
Indeed, the Liberty
Bell's shape on
top is vaguely
bell-shaped curve.
If you're wondering what
does p of x really means?
Here's one way to interpret it.
It means that if you
were to get, say,
100 numbers drawn from this
probability distribution,
and you were to plot
a histogram of these 100 numbers
drawn from this distribution,
you might get a histogram
that looks like this.
It looks vaguely bell-shaped.
What this curve on the
left indicates is not
if you have just 100 examples
or 1,000 or a million
or a billion.
But if you had a practically
infinite number of examples,
and you were to
draw a histogram of
this practically
infinite number of
examples with a very
fine histogram bin.
Then you end up with
essentially this bell-shaped
curve here on the left.
The formula for p of x is
given by this expression;
p of x equals 1 over
square root 2 Pi.
Pi here is that 3.14159
or it's about 22 over 7.
Ratio of a circle's diameter
circumference times
Sigma times e to the
negative x minus Mu,
the mean parameter squared
divided by 2 Sigma squared.
For any given value
of Mu and Sigma,
if you were to plot this
function as a function of x,
you get this type of
bell-shaped curve
that is centered at Mu,
and with the width of
this bell-shaped curve
being determined by
the parameter Sigma.
Now let's look at a few
examples of how changing Mu
and Sigma will affect the
Gaussian distribution.
First, let me set Mu equals
0 and Sigma equals 1.
Here's my plot of the Gaussian
distribution with mean 0,
Mu equals 0,
and standard deviation
Sigma equals 1.
You notice that this
distribution is centered at zero
and that is the standard
deviation Sigma is equal to 1.
Now, let's reduce the standard
deviation Sigma to 0.5.
If you plot the
Gaussian distribution
with Mu equals 0 and
Sigma equals 0.5,
it now it looks like this.
Notice that it's
still centered at
zero because Mu is zero.
But it's become a
much thinner curve
because Sigma is now 1.5.
You might recall that Sigma
is the standard
deviation is 0.5,
whereas Sigma squared is
also called the variance.
That's equal to 0.5
squared or 0.25.
You may have heard
that probabilities
always have to sum up to one,
so that's why the area under
the curve is always
equal to one,
which is why when
the Gaussian distribution
becomes skinnier,
it has to become taller as well.
Let's look at another
value of Mu and Sigma.
Now, I'm going to
increase Sigma to 2,
so the standard deviation
is 2 and the variance is 4.
This now creates a much
wider distribution
because Sigma here
is now much larger,
and because it's now a wider
distribution is become
shorter as well because the area
under the curve is
still equals 1.
Finally, let's try changing
the mean parameter Mu,
and I'll leave Sigma equals 0.5.
In this case, the center of
the distribution Mu moves
over here to the right.
But the width of
the distribution is
the same as the one on
top because the
standard deviation is
0.5 in both of these
cases on the right.
This is how different
choices of Mu and
Sigma affect the
Gaussian distribution.
When you're applying this
to anomaly detection,
here's what you have to do.
You are given a
dataset of m examples,
and here x is just a number.
Here, are plots of the training
sets with 11 examples.
What we have to do is
try to estimate what
a good choice is for
the mean parameter Mu,
as well as for the variance
parameter Sigma squared.
Given a dataset like this,
it would seem that
a Gaussian distribution
maybe looking like
that with a center
here and a standard
deviation like that.
This might be a pretty
good fit to the data.
The way you would compute Mu
and Sigma squared mathematically is
our estimate for Mu will be
just the average of all
the training examples.
It's 1 over m times sum from i
equals 1 through m of
the values of your
training examples.
The value we will use to
estimate Sigma squared
will be the average of
the squared difference
between two examples,
and that Mu that you just
estimated here on the left.
It turns out that if you
implement these two formulas
encodes with this value for
Mu and this value
for Sigma squared,
then you pretty much get
the Gaussian distribution
that I hand drew on top.
This will give you
a choice of Mu and
Sigma for a Gaussian
distribution so
that it looks like
the 11 training
samples might have
been drawn from this
Gaussian distribution.
If you've taken an
advanced statistics class,
you may have heard that
these formulas for Mu
and Sigma squared are
technically called the
maximum likelihood
estimates for Mu and Sigma.
Some statistics
classes will tell
you to use the formula 1
over n minus 1 instead of
1 over m. In practice,
using 1 over m or 1 over n
minus 1 makes very
little difference.
I always use 1 over m,
but just some other
properties of dividing
by m minus 1 that some
statisticians prefer.
But if you don't
understand what they
just said, don't worry about it.
All you need to know is that
if you set Mu according to
this formula and Sigma
squared according
to this formula,
you'd get a pretty
good estimate of
Mu and Sigma and in particular,
you get a Gaussian
distribution that will be
a possible probability
distribution in terms
of what's the
probability distribution
that the training
examples had come from.
You can probably guess
what comes next.
If you were to get an
example over here,
then p of x is pretty high.
Whereas if you were
to get an example,
we are here, then p
of x is pretty low,
which is why we would
consider this example,
okay, not really anomalous,
not a lot like the other ones.
Whereas an example
we are here to be
pretty unusual compared to
the examples we've seen,
and therefore more
anomalous because p of x,
which is the height
of this curve,
is much lower over here
on the left compared
to this point over here,
closer to the middle.
Now, we've done this only
for when x is a number,
as if you had only
a single feature
for your anomaly
detection problem.
For practical anomaly
detection applications,
you usually have a lot
of different features.
You've now seen how the
Gaussian distribution works.
If x is a single number,
this corresponds to if,
say you had just one feature
for your anomaly
detection problem.
But for practical anomaly
detection applications,
you will have many features,
two or three or some even
larger number n of features.
Let's take what you saw for
a single Gaussian and use
it to build a more
sophisticated anomaly
detection algorithm.
They can handle
multiple features.
Let's go do that