When you have a few positive
examples with Michael's 1 and
a large number of negative
examples say y = 0?
When should you use anomaly detection and
when should you use supervised learning?
The decision is actually quite
subtle in some applications.
So let me share with you some thoughts and
some suggestions for
how to pick between these
two types of algorithms.
And anomaly detection algorithm will
typically be the more appropriate
choice when you have a very small
number of positive examples,
0-20 positive examples is not uncommon.
And a relatively large
number of negative examples
with which to try to build a model for
p of x.
When you recall that the parameters for
p of x are learned only from the negative
examples and this much smaller.
So the positive examples is only used
in your cross validation set and
test set for parameter tuning and
for evaluation.
In contrast, if you have
a larger number of positive and
negative examples, then supervised
learning might be more applicable.
Now, even if you have only 20
positive training examples,
it might be okay to apply
a supervised learning algorithm.
But it turns out that the way anomaly
detection looks at the data set
versus the way supervised learning looks
at the data set are quite different.
She is the main difference,
which is that if you think there are many
different types of an obvious or
many different types of positive examples.
Then anomaly detection might
be more appropriate when there
are many different ways for
an aircraft engine to go wrong.
And if tomorrow there may
be a brand new way for
an aircraft engine to have
something wrong with it.
Then your 20 say positive examples
may not cover all of the ways that
an aircraft engine could go wrong.
That makes it hard for any algorithm
to learn from the small set of
positive examples what the anomalies,
what the positive examples look like.
And future anomalies may
look nothing like any
of the anomalous examples we've seen so
far.
If you believe this to be true for
your problem,
then I would gravitate to using
an anomaly detection algorithm.
Because what anomaly detection does is
it looks at the normal examples that
is the y = 0 negative examples and
just try to model what they look like.
And anything that deviates a lot
from normal It flags as an anomaly.
Including if there's a brand new way for
an aircraft engine to fail that had
never been seen before in your data set.
In contrast, supervised learning has
a different way of looking at the problem.
When you're applying supervised
learning ideally you would hope to have
enough positive examples for
the average to get a sense of what
the positive examples are like.
And with supervised learning,
we tend to assume that the future positive
examples are likely to be similar
to the ones in the training set.
So let me illustrate
this with one example,
if you are using a system to find,
say financial fraud.
There are many different
ways unfortunately that
some individuals are trying
to commit financial fraud.
And unfortunately there are new types of
financial fraud attempts every
few months or every year.
And what that means is that because
they keep on popping up completely new.
And unique forms of financial fraud
anomaly detection is often used to just
look for anything that's different,
then transactions we've seen in the past.
In contrast, if you look at the problem
of email spam detection, well,
there are many different types of
spam email, but even over many years.
Spam emails keep on trying
to sell similar things or
get you to go to similar websites and
so on.
Spam email that you will get in
the next few days is much more likely
to be similar to spam emails
that you have seen in the past.
So that's why supervised
learning works well for
spam because it's trying to
detect more of the types of spam
emails that you have probably seen
in the past in your training set.
Whereas if you're trying to detect brand
new types of fraud that have never been
seen before in the nominate section,
maybe more applicable.
Let's go through a few more examples.
We have already seen fraud detection
being one use case of anomaly detection.
Although supervised learning is used to
find previously observed forms of fraud.
And we've seen email spam
classification typically being address
using supervised learning.
You've also seen the example
of manufacturing where
you may want to find new
previously unseen defects.
Such as if there are brand new ways for
an aircraft engine to fail in the future
that you still want to detect.
Even if you don't have any positive
example like that in your training set.
It turns out that the manufacturing
supervised learning is also used to find
defects.
The more for finding known and
previously seen defects.
For example, if you are a smartphone
maker, you're making cell phones.
And you know that
occasionally your machine for
making the case of the smartphone
will accidentally stretch the cover.
So stretches are a common defect
on smartphones and so you can get
enough training examples of stretched
smartphones responding to label y =1.
And just train the system to decide
if a new smartphone that you just
manufactured has any stretches in it.
And the difference is if you just see
stretch smartphones over and over and
you want to check if your
phones are stretched,
then supervised learning works well.
Whereas if you suspect that they're
going to be brand new ways for
something to go wrong in the future,
then anomaly detection will work well.
Some other examples you've heard me talk
about monitoring machines in the data
center, especially
the machine's been hacked.
It can behave differently in a brand
new way unlike any previous way in his
behavior.
So that would feel more like
an anomaly detection application.
In fact, one theme is that many
security related applications because
hackers are often finding brand
new ways to hack into systems.
Many security related applications
will use anomaly detection.
Whereas returning to supervised learning,
if you want to learn to predict
the weather well, there's only a handful
types of weather that you typically see.
Is it sunny, rainy, is it going to snow?
And so because you see the same
output labels over and over,
weather prediction would tend to
be a supervised learning task.
Or if you want to use the symptoms of
the patient to see if the patient has
a specific disease that
you've seen before.
Then that would also tend to be
a supervised learning application.
So I hope that gives you a framework for
deciding when you have a small set of
positive examples as well as maybe
a large set of negative examples.
Whether to use anomaly detection or
supervised learning.
Anomaly detection tries to find brand
new positive examples that may be unlike
anything you've seen before.
Where supervised learning looks
at your positive examples and
tries to decide if a future example is
similar to the positive examples that
you've already seen.
Now, it turns out that when building
an anomaly detection algorithm, the choice
of features is very important and
when building anomaly detection systems.
I often spend a bit of time trying
to tune the features I use for
the system in the next video.
Let me share some practical tips on how
to tune the features you feed to anomaly