What is clustering?
A clustering algorithm looks at
a number of data points and
automatically finds
data points that are
related or similar
to each other.
Let's take a look
at what that means.
Let me contrast clustering,
which is an unsupervised
learning algorithm,
with what you had
previously seen with
supervised learning for
binary classification.
Given a dataset like this
with features x_1 and x_2.
With supervised learning, we
had a training set with both
the input features x as
well as the labels y.
We could plot a dataset
like this and fit, say,
a logistic regression
algorithm or
a neural network to learn a
decision boundary like that.
In supervised learning,
the dataset included
both the inputs x as well
as the target outputs y.
In contrast, in
unsupervised learning,
you are given a dataset
like this with just x,
but not the labels or
the target labels y.
That's why when I
plot a dataset,
it looks like this,
with just dots rather
than two classes
denoted by the x's and the o's.
Because we don't have
target labels y,
we're not able to tell
the algorithm what is
the "right answer,
y" that we wanted to predict.
Instead, we're going to
ask the algorithm to
find something interesting
about the data,
that is to find some interesting
structure about this data.
But the first unsupervised
learning algorithm
that you learn about is called
a clustering algorithm,
which looks for one
particular type
of structure in the data.
Namely, look at the dataset
like this and try to
see if it can be
grouped into clusters,
meaning groups of points that
are similar to each other.
A clustering algorithm,
in this case,
might find that this dataset
comprises of data from
two clusters shown here.
Here are some applications
of clustering.
In the first week of
the first course,
you heard me talk about
grouping similar news
articles together,
like the story about Pandas
or market segmentation,
where at deeplearning.ai,
we discovered that there
are many learners that come
here because you may want
to grow your skills,
or develop your careers,
or stay updated with
AI and understand how it
affects your field of work.
We want to help
everyone with any of
these skills to learn
about machine learning,
or if you don't fall into
one of these clusters,
that's totally fine too.
I hope deeplearning.ai and
Stanford Online's materials will
be useful to you as well.
Clustering has also been
used to analyze DNA data,
where you will look at the
genetic expression data from
different individuals
and try to group them
into people that
exhibit similar traits.
I find astronomy and space
exploration fascinating.
One application that
I thought was very
exciting was astronomers using
clustering for astronomical
data analysis to
group bodies in
space together for
their own analysis of
what's going on in space.
One of the applications I found
fascinating was
astronomers using
clustering to group bodies
together to figure out which
ones form one galaxy or
which one form coherent
structures in space.
Clustering today
is used for all of
these applications
and many more.
In the next video,
let's take a look at
the most commonly used
clustering algorithm
called the k-means algorithm,
and let's take a look