Let's take a look at what the K-means
clustering algorithm does.
Let me start with an example.
Here I've plotted a data set with
30 unlabeled training examples.
So there are 30 points.
And what we like to do is run
K-means on this data set.
The first thing that the K-means algorithm
does is it will take a random guess
at where might be the centers of the two
clusters that you might ask it to find.
In this example I'm going to ask
it to try to find two clusters.
Later in this week we'll talk about how
you might decide how
many clusters to find.
But the very first step is it
will randomly pick two points,
which I've shown here as a red cross and
the blue cross,
at where might be the centers
of two different clusters.
This is just a random initial guess and
they're not particularly good guesses.
But it's a start.
One thing I hope you take away from
this video is that K-means will
repeatedly do two different things.
The first is assign points
to cluster centroids and
the second is move cluster centroids.
Let's take a look at what this means.
The first of the two steps is it will
go through each of these points and
look at whether it is closer to
the red cross or to the blue cross.
The very first thing that K-means
does is it will take a random guess
at where are the centers of the cluster?
And the centers of the cluster
are called cluster centroids.
After it's made an initial guess
at where the cluster centroid is,
it will go through all of these examples,
x(1) through x(30), my 30 data points.
And for each of them it will check if it
is closer to the red cluster centroid,
shown by the red cross, or if it's
closer to the blue cluster centroid,
shown by the blue cross.
And it will assign each of these
points to whichever of the cluster
centroids It is closer to.
I'm going to illustrate that by
painting each of these examples,
each of these little round dots,
either red or blue, depending on
whether that example is closer to
the red or to the blue cluster centroid.
So this point up here is closer to the red
centroid, which is why it's painted red.
Whereas this point down there is
closer to the blue cluster centroid,
which is why I've now painted it blue.
So that was the first of the two things
that K-means does over and over.
Which is a sign points
to clusters centroids.
And all that means is it will associate
which I'm illustrating with the color,
every point of one of
the cluster centroids.
The second of the two steps
that K-means does is,
it'll look at all of the red points and
take an average of them.
And it will move the red cross
to whatever is the average
location of the red dots,
which turns out to be here.
And so the red cross, that is the red
cluster centroid will move here.
And then we do the same thing for
all the blue dots.
Look at all the blue dots, and
take an average of them, and
move the blue cross over there.
So you now have a new location for
the blue cluster centroid as well.
In the next video we'll look at
the mathematical formulas for
how to do both of these steps.
But now that you have these new and
hopefully slightly improved guesses for
the locations of the to cluster centroids,
we'll look through all of
the 30 training examples again.
And check for every one of them,
whether it's closer to the red or
the blue cluster centroid for
the new locations.
And then we will associate them which
are indicated by the color again,
every point to the closer
cluster centroid.
And if you do that, you see that
the field points change color.
So for example, this point is colored red,
because it was closer to the red
cluster centroid previously.
But if we now look again,
it's now actually closer to
the blue cluster centroid, because the
blue and red cluster centroids have moved.
So if we go through and
associate each point with the closer
cluster centroids, you end up with this.
And then we just repeat
the second part of K-means again.
Which is look at all of the red dots and
compute the average.
And also look at all of the blue dots and
compute the average location
of all of the blue dots.
And it turns out that you end up
moving the red cross over there and
the blue cross over here.
And we repeat.
Let's look at all of the points again and
we color them,
either red or blue, depending on which
cluster centroid that is closer to.
So you end up with this.
And then again, look at all of the red
dots and take their average location,
and look at all the blue dots and
take the average location, and
move the clusters to the new locations.
And it turns out that if you were to keep
on repeating these two steps, that is
look at each point and assign it to
the nearest cluster centroid and then also
move each cluster centroid to the mean
of all the points with the same color.
If you keep on doing those two steps,
you find that there are no more changes to
the colors of the points or to
the locations of the clusters centroids.
And so this means that at this point
the K-means clustering algorithm has
converged.
Because applying those two steps over and
over, results in no further
changes to either the assignment
to point to the centroids or
the location of the cluster centroids.
In this example, it looks like
K-means has done a pretty good job.
It has found that these points up
here correspond to one cluster,
and these points down here
correspond to a second cluster.
So now you've seen an illustration
of how K-means works.
The two key steps are, assign every
point to the cluster centroid,
depending on what cluster
centroid is nearest to.
And second move each cluster
centroid to the average or
the mean of all the points
that were assigned to it.
In the next video,
we'll look at how to formalize this and
write out the algorithm that does
what you just saw in this video.